{
    "chapter1": [
        {
            "question": "Which nurse most likely kept records on sanitation techniques and the effects on health?",
            "options": ["Florence Nightingale", "Mary Nutting", "Clara Barton", "Lillian Wald"],
            "answer": "Florence Nightingale",
            "explanation": "Nightingale was the first practicing nurse epidemiologist. Her statistical analyses connected poor sanitation with cholera and dysentery. Mary Nutting, Clara Barton, and Lillian Wald came after Nightingale, each contributing to the nursing profession in her own way. Mary Nutting was instrumental in moving nursing education into universities. Clara Barton founded the American Red Cross. Lillian Wald helped open the Henry Street Settlement.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the influence of social, historical, political, and economic changes on nursing practices.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
        }
    ],
    "chapter3": [
      {
        "question": "A nurse is working as a public health nurse. What will be the nurse’s primary focus?",
        "options": [
          "The individual as one member of a group",
          "Individuals and families",
          "Needs of a population",
          "Health promotion"
        ],
        "answer": "Needs of a population",
        "explanation": "Public health nursing primary focus is understanding the needs of a population. Community-based care focuses on health promotion. Community health nursing focuses on health care of individuals, families, and groups within the community.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the relationship between public health and community health nursing.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse wants to become a specialist in public health nursing. Which educational requirement will the nurse have to obtain?",
        "options": [
          "A baccalaureate degree in nursing",
          "Preparation at the basic entry level",
          "The same level of education as the community health nurse",
          "A graduate level education with a focus in public health science"
        ],
        "answer": "A graduate level education with a focus in public health science",
        "explanation": "A specialist in public health has a graduate level education with a focus in public health science. Public health nursing requires preparation at the basic entry level and sometimes requires a baccalaureate degree in nursing. A community health nurse is not the same thing as a public health nursing specialist.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the relationship between public health and community health nursing.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is working as a community health nurse. Which action is a priority for this nurse?",
        "options": [
          "Provide direct care to subpopulations.",
          "Focus on the needs of the ill individual.",
          "Provide first level of contact to health care systems.",
          "Focus on providing care in various community settings."
        ],
        "answer": "Provide direct care to subpopulations.",
        "explanation": "Community health nursing is nursing practice in the community, with the primary focus on the health care of individuals, families, and groups within the community. In addition, the community health nurse provides direct care services to subpopulations within a community. Community-based nursing centers function as the first level of contact between members of a community and the health care system. Community-based nursing focuses on providing care in various community settings, such as the home or a clinic and involves acute and chronic care.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Differentiate community health nursing from community-based nursing.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is focusing on acute and chronic care of individuals and families within a community while enhancing patient autonomy. Which type of nursing care is the nurse providing?",
        "options": [
          "Public health",
          "Community health",
          "Community-based",
          "Community assessment"
        ],
        "answer": "Community-based",
        "explanation": "Community-based nursing involves acute and chronic care of individuals and families and enhances their capacity for self-care while promoting autonomy in decision making. Public health nursing focuses on the needs of a population. Community health nursing cares for the community as a whole and considers the individual or the family as only one member of a group at risk. Community assessment is the systematic data collection on the population, monitoring the health status of the population, and making information available about the health of the community.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Differentiate community health nursing from community-based nursing.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The community health nurse is administering flu shots to children at a local playground. What is the rationale for this nurse’s action?",
        "options": [
          "To prevent individual illness",
          "To prevent community outbreak of illness",
          "To prevent outbreak of illness in the family",
          "To prevent needs of the local population groups"
        ],
        "answer": "To prevent community outbreak of illness",
        "explanation": "The nurse is trying to prevent a community outbreak of illness. By focusing on subpopulations (children), the community health nurse cares for the community as a whole and considers the individual or the family as only one member of a group at risk. Community-based nursing, as opposed to community health nursing, focuses on the needs of the individual or family. Public health nursing focuses on meeting the population groups’ needs.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the role of the community health nurse.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse attended a seminar on community-based health care. Which information indicates the nurse has a good understanding of community-based health care?",
        "options": [
          "It occurs in hospitals.",
          "Its focus is on ill individuals.",
          "Its priority is health promotion.",
          "It provides services primarily to the poor."
        ],
        "answer": "Its priority is health promotion.",
        "explanation": "Community-based health care is a model of care that reaches everyone in the community (including the poor and underinsured), focuses on primary rather than institutional or acute care, and provides knowledge about health and health promotion and models of care to the community. Community-based health care occurs outside traditional health care institutions such as hospitals.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the relationship between public health and community health nursing.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using the Healthy People 2020 to establish goals for the community. Which goal is priority?",
        "options": [
          "Reduce health care costs.",
          "Increase life expectancy.",
          "Provide services close to where patients live.",
          "Isolate patients to prevent the spread of disease."
        ],
        "answer": "Increase life expectancy.",
        "explanation": "The overall goals of Healthy People 2020 are to increase life expectancy and quality of life and eliminate health disparities through an improved delivery of health care services. It does not focus on reducing health care costs, providing services close to where patients live, or isolating patients to prevent the spread of disease.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the role of the nurse in community-based practice.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is working in community-based nursing. Which competency is priority for this nurse?",
        "options": [
          "Caregiver",
          "Collaborator",
          "Change agent",
          "Case manager"
        ],
        "answer": "Caregiver",
        "explanation": "First and foremost is the role of caregiver. While collaborator, change agent, and case manager are important, they are not the priority.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the competencies important for success in community-based nursing practice.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse observes an outbreak of lice in a certain school district. The nurse collects data and identifies a common practice of sharing lockers, caps, and hair brushes. The nurse shares the information with the school. Which community-based nursing competency did the nurse use?",
        "options": [
          "Educator",
          "Caregiver",
          "Case manager",
          "Epidemiologist"
        ],
        "answer": "Epidemiologist",
        "explanation": "As an epidemiologist, you are involved in case finding, health teaching, and tracking incident rates of an illness (outbreak of lice). The nurse did not teach the students about lice. The nurse did not provide care for the lice. The nurse did not coordinate needed resources and services for a group of patient’s well-being (case manager).",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the competencies important for success in community-based nursing practice.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is providing screening at a health fair. Which finding indicates the person may be a vulnerable patient who is most likely to develop health problems?",
        "options": [
          "One who is pregnant.",
          "One who has excessive risks.",
          "One who has unlimited access to health care.",
          "One who uses nontraditional healing practices."
        ],
        "answer": "One who has excessive risks.",
        "explanation": "Vulnerable populations are the patients who are more likely to develop health problems as a result of excessive risks or limits in access to health care services or who are dependent on others for care. Pregnancy is not a cause of vulnerability, except in cases where the mother is an adolescent, is addicted to drugs, or is at high risk for other reasons. A person who has unlimited access to health care is not vulnerable. Frequently, the immigrant population practices nontraditional healing practices. Many of these healing practices are effective and complement traditional therapies.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify characteristics of patients from vulnerable populations that influence the community-based nurse’s approach to care.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The instructor is teaching student nurses about identifying members of vulnerable populations when the nursing student asks, “Why is it that not all poor people are considered members of vulnerable populations?” How should the nurse respond?",
        "options": [
          "“All poor people are members of a vulnerable population.”",
          "“Poor people are members of a vulnerable population only if they take drugs.”",
          "“Poor people are members of a vulnerable population only if they are homeless.”",
          "“Members of vulnerable groups frequently have a combination of risk factors.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Members of vulnerable groups frequently have a combination of risk factors.”",
        "explanation": "Members of vulnerable groups frequently have many risks or a combination of risk factors that make them more sensitive to the negative effects of individual risk factors. Individual risk factors are not always overwhelming, depending on the patient’s beliefs and values and sources of social support.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify characteristics of patients from vulnerable populations that influence the community-based nurse’s approach to care.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is making a home visit to a Korean mother after the birth of girl. The spouse is pressing different parts of the patient’s hand and lower arm to relieve a headache. What is the nurse’s next action?",
        "options": [
          "Tell the spouse to stop and give the mother acetaminophen.",
          "Let the spouse finish and then give the mother medication.",
          "Ask the mother and/or spouse to explain the procedure.",
          "Explain to the spouse that it will not work."
        ],
        "answer": "Ask the mother and/or spouse to explain the procedure.",
        "explanation": "The nurse should not judge the patient’s/family’s beliefs and values about health. The nurse needs to understand cultural beliefs, values, and practices to determine their specific needs. Acetaminophen may not be an acceptable alternative for this family. Criticizing the family’s beliefs and practices or saying they will not work may only create a barrier to care.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify characteristics of patients from vulnerable populations that influence the community-based nurse’s approach to care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing the social system of a community. Which area should the nurse assess?",
        "options": [
          "Housing",
          "Economic status",
          "Volunteer programs",
          "Predominant ethnic groups"
        ],
        "answer": "Volunteer programs",
        "explanation": "Social systems include volunteer programs, education system, government, and health systems. Housing and economic status are included in the structure assessment. Predominant ethnic groups are a component of the population assessment.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe elements of a community assessment.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is working with a 16-year-old pregnant female who tells the nurse that she needs an abortion. The nurse, acting as a counselor, provides the patient with information on alternatives to abortion, but after several sessions, the patient still insists on having the abortion. What should the nurse, in the counselor role, do next?",
        "options": [
          "Encourage the patient to speak with a “Right-to-Life” advocate.",
          "Refuse to provide a referral to an abortion service.",
          "Provide referral to an abortion service.",
          "Delay referral to an abortion service."
        ],
        "answer": "Provide referral to an abortion service.",
        "explanation": "As a counselor, the nurse is responsible for providing information, listening objectively, and being supportive, caring, and trustworthy and providing a referral to an abortion service. The nurse does not make decisions, like going to a “Right-to-Life” advocate, but rather helps the patient reach decisions that are best for him or her. To refuse to provide a referral or to delay referral would not be supportive of the patient’s decision.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the competencies important for success in community-based nursing practice.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Before a patient with beginning stage of Alzheimer’s disease is discharged, the community-based nurse is making a visit to the patient’s home. The patient’s daughter and family live in the home with the patient. What is the major focus of this visit?",
        "options": [
          "Teach the family how to monitor blood pressure.",
          "Demonstrate techniques for providing care.",
          "Stress to the family how difficult it will be to provide care at home.",
          "Encourage the family to send the patient to an extended care facility."
        ],
        "answer": "Demonstrate techniques for providing care.",
        "explanation": "The role of the community health nurse, when dealing with patients with Alzheimer’s disease, is to maintain the best possible functioning, protection, and safety for the patient. The nurse should demonstrate to the primary family caregiver techniques for dressing, feeding, and toileting the patient while providing encouragement and emotional support to the caregiver. Monitoring blood pressure is not necessary for an Alzheimer’s patient; blood pressure would be for a patient with hypertension. The nurse should protect the patient’s rights and maintain family stability, not encourage placement in an extended care facility.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the competencies important for success in community-based nursing practice.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "While conducting a community assessment, the nurse seeks data on the average household income and the number of residents on public assistance. In doing so, the nurse is evaluating which component of a community assessment?",
        "options": [
          "Structure",
          "Population",
          "Social system",
          "Welfare system"
        ],
        "answer": "Structure",
        "explanation": "Economic status is part of the community structure. Population would involve age and gender distribution, growth trends, density, education level, and ethnic or religious groups. The welfare system is part of the social system that also includes the education, government, communication, and health systems.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe elements of a community assessment.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse uses statistics on increased incidence of communicable disease to influence legislatures to pass a bill for mandatory vaccinations to enroll in school. Which type of nursing will the nurse use in this process?",
        "options": [
          "Public health nursing",
          "Community-based nursing",
          "Community health nursing",
          "Vulnerable population nursing"
        ],
        "answer": "Public health nursing",
        "explanation": "A public health nurse understands factors that influence health promotion and health maintenance, the trends and patterns influencing the incidence of disease within populations, environmental factors contributing to health and illness, and the political processes used to affect public policy. Community health nursing is nursing practice in the community, with the primary focus on the health care of individuals, families, and groups within the community. Community-based nursing care takes place in community settings such as the home or a clinic, where the focus is on the needs of the individual or family. While there is no specific vulnerable population nursing, all types of nursing should care for these populations.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Explain the relationship between public health and community health nursing.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A community-based nursing is working with a family. For which key areas will the nurse need a strong knowledge base? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Family theory",
          "Communication",
          "Group dynamics",
          "Cultural diversity",
          "Individual-centered care"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Family theory",
          "Communication",
          "Group dynamics",
          "Cultural diversity"
        ],
        "explanation": "With the individual and family as the patients, the context of community-based nursing is family-centered care (not individual-centered care) within the community. This focus requires a strong knowledge base in family theory, principles of communication, group dynamics, and cultural diversity. The nurse leans to partner with patients and families, not just with individuals.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the role of the nurse in community-based practice.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "Offering which community-based nursing activities indicates the nurse is working in the role of educator? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Prenatal classes",
          "A child safety program",
          "To defend patients’ decisions",
          "Creative solutions to local problems",
          "To coordinate resources after discharge"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Prenatal classes",
          "A child safety program"
        ],
        "explanation": "Prenatal classes, infant care, child safety, and cancer screening are just some of the health education programs provided in a community practice setting. Offers to defend patients’ decisions is the role of patient advocate. Offers creative solutions to local problems indicates a change agent. Collaborator will offer to coordinate resources after discharge.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the competencies important for success in community-based nursing practice.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for vulnerable populations in a local community. Which patients will the nurse care for in this community? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "A 47-year-old immigrant who speaks only Spanish",
          "A 35-year-old living in own home",
          "A 22-year-old pregnant woman",
          "A 40-year-old schizophrenic",
          "A 15-year-old rape victim"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "A 47-year-old immigrant who speaks only Spanish",
          "A 40-year-old schizophrenic",
          "A 15-year-old rape victim"
        ],
        "explanation": "Individuals living in poverty, older adults, people who are homeless, immigrant populations, individuals in abusive relationships (rape), substance abusers, and people with severe mental illnesses (schizophrenic) are examples of vulnerable populations. Middle-aged people living in their own home are not an example of a vulnerable population. Pregnancy is not an example of a vulnerable population.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify characteristics of patients from vulnerable populations that influence the community-based nurse’s approach to care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a community. Match each community element the nurse will assess with the correct example.",
          "matching": [
            "Structure",
            "Population",
            "Social system"
          ],
          "options": [
            "Education level",
            "Housing",
            "Government"
          ],
          "answer": {
            "Structure": "Housing",
            "Population": "Education level",
            "Social system": "Government"
          },
          "explanation": "In assessing a community, a nurse examines various elements to understand its dynamics and needs. Housing (Structure) is evaluated through the area's encompassing residences, living conditions, and availability. Education level (Population) is analyzed by determining literacy rates and access to resources. Government (Social system) can be assessed by focusing on governance structure and policies. By evaluating housing, education level, and government, the nurse gains insights into the community's health and tailors interventions accordingly.",
          "dif":"Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze nursing actions most often associated in a breach of nursing practice.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
      }
    ],
    "chapter6": [
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching about the goals of Healthy People 2020. Which information should the nurse include in the teaching session?",
        "options": [
          "Eliminate health disparities in America.",
          "Eliminate health behaviors in America.",
          "Eliminate quality of life in America.",
          "Eliminate healthy life in America."
        ],
        "answer": "Eliminate health disparities in America.",
        "explanation": "The nurse should include eliminating health disparities in America. Healthy People 2020 promotes a society in which all people live long, healthy lives. There are four overarching goals: (1) attain high-quality, longer lives free of preventable disease, disability, injury, and premature death; (2) achieve health equity, eliminate disparities, and improve the health of all groups; (3) create social and physical environments that promote good health for all; and (4) promote quality of life, healthy development, and healthy behaviors across all life stages.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "List the four general Healthy People 2020 public health goals for Americans.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is following the goals of Healthy People 2020 to provide care. Which action should the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Allow people to continue current behaviors to reduce the stress of change.",
          "Focus only on health changes that will lead to better local communities.",
          "Create social and physical environments that promote good health.",
          "Focus on illness treatment to provide fast recuperation."
        ],
        "answer": "Create social and physical environments that promote good health.",
        "explanation": "Healthy People 2020 includes four goals, one of which is to create social and physical environments that promote good health for all. The goals do not include continuing current behaviors to reduce stress, focusing only on health changes for communities, or focusing on fast recuperation.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "List the four general Healthy People 2020 public health goals for Americans.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using the World Health Organization definition of health to provide care. Which area will the nurse focus on while providing care?",
        "options": [
          "Focusing on helping patients be disease free",
          "Providing care that involves the whole person",
          "Assuring that care is strictly personal in nature",
          "Directing focus only on the pathological state"
        ],
        "answer": "Providing care that involves the whole person",
        "explanation": "The World Health Organization (WHO) defines health as a “state of complete physical, mental, and social well-being, not merely the absence of disease or infirmity.” Therefore, nurses’ attitudes toward health and illness should consider the total person, as well as the environment in which the person lives. All people free of disease are not necessarily healthy. Strictly personal and a focus only on pathological states do not correlate to WHO’s definition.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the definition of health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is preparing a smoking cessation class for family members of patients with lung cancer. The nurse believes that the class will convert many smokers to nonsmokers once they realize the benefits of not smoking. Which health care model is the nurse following?",
        "options": [
          "Health belief model",
          "Holistic health model",
          "Health promotion model",
          "Maslow’s hierarchy of needs"
        ],
        "answer": "Health belief model",
        "explanation": "The health belief model addresses the relationship between a person’s beliefs and behaviors. The holistic health model recognizes the natural healing abilities of the body and incorporates complementary and alternative interventions such as music therapy. The health promotion model focuses on the following three areas: (1) individual characteristics and experiences, (2) behavior-specific knowledge and affect, and (3) behavioral outcomes, in which the patient commits to or changes a behavior. Maslow’s’ hierarchy of needs is based on the theory that all people share basic human needs, and the extent to which basic needs are met is a major factor in determining a person’s level of health.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss the health belief, health promotion, basic human needs, and holistic health models to understand the relationship between",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using Maslow’s hierarchy to prioritize care for an anxious patient that is not eating and will not see family members. Which area should the nurse address first?",
        "options": [
          "Anxiety",
          "Not eating",
          "Mental health",
          "Not seeing family members"
        ],
        "answer": "Not eating",
        "explanation": "According to Maslow, in all cases an emergent physiological need takes precedence over a higher-level need. Nutrition is a physiological need and should be addressed first. Anxiety, mental health, and not seeing family members are all higher-level needs.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss the health belief, health promotion, basic human needs, and holistic health models to understand the relationship between",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is reporting moderate incisional pain that was not relieved by the last dose of pain medication. The patient is not due for another dose of medication for another 2 1/2 hours. The nurse repositions the patient, asks what type of music the patient likes, and sets the television to the channel playing that type of music. Which health care model is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "Health belief model",
          "Holistic health model",
          "Health promotion model",
          "Maslow’s hierarchy of needs"
        ],
        "answer": "Holistic health model",
        "explanation": "The holistic health model recognizes the natural healing abilities of the body and incorporates complementary and alternative interventions such as music therapy. The health belief model addresses the relationship between a person’s beliefs and behaviors. The health promotion model notes that each person has unique personal characteristics and experiences that affect subsequent actions. The basic human needs model believes that the extent to which basic needs are met is a major factor in determining a person’s level of health. Maslow’s hierarchy of needs is a model that nurses use to understand the interrelationships of basic human needs.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the health belief, health promotion, basic human needs, and holistic health models to understand the relationship between",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing internal variables that are affecting the patient’s health status. Which area should the nurse assess?",
        "options": [
          "Perception of functioning",
          "Socioeconomic factors",
          "Cultural background",
          "Family practices"
        ],
        "answer": "Perception of functioning",
        "explanation": "Internal variables include a person’s developmental stage, intellectual background, perception of functioning, and emotional and spiritual factors. External variables influencing a person’s health beliefs and practices include family practices, socioeconomic factors, and cultural background.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe variables influencing health beliefs and practices.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is admitting a patient with uncontrolled diabetes mellitus. It is the fourth time the patient is being admitted in the last 6 months for high blood glucose levels. During the admission process, the nurse asks the patient about employment status and displays a nonjudgmental attitude. What is the rationale for the nurse’s actions?",
        "options": [
          "External variables have little effect on compliance.",
          "A person’s compliance is affected by economic status.",
          "Employment status is an internal variable that impacts compliance.",
          "Noncompliant patients thrive on the disapproval of authority figures."
        ],
        "answer": "A person’s compliance is affected by economic status.",
        "explanation": "A person’s compliance with treatment is affected by economic status. A person tends to give a higher priority to food and shelter than to costly drugs or treatments. External variables can have a major impact on compliance. Employment status is an external variable, not an internal variable. A person generally seeks approval and support from social networks, and this desire for approval affects health beliefs and practices; noncompliance does not occur from thriving on disapproval of authority figures.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe variables influencing health beliefs and practices.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is working on a committee to evaluate the need for increasing the levels of fluoride in the drinking water of the community. Which concept is the nurse fostering?",
        "options": [
          "Illness prevention",
          "Wellness education",
          "Active health promotion",
          "Passive health promotion"
        ],
        "answer": "Passive health promotion",
        "explanation": "Fluoridation of municipal drinking water and fortification of homogenized milk with vitamin D are examples of passive health promotion strategies. With active strategies of health promotion, individuals are motivated to adopt specific health programs such as weight reduction and smoking cessation programs. Illness prevention activities such as immunization programs protect patients from actual or potential threats to health. Wellness education teaches people how to care for themselves in a healthy way.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe health promotion, wellness, and illness prevention activities.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is working in a clinic that is designed to provide health education and immunizations. Which type of preventive care is the nurse providing?",
        "options": [
          "Primary prevention",
          "Secondary prevention",
          "Tertiary prevention",
          "Risk factor prevention"
        ],
        "answer": "Primary prevention",
        "explanation": "Primary prevention precedes disease or dysfunction and is applied to people considered physically and emotionally healthy. Primary prevention includes health education programs, immunizations, and physical and nutritional fitness activities. Secondary prevention focuses on individuals who are experiencing health problems or illnesses and who are at risk for developing complications or worsening conditions. Activities are directed at diagnosis and prompt intervention. Tertiary prevention occurs when a defect or disability is permanent and irreversible. It involves minimizing the effects of long-term disease or disability through interventions directed at preventing complications and deterioration. While risk factor modification is an integral component of health promotion, it is not a type of preventive care.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the three levels of preventive care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is admitted to the emergency department of the local hospital from home with reports of chest discomfort and shortness of breath. The patient is placed on oxygen, has labs and blood gases drawn, and is given an electrocardiogram and breathing treatments. Which level of preventive care is this patient receiving?",
        "options": [
          "Primary prevention",
          "Secondary prevention",
          "Tertiary prevention",
          "Health promotion"
        ],
        "answer": "Secondary prevention",
        "explanation": "Secondary prevention focuses on individuals who are experiencing health problems or illnesses and who are at risk for developing complications or worsening conditions. Activities are directed at diagnosis and prompt intervention. Primary prevention precedes disease or dysfunction and is applied to people considered physically and emotionally healthy. Health promotion includes health education programs, immunizations, and physical and nutritional fitness activities for healthy people. Tertiary prevention occurs when a defect or disability is permanent and irreversible. It involves minimizing the effects of long-term disease or disability through interventions directed at preventing complications and deterioration.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the three levels of preventive care.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is admitted to a rehabilitation facility following a stroke. The patient has right-sided paralysis and is unable to speak. The patient will be receiving physical therapy and speech therapy. Which level of preventive care is the patient receiving?",
        "options": [
          "Primary prevention",
          "Secondary prevention",
          "Tertiary prevention",
          "Health promotion"
        ],
        "answer": "Tertiary prevention",
        "explanation": "Tertiary prevention occurs when a defect or disability is permanent and irreversible. It involves minimizing the effects of long-term disease or disability through interventions directed at preventing complications and deterioration. Secondary prevention focuses on individuals who are experiencing health problems or illnesses and who are at risk for developing complications or worsening conditions. Activities are directed at diagnosis and prompt intervention. Primary prevention precedes disease or dysfunction and is applied to people considered physically and emotionally healthy. Health promotion includes health education programs, immunizations, and physical and nutritional fitness activities.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the three levels of preventive care.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Upon completing a history, the nurse finds that a patient has risk factors for developing lung disease. How should the nurse interpret this finding?",
        "options": [
          "A person with the risk factor will get the disease.",
          "The chances of getting the disease are increased.",
          "Risk modification will have no effect on disease prevention.",
          "The disease is guaranteed not to develop if the risk factor is controlled."
        ],
        "answer": "The chances of getting the disease are increased.",
        "explanation": "The presence of risk factors does not mean that a disease will develop, but risk factors increase the chances that the individual will experience a particular disease or dysfunction. Control of risk factors does not guarantee that a disease will not develop. However, risk factor modification can assist patients in adopting activities to promote health and decrease risks of illness.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe four types of risk factors affecting health.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has been trying to quit smoking. The patient has been smoke free for 2 weeks but had two cigarettes last night and at least two this morning. What should the nurse anticipate?",
        "options": [
          "The patient does not want to and will never quit smoking.",
          "The patient must pick up the attempt right where the patient left off.",
          "The patient will return to the contemplation or precontemplation phase.",
          "The patient will need to adopt a new lifestyle for change to be effective."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient will return to the contemplation or precontemplation phase.",
        "explanation": "When relapse occurs, the person will return to the contemplation or precontemplation stage before attempting the change again. The patient cannot pick up the attempt where left off. It is believed that change involves movement through a series of stages (precontemplation, contemplation, preparation, action, and maintenance). Anticipating that the patient does not want to and will never quit is premature. While the patient will need to adopt a new lifestyle for change to be effective, it does not correlate to this scenario since the patient relapsed.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss risk factor modification and changing health behaviors.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is working in a drug rehabilitation clinic and is in the process of admitting a patient for “detox.” What should the nurse do next?",
        "options": [
          "Identify the patient’s stage of change.",
          "Realize that the patient is ready to change.",
          "Teach the patient that choices will have to change.",
          "Instruct the patient that relapses will not be tolerated."
        ],
        "answer": "Identify the patient’s stage of change.",
        "explanation": "The nurse should identify the stage of change and assess where the patient is currently in this situation. To be most effective, nursing interventions should match the stage of change. The nurse cannot realize the patient is ready for change because only a minority of people are actually in the action stage of changing. While teaching that choices will have to change, it will follow later after the nurse has determined which stage the person is in. As individuals attempt a change in behavior, relapse followed by recycling through the stages occurs frequently.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss risk factor modification and changing health behaviors.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A female patient has been overweight for most of her life. She has tried dieting in the past and has lost weight, only to regain it when she stopped dieting. The patient is visiting the weight loss clinic/health club because she has decided to do it. She states that she will join right after the holidays, in 3 months. Which stage is the patient displaying?",
        "options": [
          "Precontemplation",
          "Contemplation",
          "Preparation",
          "Action"
        ],
        "answer": "Contemplation",
        "explanation": "This patient is planning to make the change within the next 6 months and is in the contemplation stage. These stages range from no intention to change (precontemplation), to considering a change within the next 6 months (contemplation), to making small changes (preparation), to actively engaging in strategies to change behavior (action), to maintaining a changed behavior (maintenance).",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss risk factor modification and changing health behaviors.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "Upon completion of the assessment, the nurse finds that the patient has quit drinking and has been alcohol free for the past 2 years. Which stage best describes the nurse’s assessment finding?",
        "options": [
          "Contemplation",
          "Maintenance",
          "Preparation",
          "Action"
        ],
        "answer": "Maintenance",
        "explanation": "Because the patient has been alcohol free for 2 years, the patient is in the maintenance stage. These stages range from no intention to change (precontemplation), to considering a change within the next 6 months (contemplation), to making small changes (preparation), to actively engaging in strategies to change behavior (action), to maintaining a changed behavior (maintenance).",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss risk factor modification and changing health behaviors.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient had a colostomy placed 1 week ago. When approached by the nurse, the patient and their spouse refuse to talk about it and reject the opportunity to be taught about how to care for it. How will the nurse evaluate this couple’s stage of adjustment?",
        "options": [
          "Shock",
          "Withdrawal",
          "Acceptance",
          "Rehabilitation"
        ],
        "answer": "Withdrawal",
        "explanation": "As the patient and family recognize the reality of a change, they become anxious and may withdraw, refusing to discuss it. This is an adaptive coping mechanism that assists the patient in making the adjustment. Initially, the patient may be shocked by the change. This is followed by withdrawal, acknowledgment, acceptance, and rehabilitation (ready to adapt to the change through use of colostomy bag).",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe the effect of illness on patients and families.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient diagnosed with chronic emphysema (lung disease) states “I would be better off dead.” The nurse learns that the patient, has recently become unemployed because of oxygen dependency. The patient’s spouse will have to go to work to support the family. Which action should the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Develop a plan of care for the family.",
          "Contact psychiatric services for a referral.",
          "Assure the patient that things will work out.",
          "Focus the plan of care solely on maximizing patient function."
        ],
        "answer": "Develop a plan of care for the family.",
        "explanation": "Because of the effects of chronic illness, family dynamics often change. The nurse must view the whole family as a patient under stress, planning care to help the family regain its maximal level of functioning and well-being. Psychiatric services may be a part of that plan but do not represent the entire plan. Offering false assurance is never acceptable. Focusing only on the patient will not help the family adjust.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the effect of illness on patients and families.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching about the transtheoretical model of change. In which order will the nurse place the progression of the stages from beginning to end? 1. Action 2. Preparation 3. Maintenance 4. Contemplation 5. Precontemplation",
        "options": [
          "5, 4, 2, 1, 3",
          "2, 5, 4, 3, 1",
          "4, 5, 3, 1, 2",
          "1, 5, 2, 3, 4"
        ],
        "answer": "5, 4, 2, 1, 3",
        "explanation": "The stages of change in the transtheoretical model of change include five stages. These stages range from no intention to change (precontemplation), considering a change within the next 6 months (contemplation), making small changes (preparation), and actively engaging in strategies to change behavior (action), to maintaining a changed behavior (maintenance stage).",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe variables influencing health beliefs and practices.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which areas should the nurse assess to determine the effects of external variables on a patient’s illness? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Patient’s perception of the illness",
          "Patient’s coping skills",
          "Socioeconomic status",
          "Cultural background",
          "Social support"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Socioeconomic status",
          "Cultural background",
          "Social support"
      ],
        "explanation": "External variables influencing a patient’s illness behavior include the visibility of symptoms, social group, cultural background, economic variables, accessibility of the health care system, and social support. Internal variables include the patient’s perceptions of symptoms and the nature of the illness, as well as the patient’s coping skills and locus of control.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe variables influencing illness behavior.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse meets the following goals: helps a patient maintain health and helps a patient with an illness. Which factors assist the nurse in achieving these goals? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Understands the challenges of today’s health care system.",
          "Identifies actual and potential risk factors.",
          "Has coined the term “illness behavior.”",
          "Minimizes the effects of illnesses.",
          "Experiences compassion fatigue."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Understands the challenges of today’s health care system.",
          "Identifies actual and potential risk factors.",
          "Minimizes the effects of illnesses."
      ],
        "explanation": "Nurses are in a unique position to assist patients in achieving and maintaining optimal levels of health. Nurses understand the challenges of today’s health care system. Nurses can identify actual and potential risk factors that predispose a person or group to illness. Nurses who understand how patients react to illness can minimize the effects of illness and assist patients and their families in maintaining or returning to the highest level of functioning. Nurses did not coin the phrase “illness behavior.” While nurses can experience compassion fatigue, it does not help in meeting patient goals.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss a nurse’s role in health and illness.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      }
    ],
    "chapter10": [
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing the family unit to determine their ability to adapt to the change required of a member having surgery. Which area is the nurse monitoring?",
        "options": [
          "Family durability",
          "Family resiliency",
          "Family diversity",
          "Family forms"
        ],
        "answer": "Family resiliency",
        "explanation": "Family resiliency is the ability of the family to cope with expected and unexpected stressors; it’s the families’ ability to adapt to changes. Family diversity is the uniqueness of each family unit. Every person within a family unit has specific needs, strengths, and important developmental considerations. Family durability is a system of support and structure within a family that extends beyond the walls of the household. Family forms are patterns of people considered by family members to be included in the family.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss how the term family reflects family diversity.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse reviews the current trends affecting today’s family. Which trend will the nurse find?",
        "options": [
          "More mothers are full time at home parents.",
          "Adolescent mothers usually live on their own.",
          "More grandparents are raising their grandchildren.",
          "Teenage fathers usually have stronger support systems."
        ],
        "answer": "More grandparents are raising their grandchildren.",
        "explanation": "More grandparents are raising their grandchildren. The majority of women work outside the home, and about 70% of mothers with children under the age of 18 are in the workforce. The majority of adolescent mothers continue to live with their families. Teenage fathers usually have poorer support systems and fewer resources to teach them how to parent.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss current trends in the American family.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A spouse brings the children in to visit their mother in the hospital. The nurse asks how the family is doing. The husband states, “None of her jobs are getting done, and I don’t do those jobs, so the house and the kids are falling apart.” How will the nurse interpret this finding?",
        "options": [
          "The family structure is resilient.",
          "The family structure is flexible.",
          "The family structure is hardy.",
          "The family structure is rigid."
        ],
        "answer": "The family structure is rigid.",
        "explanation": "A rigid structure specifically dictates who is able to accomplish different tasks and also limits the number of persons outside the immediate family allowed to assume these tasks. Resiliency helps to evaluate healthy responses when individuals and families are experiencing stressful events. An extremely flexible structure also presents problems for the family. There is sometimes an absence of stability that would otherwise lead to automatic action during a crisis or rapid change. Hardiness is the internal strength and durability of the family unit characterized by a sense of control over the outcome of life and an active, rather than passive, orientation in adapting to stressful events.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Explain how the relationship between family structure and patterns of functioning affects the health of individuals with in the family and",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse cares for the family’s as well as the patient’s needs using available resources. Which approach is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "Family as context",
          "Family as patient",
          "Family as system",
          "Family as caregivers"
        ],
        "answer": "Family as system",
        "explanation": "When you care for the family as a system, you are caring for each family member (family as context) and the family unit (family as patient), using all available environmental, social, psychological, and community resources. When you view the family as context, the primary focus is on the health and development of an individual member existing within a specific environment (i.e., the patient’s family). When you view the family as patient, the family processes and relationships (e.g., parenting or family caregiving) are the primary focuses of nursing care. There is no approach for family as caregivers; rather, it is a term to describe family members caring for other family members usually at home.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Compare family as context to family as patient and explain the way these perspectives influence nursing practice.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who needs constant care in the home setting and for whom most of the care is provided by the patient’s family. Which action should the nurse take to help relieve stress?",
        "options": [
          "Encourage caregiver to do as much as possible.",
          "Focus primarily on the patient.",
          "Point out weaknesses.",
          "Provide education."
        ],
        "answer": "Provide education.",
        "explanation": "Providing education to the family and caregiver helps relieve some of the stress of caregiving. Help the family focus on their strengths instead of on problems and weaknesses. While caregivers desire to care for the loved one, they often feel extreme pressure to do everything; therefore, encouraging the caregiver to do more will add stress. Focusing primarily on the patient will not be beneficial; the entire family is the patient.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the role of families and family members as caregivers.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is working with a patient. When the nurse asks about family members, the patient states that it includes my spouse, children, and aunt and uncle. How will the nurse describe this type of family?",
        "options": [
          "Nuclear",
          "Blended",
          "Extended",
          "Alternative"
        ],
        "answer": "Extended",
        "explanation": "The extended family includes relatives (aunts, uncles, grandparents, and cousins) in addition to the nuclear family. The nuclear family consists of husband and wife (and perhaps one or more children). The blended family is formed when parents bring unrelated children from prior adoptive or foster parenting relationships into a new, joint living situation. Relationships include multi-adult households, “skip-generation” families (grandparents caring for grandchildren), communal groups with children, “nonfamilies” (adults living alone), cohabitating partners, and homosexual couples.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss common family forms and their health implications.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "An emergency department nurse is assessing a child that lives in a car with family members. Which area should the nurse assess closely?",
        "options": [
          "Ears",
          "Eyes",
          "Head",
          "Hands"
        ],
        "answer": "Ears",
        "explanation": "Children of homeless families are often in fair or poor health and have higher rates of asthma, ear infections, stomach problems, and mental illness. Eyes, head, and hands are not as important as the ears.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss factors that promote or impede family health.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is interviewing a patient who is being admitted to the hospital. The patient’s family went home before the nurse’s interview. The nurse asks the patient, “Who decides when to come to the hospital?” What is the rationale for the nurse’s action?",
        "options": [
          "To assess the family form",
          "To assess the family function",
          "To assess the family structure",
          "To assess the family generalization"
        ],
        "answer": "To assess the family structure",
        "explanation": "To assess the family structure, the nurse asks questions that determine the power structure and patterning of roles and tasks (e.g., “Who decides where to go on vacation?”). When focusing on family form, the nurse should begin the family assessment by determining the patient’s definition of family. Family function is the ability of the family to provide emotional support and to cope with health problems or situations. The question asked by the nurse will not assess that. Nurses do not assess family generalization.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Explain how the relationship between family structure and patterns of functioning affects the health of individuals with in the family and",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient injured in a motor vehicle accident. Which action by the unlicensed assistive personnel will cause the nurse to intervene?",
        "options": [
          "Tells the family not to leave the bedside.",
          "Offers the family a sandwich.",
          "Gives the family a blanket.",
          "Sits with the family."
        ],
        "answer": "Tells the family not to leave the bedside.",
        "explanation": "The action of telling the family not to leave is inappropriate and should be corrected. Sometimes telling the family that you will stay with their loved one while they are gone is all they need to feel comfortable in leaving. Offering a sandwich, giving a blanket, and sitting with the family are appropriate and do not require the nurse to intervene. When the victim of trauma is hospitalized, take time to make sure that the family is comfortable. You can bring them something to eat or drink, give them a blanket, or encourage them to get a meal.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss factors that promote or impede family health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using the family as context approach to provide care to a patient. What should the nurse do next?",
        "options": [
          "Assess family patterns versus individual characteristics.",
          "Assess how much the family provides the patient’s basic needs.",
          "Use “family as patient” and “family as context” approaches simultaneously.",
          "Plan care to meet not only the patient’s needs but also those of the family as well."
        ],
        "answer": "Assess how much the family provides the patient’s basic needs.",
        "explanation": "When the nurse views the family as context, the primary focus is on the health and development of an individual member existing within a specific environment (i.e., the patient’s family). Although the focus is on the individual’s health status, the nurse assesses how much the family provides the individual’s basic needs. Family patterns are in the realm of “family as patient” approach. Often, the nurse will use the two simultaneously (family as context and family as patient) with the approach of “family as system.” “Family as patient” involves planning to meet the needs of the patient and those of the family as well.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare family as context to family as patient and explain the way these perspectives influence nursing practice.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse, caring for a patient in hospice, notes that while the patient is getting adequate care, the caregiver is not sleeping well. The nurse also assesses the need for better family nutrition and meals assistance. The nurse discusses these needs with the patient and family and develops a plan of care with them using community resources. Which approach is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "Family as context",
          "Family as patient",
          "Family as system",
          "Family as caregiver"
        ],
        "answer": "Family as system",
        "explanation": "When you care for the family as a system, you are caring for each family member (family as context) and the family unit (family as patient), using all available environmental, social, psychological, and community resources. In family as context, the primary focus is on the health of an individual member. In family as patient, family processes and relationships are the primary focus. Family as caregiver is not an approach to family-focused nursing but is a term used to describe a family member caring for another family member.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare family as context to family as patient and explain the way these perspectives influence nursing practice.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for an older-adult patient who has no apparent family. When questioned about family and the definition of family, the patient states, “I have no family. They’re all gone.” When asked, “Who prepares your meals?” the patient states, “I do, or I go out.” Which approach should the nurse use for this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Family as context",
          "Family as patient",
          "Family as system",
          "Family as caregiver"
        ],
        "answer": "Family as context",
        "explanation": "If only one family member receives nursing care, it is realistic and practical to use the approach “family as context.” Although family nursing is based on the assumption that all people regardless of age are a member of some type of family form, the patient insists that there is no family. The nurse should investigate further. However, at this time, family as patient or as system is not appropriate. Family as caregiver is not an approach but rather is a term to describe a family member caring for another family member.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Compare family as context to family as patient and explain the way these perspectives influence nursing practice.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for an older-adult patient at home who requires teaching for dressing changes. The spouse and adult child are also involved in changing the dressing. Which statement by the nurse will most likely elicit a positive response from the patient and family?",
        "options": [
          "“You’re doing that all wrong. Let me show you how to do it.”",
          "“I don’t know who showed you how to change a dressing, but you’re not doing it right. Let me show you again.”",
          "“You’re hesitant about changing the dressing like I was before I was shown an easier way; would you like to see?”",
          "“I used to change the dressing the same way you are doing it: the wrong way. I’ll show you the right way to do it.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“You’re hesitant about changing the dressing like I was before I was shown an easier way; would you like to see?”",
        "explanation": "When the nurse is confident and skillful instead of coming across as an authority on the subject, the patient’s/family’s defenses will be down, making the patient/family more willing to listen without feeling embarrassed. Respectful communication is necessary. Saying that you’re doing it wrong, you’re not doing it right, or the wrong way is not respectful or necessary.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss the role of families and family members as caregivers.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is providing discharge teaching for an older-adult patient who will need tube feedings at home. The spouse is the only source of care and states “I will not be able to perform the feedings due to arthritis.” Which action should the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Obtain extra feeding supplies.",
          "Arrange for home care.",
          "Cancel the discharge.",
          "Teach the spouse."
        ],
        "answer": "Arrange for home care.",
        "explanation": "Discharge planning with a family involves an accurate assessment of what will be needed for care at the time of discharge, along with any shortcomings in the home setting. If no one can do the feedings properly, the nurse will need to arrange for a home care service referral. Extra feeding supplies will not help the situation if the spouse cannot use them. Canceling the discharge is not an option. Teaching the spouse will not be effective since the spouse is unable to perform the feeding.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Use the nursing process to provide for the health care needs of the family.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing threats concerning the family. Which areas will the nurse include in the assessment? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Homelessness",
          "Domestic violence",
          "Presence of illness",
          "Changing economic status",
          "Rise of homosexual families"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Homelessness",
          "Domestic violence",
          "Presence of illness",
          "Changing economic status"
        ],
        "explanation": "Social scientists have identified five trends as threats facing the family. These include: (1) changing economic status, (2) homelessness, (3) domestic violence, (4) the presence of acute or chronic illness or trauma, and (5) end-of-life care. Homosexual families are not a threat facing the family; in fact, many homosexual couples now define their relationship in family terms.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss current trends in the American family.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing the realms of family life. Which processes will the nurse assess? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Developmental",
          "Interactive",
          "Integrity",
          "Coping",
          "Life"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Developmental",
          "Interactive",
          "Integrity",
          "Coping"
        ],
        "explanation": "The five realms of family life that should be assessed include: developmental, interactive, integrity, coping, and health, not life.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Use the nursing process to provide for the health care needs of the family.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is focusing on the interactive processes of family life and is asking the patient questions. Match the questions the nurse will ask to the interactive process.",
        "options": [
          "Who is the “peacekeeper” of the family?",
          "How are house rules established?",
          "How often does the family hug each other?",
          "Who at your workplace is close to the family?"
        ],
        "matching": [
          "Intimacy expression",
          "Social support",
          "Roles",
          "Family nurturing"
        ],
        "answer": {
          "Intimacy expression": "How often does the family hug each other?",
          "Social support": "Who at your workplace is close to the family?",
          "Roles": "Who is the “peacekeeper” of the family?",
          "Family nurturing": "How are house rules established?"
        },
        "explanation": "In assessing the interactive processes of family life, a nurse poses specific questions to understand different aspects of family dynamics. Exploring intimacy expression involves asking about the frequency of hugs within the family, shedding light on the level of physical and emotional closeness. Queries regarding social support extend beyond the family unit, seeking insights into external relationships and support networks by asking about connections at the patient's workplace. Understanding roles within the family framework involves identifying who serves as the \"peacekeeper,\" unveiling the distribution of responsibilities and dynamics within the family. Inquiring about the establishment of house rules delves into family nurturing, revealing how norms and boundaries are set to create a supportive environment for the family's well-being and development.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Use the nursing process to provide for the health care needs of the family.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      }
    ],
    "chapter11": [
      {
        "question": "When caring for a middle-aged adult exhibiting maladaptive coping skills, the nurse is trying to determine the cause of the patient’s behavior. Which information from a growth and development perspective should the nurse consider when planning care?",
        "options": [
          "Individuals have uniform patterns of growth and development.",
          "Culture usually has no effect on predictable patterns of growth and development.",
          "Health is promoted based on how many developmental failures a patient experiences.",
          "When individuals experience repeated developmental failures, inadequacies sometimes result."
        ],
        "answer": "When individuals experience repeated developmental failures, inadequacies sometimes result.",
        "explanation": "If individuals have repeated development failures, inadequacies sometimes result should be considered. Developmental failures could manifest with ineffective coping skills. However, when an individual experiences successes, health is promoted. Patients have unique patterns of growth and development that are not uniform. Nurses must consider the influence of culture and context on growth and development.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss factors influencing growth and development.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is measuring an infant’s head circumference and height. Which area is the nurse assessing?",
        "options": [
          "Moral development",
          "Cognitive development",
          "Biophysical development",
          "Psychosocial development"
        ],
        "answer": "Biophysical development",
        "explanation": "Biophysical development is how our physical bodies grow and change. Moral development is the difference between right and wrong. Cognitive development comprises changes in intelligence, use of language, and development of thinking. Psychosocial development consists of variations in emotions and relationships with others.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe biophysical developmental theories.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which question will be most appropriate for a nurse to ask when assessing an adult patient for growth and developmental delays?",
        "options": [
          "“How many times per week do you exercise?”",
          "“Are you able to stand on one foot for 5 seconds?”",
          "“Would you please describe your usual activities during the day?”",
          "“How many hours a day do you spend watching television or sitting in front of a computer?”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Would you please describe your usual activities during the day?”",
        "explanation": "Asking the patient to describe usual daily activities will provide the nurse with useful information about the patient’s current patterns. Understanding normal growth and development helps nurses predict, prevent, and detect deviations from patients’ own expected patterns. How many hours are spent watching television or in front of a computer and how many times the patient exercises in a week would not provide the nurse with as much information about the patient’s expected patterns when stated patterns are compared with expected patterns for the patient’s age-group to detect delays. The question about standing on one foot is for a child, not an adult.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing implications for the application of developmental principles to patient care.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using the proximodistal pattern to assess an infant’s growth and development as normal. Which assessment finding will the nurse determine as normal?",
        "options": [
          "Bangs objects before turns.",
          "Lifts head before grasps.",
          "Walks before crawls.",
          "Laughs before coos."
        ],
        "answer": "Lifts head before grasps.",
        "explanation": "Lifting the head before grasping is a normal finding according to proximodistal growth. The proximodistal growth pattern starts at the center of the body and moves toward the extremities (e.g., organ systems in the trunk of the body develop before arms and legs). The infant should turn before banging objects and crawl before walking according to the proximodistal pattern of growth. The infant should coo before laughing, but this is not an example of proximodistal; this is an example of language development.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe biophysical developmental theories.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing an 18-month-old toddler. The nurse distinguishes normal from abnormal findings by remembering Gesell’s theory of development. Which information will the nurse consider?",
        "options": [
          "Growth in humans is determined solely by heredity.",
          "Environmental influence does not influence development.",
          "The cephalocaudal pattern describes the sequence in which growth is fastest at the top.",
          "Gene activity influences development but does not affect the sequence of development."
        ],
        "answer": "The cephalocaudal pattern describes the sequence in which growth is fastest at the top.",
        "explanation": "Gesell’s theory of development states that the cephalocaudal pattern describes the sequence in which growth is fastest at the top (e.g., head/brain develop faster than arm and leg coordination). Growth in humans is determined by heredity, genes, and environment. Environment does influence development. Gesell’s theory states that genes direct the sequence of development, but environmental factors also influence development, resulting in developmental changes.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe biophysical developmental theories.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is working with a patient who wants needs to be met and is impatient and demanding when these needs are not met immediately. How should the nurse interpret this finding according to Freud?",
        "options": [
          "The id is functioning.",
          "The ego is functioning.",
          "The superego is functioning.",
          "The Oedipus complex is functioning."
        ],
        "answer": "The id is functioning.",
        "explanation": "The id is functioning. The id (i.e., basic instinctual impulses driven to achieve pleasure) is the most primitive part of the personality and originates in the infant. The infant, in this case the patient, cannot tolerate delay and must have needs met immediately. The ego represents the reality component, mediating conflicts between the environment and the forces of the id. The ego helps people judge reality accurately, regulate impulses, and make good decisions. The third component, the superego, performs regulating, restraining, and prohibiting actions. Often referred to as the conscience, the superego is influenced by the standards of outside social forces (e.g., parent or teacher). The child fantasizes about the parent of the opposite sex as his or her first love interest, known as the Oedipus or Electra complex. By the end of this stage, the child attempts to reduce this conflict by identifying with the parent of the same sex as a way to win recognition and acceptance.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe and compare the psychoanalytical/psychosocial theories proposed by Freud and Erikson.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is teaching a young-adult couple about promoting the health and psychosocial development of their 8-year-old child. Which information from the parent indicates a correct understanding of the teaching?",
        "options": [
          "“We will provide consistent, devoted relationships to meet needs.”",
          "“We will limit choices and provide punishment for mistakes.”",
          "“We will provide proper support for learning new skills.”",
          "“We will instill a strong identity of who our child is.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“We will provide proper support for learning new skills.”",
        "explanation": "An 8-year-old-child would be in the industry versus inferiority stage of development. During this stage, the child needs to be praised (proper support) for accomplishments such as learning new skills. Developing a strong identity is part of the identity versus role confusion stage, usually occurring during puberty. During the autonomy versus shame and doubt stage, limiting choices and harsh punishment lead to feelings of shame and doubt. Providing consistent, devoted relationship to meet needs is usually a part of the trust versus mistrust stage.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe and compare the psychoanalytical/psychosocial theories proposed by Freud and Erikson.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using Jean Piaget’s developmental theory to focus on cognitive development. Which area will the nurse assess in this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Latency",
          "Formal operations",
          "Intimacy versus isolation",
          "The postconventional level"
        ],
        "answer": "Formal operations",
        "explanation": "Jean Piaget’s theory includes four stages in sequential order: sensorimotor, preoperational, concrete operations, and formal operations. Intimacy versus isolation is part of Erik Erikson’s psychosocial theory of development. Latency is stage 4 of Freud’s five-stage psychosexual theory of development. The postconventional level of reasoning is part of Kohlberg’s theory of moral development.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe Piaget’s theory of cognitive development.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a 17-year-old adolescent’s cognitive development. Which behavior indicates the adolescent has reached formal operations?",
        "options": [
          "Uses play to understand surroundings.",
          "Discusses the topic of justice in society.",
          "Hits other students to deal with environmental change.",
          "Questions where the ice is hiding when ice has melted in a drink."
        ],
        "answer": "Discusses the topic of justice in society.",
        "explanation": "Discussing the topic of justice demonstrates that the adolescent is concerned about issues that affect others besides self. In the formal operations period, as adolescents mature, their thinking moves to abstract and theoretical subjects. They have the capacity to reason with respect to possibilities. Hitting would be a common schema during the sensorimotor stage of development. Using play to learn about the environment is indicative of the preoperational stage. During the concrete operations stage (ages 6 to 12 years), children are able to coordinate two concrete perspectives in social and scientific thinking, such as understanding the difference between “hiding” and “melting.”",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe Piaget’s theory of cognitive development.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a 4-year-old patient. Which object will the nurse allow the child to play with safely to foster cognitive development?",
        "options": [
          "The pump administering intravenous fluids",
          "A book to read alone in a quiet place",
          "The blood pressure cuff",
          "A baseball bat"
        ],
        "answer": "The blood pressure cuff",
        "explanation": "Children should be allowed to play with any equipment that is safe, like a blood pressure cuff. A 4-year-old child would be in the preoperational period of cognitive development. Children at this stage are still egocentric. Play is very important to foster cognitive development. The IV pump and bat are not safe pieces of equipment for a 4-year-old child to play with. A 4-year-old child is of preschool age and more than likely is not able to read yet. Also, the book does not allow for any human interaction and communication if he or she reads alone.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe Piaget’s theory of cognitive development.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient follows all the instructions a nurse provides because the patient wants to be perceived as a “good” patient. How should the nurse interpret this information according to moral development?",
        "options": [
          "The patient is in postformal thought reasoning.",
          "The patient is in postconventional reasoning.",
          "The patient is in preconventional reasoning.",
          "The patient is in conventional reasoning."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient is in conventional reasoning.",
        "explanation": "The patient is in conventional reasoning, specifically stage 3: Good Boy-Nice Girl Orientation. The patient wants to win approval from the nurse by “being good.” Developmentalists proposed a fifth stage of cognitive (not moral) development termed postformal thought. Within this stage, adults demonstrate the ability to recognize that answers vary from situation to situation and that solutions need to be sensible. The person finds a balance between basic human rights and obligations and societal rules and regulations in the level of postconventional reasoning. Individuals move away from moral decisions based on authority or conformity to groups to define their own moral values and principles. Preconventional reasoning is the premoral level, in which there is limited cognitive thinking and the individual’s thinking is primarily egocentric. At this stage, thinking is mostly based on likes and pleasures.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply developmental theories when planning interventions in the care of patients throughout the life span.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "An 18-month-old patient is brought into the clinic for evaluation because the parent is concerned because the child hits siblings and says only “No” when communicating verbally. Which recommendation by the nurse will be best for this situation?",
        "options": [
          "Assure the mother that the child is developmentally within specified norms.",
          "Encourage the mother to seek psychological counseling for the child.",
          "Consult the social worker because the child is hitting other children.",
          "Remove all toys from the child’s room until this behavior ceases."
        ],
        "answer": "Assure the mother that the child is developmentally within specified norms.",
        "explanation": "Assure the mother that the child is displaying normal behavior. At 18 months, the child is in the sensorimotor period of development. Piaget describes hitting, looking, grasping, and kicking as normal schemas to deal with the environment. The social worker does not need to be consulted in this case nor is psychological counseling warranted, because the child is exhibiting normal behaviors. Play is an important part of all children’s development. Removing toys and the opportunity to play with them may actually hinder the child’s development.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing implications for the application of developmental principles to patient care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A formerly independent older adult becomes severely withdrawn upon admission to a nursing home. Which action should the nurse take first?",
        "options": [
          "Offer a reward to the patient for participation in all events.",
          "Encourage the patient to eat meals in the dining room with others.",
          "Allow the patient to incorporate personal belongings into the room.",
          "Advise the patient of the importance of attending mandatory activities."
        ],
        "answer": "Allow the patient to incorporate personal belongings into the room.",
        "explanation": "The nurse should first allow the patient to actively participate in an independent activity (the patient was formerly independent), such as preparing the room with personal belongings. Erikson’s theory proposes that the older adult faces integrity versus despair. Offering a reward does not address the need for continued independence. Encouraging eating in the dining room would be a step after fixing the room since it does not address independence, and the question is asking for the first action. Advising the patient to attend all mandatory activities as the first intervention does not allow for the patient’s independence. Some activities may be mandatory, but by first allowing the patient to decorate room, the nurse is fostering independence and is helping the patient feel welcome and more at home, fostering integrity.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply developmental theories when planning interventions in the care of patients throughout the life span.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a 14-year-old patient in the hospital. Which goal will be priority?",
        "options": [
          "Maintain industry.",
          "Maintain identity.",
          "Maintain intimacy.",
          "Maintain initiative."
        ],
        "answer": "Maintain identity.",
        "explanation": "According to Erikson, a 14-year-old adolescent is developing an identity versus role confusion. Maintaining initiative is priority for a 3- to 6-year old. Maintaining industry is priority for a 6- to 11-year old. Maintaining intimacy is for young adults.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing implications for the application of developmental principles to patient care.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is teaching the parents of a 3-year-old child who is at risk for developmental delays. Which instruction will the nurse include in the teaching plan?",
        "options": [
          "Insist that your child discuss various points of view.",
          "Encourage play as your child is exploring the surroundings.",
          "Discuss world events with your child to foster language development.",
          "Actively encourage your child to read lengthy books to foster reading abilities."
        ],
        "answer": "Encourage play as your child is exploring the surroundings.",
        "explanation": "A 3-year-old child is going to use play to learn and discover the surrounding environment. Children at this age are egocentric and often are unable to see the world from any perspective other than their own. Very young children are not able to understand and comment on world events because their thinking has not advanced to abstract reasoning yet. A 3-year-old child is likely unable to read; lengthy is not appropriate.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply developmental theories when planning interventions in the care of patients throughout the life span.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a young adult after surgery. Which action by the nurse will be priority?",
        "options": [
          "Allow involvement of peers.",
          "Allow involvement of partner.",
          "Allow involvement of volunteer activities.",
          "Allow involvement of consistent schedule."
        ],
        "answer": "Allow involvement of partner.",
        "explanation": "Nurses must understand that during hospitalization, a young adult’s need for intimacy remains present; thus young adults benefit from the support of their partner or significant other during this time. Involvement of peers is priority for adolescents. Volunteer activities are priority for middle-aged adults. Consistent schedule is priority for infants and toddlers.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing implications for the application of developmental principles to patient care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse takes the history of a middle-aged patient in a health clinic. Which information indicates the patient has achieved generativity?",
        "options": [
          "Married for 30 years.",
          "Teaches preschoolers.",
          "Has no regrets with life choices.",
          "Cares for aging parents after work."
        ],
        "answer": "Teaches preschoolers.",
        "explanation": "Teaching preschoolers indicates generativity. Middle-aged adults achieve success (generativity) in this stage by contributing to future generations through parenthood, teaching, mentoring, and community involvement. Married for 30 years indicates achievement of intimacy. Having no regrets is associated with ego integrity. Caring for aging parents is admirable but it does not indicate development of the next generation (generativity).",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing implications for the application of developmental principles to patient care.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which action should the nurse take when teaching a 5-year-old patient about a scheduled surgery?",
        "options": [
          "Do not discuss the procedure with the child to decrease anxiety.",
          "Let the child know the surgery will be at 9:00 AM in the morning.",
          "Insist that the parents wait outside the room to ensure privacy of the child.",
          "Allow the child to touch and hold medical equipment such as thermometers."
        ],
        "answer": "Allow the child to touch and hold medical equipment such as thermometers.",
        "explanation": "Nursing interventions during the preoperational period (ages 2 to 7 years) should recognize the use of play (such as handling equipment) to help the child understand the events taking place. The nurse should talk to the child about the procedure in terms the child can understand. Children at this stage have difficulty conceptualizing time; telling the child surgery is at 9:00 AM in the morning is inappropriate. Parents should be allowed in the room.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply developmental theories when planning interventions in the care of patients throughout the life span.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse works on a pediatric unit and is using a psychosocial developmental approach to child care. In which order from the first to the last will the nurse place the developmental stages?\n1. Initiative versus guilt\n2. Trust versus mistrust\n3. Industry versus inferiority\n4. Identity versus role confusion\n5. Autonomy versus shame and doubt",
        "options": [
          "2, 5, 3, 1, 4",
          "2, 1, 3, 5, 4",
          "2, 3, 1, 5, 4",
          "2, 5, 1, 3, 4"
        ],
        "answer": "2, 5, 1, 3, 4",
        "explanation": "Erikson uses a psychosocial approach to development. The stages are as follows: trust versus mistrust, autonomy versus shame and doubt, initiative versus guilt, industry versus inferiority, and identity versus role confusion.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe and compare the psychoanalytical/psychosocial theories proposed by Freud and Erikson.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is developing a plan of care concerning growth and development for a hospitalized adolescent. What interventions should the nurse implement? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Apply developmental theories when making observations of the adolescent’s patterns of growth and development.",
          "Compare the adolescent’s assessment findings versus normal findings.",
          "Recognize one’s own (the nurse’s) moral developmental level.",
          "Focus on one developmental theory for consistency.",
          "Apply a unidimensional life span perspective."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Apply developmental theories when making observations of the adolescent’s patterns of growth and development.",
          "Compare the adolescent’s assessment findings versus normal findings.",
          "Recognize one’s own (the nurse’s) moral developmental level."
        ],
        "explanation": "Today’s nurses need to be knowledgeable about several theoretical perspectives when working with patients. These theories form the basis for meaningful observation of an individual’s pattern of growth and development. They provide important guidelines for nurses to recognize deviations from the norm. Recognizing your own moral developmental level is essential in separating your own beliefs from those of others when helping patients with their moral decision-making process. No one theory successfully describes all the intricacies of human growth and development. Growth and development, as supported by a life span perspective, is multidimensional, not unidimensional.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply developmental theories when planning interventions in the care of patients throughout the life span.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing temperaments of children. Which terms should the nurse use to describe findings? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "The easy child",
          "The defiant child",
          "The difficult child",
          "The slow-to-warm up child",
          "The momma’s boy or daddy’s girl"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "The easy child",
          "The difficult child",
          "The slow-to-warm up child"
        ],
        "explanation": "Psychiatrists identified three basic classes of temperament: the easy child, the difficult child, and the slow-to-warm up child. There is no momma’s boy or daddy’s girl or defiant child.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Apply developmental theories when planning interventions in the care of patients throughout the life span.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      }
    ],
    "chapter22": [
        {
            "question": "Four patients in labor all request epidural analgesia to manage their pain at the same time. Which ethical principle is most compromised when only one nurse anesthetist is on call?",
            "options": ["Justice", "Fidelity", "Beneficence", "Nonmaleficence"],
            "answer": "Justice",
            "explanation": "Justice refers to fairness and is used frequently in discussion regarding access to health care resources. Here the just distribution of resources, in this case pain management, cannot be justly apportioned Nonmaleficence refers to avoidance of harm; beneficence refers to taking positive actions to help others. Fidelity refers to the agreement to keep promises. Each of these principles is partially expressed in the question; however, justice is most comprised because not all laboring patients have equal access to pain management owing to lack of personnel resources.",
            "dif": "Apply(application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the role of ethics in professional nursing.",
            "top": "Caring",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
        },
        {
            "question": "The patient reports to the nurse of being afraid to speak up regarding a desire to end care for fear of upsetting spouse and children. Which principle in the nursing code of ethics ensures that the nurse will promote the patient's cause?",
            "options": ["Advocacy", "Responsibility", "Confidentiality", "Accountability"],
            "answer": "Advocacy",
            "explanation": "Nurses advocate for patients when they support the patient's cause. A nurse's ability to adequately advocate for a patient is based on the unique relationship that develops and the opportunity to better understand the patient's point of view. Responsibility refers to respecting one's professional obligations and following through on promises. Confidentiality deals with privacy issues, and accountability refers to answering for one's actions.",
            "dif": "Apply(application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the role of ethics in professional nursing.",
            "top": "Caring",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "The patient's son requests to view documentation in the medical record. What is the nurse's best response to this request?",
            "options": ["I'll be happy to get that for you.", "You are not allowed to look at it.", "You will need your mother's permission.", "I cannot let you see the chart without a doctor's order."],
            "answer": "You will need your mother's permission.",
            "explanation": "The mother's permission is needed. The nurse understands that sharing health information is governed by HIPAA legislation, which defines rights and privileges of patients for protection of privacy. Private health information cannot be shared without the patient's specific permission. The nurse cannot obtain the records without permission. The son can look at it after approval from the patient. While talking to the physician or getting an order is appropriate, the patient still has to give consent.",
            "dif": "Analyze(analysis)",
            "obj": "Discuss the role of ethics in professional nursing.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "When professionals work together to solve ethical dilemmas, nurses must examine their own values. What is the best rationale for this step?",
            "options": ["So fact is separated from opinion.", "So different perspectives are respected.", "So judgmental attitudes can be provoked.", "So the group identifies the one correct solution."],
            "answer": "So different perspectives are respected.",
            "explanation": "Values are personal beliefs that influence behavior. To negotiate differences of value, it is important to be clear about your own values: what you value, why, and how you respect your own values even as you try to respect those of others whose values differ from yours. Ethical dilemmas are a problem in that no one right solution exists. It is not to separate fact from opinion. Judgmental attitudes are not to be used, much less provoked.",
            "dif": "Analyze(analysis)",
            "obj": "Discuss the role of values in the study of ethics.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
        },
        {
            "question": "A nurse is experiencing an ethical dilemma with a patient. Recognizing what information as a factor indicates the nurse has a correct understanding of the primary cause of ethical dilemmas?",
            "options": ["Unequal power", "Presence of conflicting values", "Judgmental perceptions of patients", "Poor communication with the patient"],
            "answer": "Presence of conflicting values",
            "explanation": "Ethical dilemmas almost always occur in the presence of conflicting values. While unequal power, judgmental perceptions, and poor communication can contribute to the dilemma, these are not causes of a dilemma. Without clarification of values, the nurse may not be able to distinguish fact from opinion or value, and this can lead to judgmental attitudes.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the role of values in the study of ethics.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nurse questions a health care provider's decision to not tell the patient about a cancer diagnosis. Which ethical principle is the nurse trying to uphold for the patient?",
            "options": ["Consequentialism", "Autonomy", "Fidelity", "Justice"],
            "answer": "Autonomy",
            "explanation": "The nurse is upholding autonomy. Autonomy refers to the freedom to make decisions free of external control. Respect for patient autonomy refers to the commitment to include patients in decisions about all aspects of care. Consequentialism is focused on the outcome and is a philosophical approach. Justice refers to fairness and is most often used in discussions about access to health care resources. Fidelity refers to the agreement to keep promises.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Examine and clarify personal values.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nurse finds it difficult to care for a patient whose advance directive states that no extraordinary resuscitation measures should be taken. Which step may help the nurse to find resolution in this assignment?",
            "options": ["Review one's own personal values.", "Call for an ethical committee consult.", "Decline the assignment on religious grounds.", "Convince the family to challenge the directive."],
            "answer": "Review one's own personal values.",
            "explanation": "Clarifying values—your own, your patients', your co-workers'—is an important and effective part of ethical discourse. Calling for a consult, declining the assignment, and convincing the family to challenge the patient's directive are not ideal resolutions because they do not address the reason for the nurse's discomfort, which is the conflict between the nurse's values and those of the patient. The nurse should value the patient's decisions over the nurse's personal values.",
            "dif": "Apply(application)",
            "obj": "Examine and clarify personal values.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nurse values autonomy above all other principles. Which patient assignment will the nurse find most difficult to accept?",
            "options": ["Older-adult patient who requires dialysis.", "Teenager in labor who requests epidural anesthesia.", "Middle-aged father of three with an advance directive declining life support.", "Family elder who is making the decisions for a young-adult female member."],
            "answer": "Family elder who is making the decisions for a young-adult female member.",
            "explanation": "Autonomy refers to freedom from external control. A person who values autonomy highly may find it difficult to accept situations where the patient is not the primary decision maker regarding his or her care. A teenager requesting an epidural, a father with an advance directive, and an elderly patient requiring dialysis all describe a patient or family who can make their own decisions and choices regarding care.",
            "dif": "Analyze(analysis)",
            "obj": "Examine and clarify personal values.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "A nurse must make an ethical decision concerning vulnerable patient populations. Which philosophy of health care ethics would be particularly useful for this nurse?",
            "options": ["Teleology", "Deontology", "Utilitarianism", "Feminist ethics"],
            "answer": "Feminist ethics",
            "explanation": "Feminist ethics particularly focuses on the nature of relationships, especially those where there is a power imbalance or a point of view that is ignored or invisible. Deontology refers to making decisions or “right-making characteristics,” bioethics focuses on consensus building, while utilitarianism and teleology speak to the greatest good for the greatest number.",
            "dif": "Apply(application)",
            "obj": "understand the basic philosophies of health care and ethics.",
            "top": "Caring",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "A nurse agrees with regulations for mandatory immunizations of children. The nurse believes that immunizations prevent diseases as well as prevent spread of the disease to others. Which ethical framework is the nurse using?",
            "options": ["Deontology", "Ethics of care", "Utilitarianism", "Feminist ethics"],
            "answer": "Utilitarianism",
            "explanation": "Utilitarianism is a system of ethics that believes that value is determined by usefulness. This system of ethics focuses on the outcome of the greatest good for the greatest number of people. Deontology would not look to consequences of actions but on the “right-making characteristic” such as fidelity and justice. The ethics of care emphasizes the role of feelings. Relationships, which are an important component of feminist ethics, are not addressed in this case.",
            "dif": "Analyze(analysis)",
            "obj": "understand the basic philosophies of health care and ethics.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nurse has become aware of missing narcotics in the patient care area. Which ethical principle obligates the nurse to report the missing medications?",
            "options": ["Advocacy", "Responsibility", "Confidentiality", "Accountability"],
            "answer": "Responsibility",
            "explanation": "Responsibility refers to one's willingness to respect and adhere to one's professional obligations. It is the nurse's responsibility to report missing narcotics. Accountability refers to the ability to answer for one's actions. Advocacy refers to the support of a particular cause. The concept of confidentiality is very important in health care and involves protecting patients' personal health information.",
            "dif": "Apply(application)",
            "obj": "Explain a nursing perspective in ethics.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
        },
        {
            "question": "A young woman who is pregnant with a fetus exposed to multiple teratogens consents to have her fetus undergo serial PUBS(percutaneous umbilical blood sampling) to examine how exposure affects the fetus over time. Although these tests will not improve the fetus's outcomes and will expose it to some risks, the information gathered may help infants in the future. Which ethical principle is at greatest risk?",
            "options": ["Fidelity", "Autonomy", "Beneficence", "Nonmaleficence"],
            "answer": "Nonmaleficence",
            "explanation": "Nonmaleficence is the ethical principle that focuses on avoidance of harm or hurt. Repeated PUBS may expose the mother and fetus to some risks. Fidelity refers to the agreement to keep promises (obtain serial PUBS). Autonomy refers to freedom from external control (mother consented), and beneficence refers to taking positive actions to help others (may help infants in the future).",
            "dif": "Analyze(analysis)",
            "obj": "Apply critical thinking to ethical dillemas.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "A nurse is discussing quality of life issues with another colleague. Which topic will the nurse acknowledge for increased attention paid to quality of life concerns?",
            "options": ["Health care disparities", "Aging of the population", "Abilities of disabled persons", "Health care financial reform"],
            "answer": "Abilities of disabled persons",
            "explanation": "The population of disabled persons in the United States and elsewhere has reshaped the discussion about quality of life (QOL). Health care disparities, an aging population, and health care reform are components impacted by personal definitions of quality but are not the underlying reason why QOL discussions have arisen.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss contemporary ethical issues.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which action by the nurse indicates a safe and efficient use of social networks?",
            "options": ["Promotes support for a local health charity.", "Posts a picture of a patient's infected foot.", "Vents about a patient problem at work.", "Friends a patient."],
            "answer": "Promotes support for a local health charity.",
            "explanation": "Social networks can be a supportive source of information about patient care or professional nursing activities. Even if you post an image of a patient without any obvious identifiers, the nature of shared media reposting can result in the image surfacing in a place where just the context of the image provides clues for friends or family to identify the patient. The ANA and NCSBN states, “Effective nurse-patient relationships are built on trust. Patients need to be confident that their most personal information and their basic dignity will be protected by the nurse.” Becoming friends in online chat rooms, Facebook, or other public sites can interfere with your ability to maintain a therapeutic relationship.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss contemporary ethical issues.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a dying patient. Which intervention is considered futile?",
            "options": ["Giving pain medication for pain", "Providing oral care every 5 hours", "Administering the influenza vaccine", "Supporting lower extremities with pillows"],
            "answer": "Administering the influenza vaccine",
            "explanation": "Administering the influenza vaccine is futile. A vaccine is administered to prevent or lessen the likelihood of contracting an infectious disease at some time in the future. The term futile refers to something that is hopeless or serves no useful purpose. In health care discussions, the term refers to interventions unlikely to produce benefit for a patient. Care delivered to a patient at the end of life that is focused on pain management, oral hygiene, and comfort measures is not futile.",
            "dif": "Analyze(analysis)",
            "obj": "Discuss contemporary ethical issues.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
        },
        {
            "question": "During a severe respiratory epidemic, the local health care organizations decide to give health care workers priority access to ventilators over other members of the community who also need that resource. Which philosophy would give the strongest support for this decision?",
            "options": ["Deontology", "Utilitarianism", "Ethics of care", "Feminist ethics"],
            "answer": "Utilitarianism",
            "explanation": "Utilitarianism focuses on the greatest good for the most people; the organizations decide to ensure that as many health care workers as possible will survive to care for other members of the community. Deontology defines actions as right or wrong based on their “right-making characteristics” such as fidelity to promises, truthfulness, and justice. Feminist ethics looks to the nature of relationships to guide participants in making difficult decisions, especially relationships in which power is unequal or in which a point of view has become ignored or invisible. The ethics of care and feminist ethics are closely related, but ethics of care emphasizes the role of feelings.",
            "dif": "Apply(application)",
            "obj": "Understand the basic philosophies of health care ethics.",
            "top": "Caring",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient and family about quality of life. Which information should the nurse include in the teaching session about quality of life?",
            "options": ["It is deeply social.", "It is hard to define and deeply personal", "It is an observed measurement for most people.", "It is consistent and stable over the course of one's lifetime."],
            "answer": "It is hard to define and deeply personal",
            "explanation": "Quality of life remains deeply individual (not social) and difficult to predict. Quality of life is not just a measurable entity but a shared responsibility. Quality of life measures may take into account the age of the patient, the patient's ability to live independently, his or her ability to contribute to society in a gainful way, and other nuanced measures of quality.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss contemporary ethical issues.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient supported with a ventilator who has been unresponsive since arrival via ambulance 8 days ago. The patient has not been identified, and no family members have been found. The nurse is concerned about the plan of care regarding maintenance or withdrawal of life support measures. Place the steps the nurse will use to resolve this ethical dilemma in the correct order. \n1. The nurse identifies possible solutions or actions to resolve the dilemma.\n2. The nurse reviews the medical record, including entries by all health care disciplines, to gather information relevant to this patient's situation.\n3. Health care providers use negotiation to redefine the patient's plan of care.\n4. The nurse evaluates the plan and revises it with input from other health care providers as necessary.\n5. The nurse examines the issue to clarify opinions, values, and facts.\n6. The nurse states the problem.\n7. Nurse confirms that the problem is ethical in nature",
            "options": [
              "6, 7, 1, 2, 5, 4, 3",
              "5, 6, 7, 2, 3, 4, 1",
              "1, 2, 5, 4, 7, 3, 6",
              "7, 2, 5, 6, 1, 3, 4"
            ],
            "answer": "7, 2, 5, 6, 1, 3, 4",
            "explanation": "Step 1. Ask the question: is this an ethical problem?\nStep 2. Gather as much information as possible that is relevant to the case.\nStep 3. Examine and determine your values about the issues.\nStep 4. Verbalize and name the problem.\nStep 5. Consider possible courses of action.\nStep 6. Negotiate the outcome by creating and implementing a plan of action.\nStep 7. Evaluate the action.",
            "dif": "Analyze(analysis)",
            "obj": "Apply critical thinking to ethical dillemas.",
            "top": "Caring",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
            "question": "A nurse is a member of the ethics committee. Which roles will the nurse fulfill in this committee? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Educator",
              "Case consultant",
              "Purchasing Agent",
              "Direct patient care provider",
              "Policy reviewer and recommender"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Educator",
                "Case consultant",
                "Policy reviewer and recommender"
            ],
            "explanation": "An ethics committee devoted to the teaching and processing of ethical issues and dilemmas exists in most health care facilities. It is generally multidisciplinary and it serves several purposes: education, policy recommendation, and case consultation. It does not have purchasing power or provide direct patient care.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Explain a nursing perspective in ethics.",
            "top": "Caring",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          }
    ],
    "chapter23": [
        {
          "question": "A newly hired experienced nurse is preparing to change a patient's abdominal dressing and hasn't done it before at this hospital. Which action by the nurse is best?",
          "options": [
            "Have another nurse do it so the correct method can be viewed.",
            "Change the dressing using the method taught in nursing school.",
            "Ask the patient how the dressing change has been recently done.",
            "Check the policy and procedure manual for the facility's method."
          ],
          "answer": "Check the policy and procedure manual for the facility's method.",
          "explanation": "The Joint Commission requires accredited hospitals to have written nursing policies and procedures. These internal standards of care are specific and need to be accessible on all nursing units. For example, a policy/procedure outlining the steps to follow when changing a dressing or administering medication provides specific information about how nurses are to perform. The nurse being observed may not be doing the procedure according to the facility's policy or procedure. The procedure taught in nursing school may not be consistent with the policy or procedure for this facility. The patient is not responsible for maintaining the standards of practice. Patient input is important, but it's not what directs nursing practice.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "List sources of standards of care for nurses.",
          "top": "Planning",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A new nurse notes that the health care unit keeps a listing of patient names in a closed book behind the front desk of the nursing station so patients can be located easily. Which action is most appropriate for the nurse to take?",
          "options": [
            "Talk with the nurse manager about the listing being a violation of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).",
            "Use the book as needed while keeping it away from individuals not involved in patient care.",
            "Move the book to the upper ledge of the nursing station for easier access.",
            "Ask the nurse manager to move the book to a more secluded area."
          ],
          "answer": "Use the book as needed while keeping it away from individuals not involved in patient care.",
          "explanation": "The book is located where only staff would have access so the nurse can use the book as needed. The privacy section of the HIPAA provides standards regarding accountability in the health care setting. These rules include patient rights to consent to the use and disclosure of their protected health information, to inspect and copy their medical record, and to amend mistaken or incomplete information. It is not the responsibility of the new nurse to move items used by others on the patient unit. The listing is protected as long as it is used appropriately as needed to provide care. There is no need to move the book to a more secluded area.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Describe the legal obligations and role of the nurse regarding federal and state laws that affect health care.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A 17-year-old patient, dying of heart failure, wants to have organs removed for transplantation after death. Which action by the nurse is correct?",
          "options": [
            "Instruct the patient to talk with parents about the desire to donate organs.",
            "Notify the health care provider about the patient's desire to donate organs.",
            "Prepare the organ donation form for the patient to sign while still oriented.",
            "Contact the United Network for Organ Sharing after talking with the patient."
          ],
          "answer": "Instruct the patient to talk with parents about the desire to donate organs.",
          "explanation": "In this situation, the parents would need to sign the form because the teenager is under age 18. An individual who is at least 18 may sign the form allowing organ donation upon death. The nurse cannot allow the patient to sign the organ donation document because the patient is younger than age 18. The health care provider will be notified about the patient's wishes after the parents agree to donate the organs. The United Network for Organ Sharing (UNOS) has a contract with the federal government and sets policies and guidelines for the procurement of organs.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze legal aspects of nurse-patient, nurse-health care provider, nurse-nurse, and nurse-employer relationships.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "An obstetric nurse comes across an automobile accident. The driver seems to have a crushed upper airway, and while waiting for emergency medical services to arrive, the nurse makes a cut in the trachea and inserts a straw from a purse to provide an airway. The patient survives and has a permanent problem with vocal cords, making it difficult to talk. Which statement is true regarding the nurse's performance?",
          "options": [
            "The nurse acted appropriately and saved the patient's life.",
            "The nurse stayed within the guidelines of the Good Samaritan Law.",
            "The nurse took actions beyond those that are standard and appropriate.",
            "The nurse should have just stayed with the patient and waited for help."
          ],
          "answer": "The nurse took actions beyond those that are standard and appropriate.",
          "explanation": "An obstetric nurse would not have been trained in performing a tracheostomy (cut in the trachea) and doing so would be beyond what the nurse has been trained or educated to do. If you perform a procedure exceeding your scope of practice and for which you have no training, you are liable for injury that may result from that act. You should only provide care that is consistent with your level of expertise. The nurse did not act appropriately. The nurse is not protected by the Good Samaritan Law because the nurse acted outside the scope of practice and training. The nurse should have acted within what was trained and educated to do in this circumstance, not just stay with the patient.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Explain the legal concept of standard of care and informed consent.",
          "top": "Evaluation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A nurse performs cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) on a 92 year old with brittle bones and breaks a rib during the procedure, which then punctures a lung. The patient recovers completely without any residual problems and sues the nurse for pain and suffering and for malpractice. Which key point will the prosecution attempt to prove against the nurse?",
          "options": [
            "The CPR procedure was done incorrectly.",
            "The patient would have died if nothing was done.",
            "The patient was resuscitated according to the policy.",
            "The older patient with brittle bones might sustain fractures when chest compressions are done."
          ],
          "answer": "The CPR procedure was done incorrectly.",
          "explanation": "Certain criteria are necessary to establish nursing malpractice. The prosecution would try to prove that a breach of duty had occurred (CPR done incorrectly), which had caused injury. The defense team, not the prosecution, would explain the correlation between brittle bones and rib fractures during CPR and that the patient was resuscitated according to policy. In this situation, although harm was caused, it was not because of failure of the nurse to perform a duty according to standards, the way other nurses would have performed in the same situation. The fact that the patient sustained injury, as a result of age and physical status, does not mean the nurse breached any duty to the patient. The nurse would need to make sure the defense attorney knew that the cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) was done correctly. Without intervention, the patient most likely would not have survived.",
          "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
          "obj": "List the elements needed to establish negligence.",
          "top": "Evaluation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A recent immigrant who does not speak English is alert but requires hospitalization. What is the initial action that the nurse must take to enable informed consent to be obtained?",
          "options": [
            "Ask a family member to translate what the nurse is saying.",
            "Request an official interpreter to explain the terms of consent.",
            "Notify the nursing manager that the patient doesn't speak English.",
            "Use hand gestures and medical equipment while explaining in English."
          ],
          "answer": "Request an official interpreter to explain the terms of consent.",
          "explanation": "An official interpreter must be present to explain the terms of consent if a patient speaks only a foreign language. A family member or acquaintance who speaks a patient's language should not interpret health information. Family members can tell those caring for the patient what the patient is saying, but privacy regarding the patient's condition, assessment, etc., must be protected. A nurse can take care of requesting an interpreter, and the nurse manager is not needed. Using hand gestures and medical equipment is inappropriate when communicating with a patient who does not understand the language spoken. Certain hand gestures may be acceptable in one culture and not appropriate in another. The medical equipment may be unknown and frightening to the patient, and the patient still doesn't understand what is being said.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Explain the legal concept of standard of care and informed consent.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A pediatric oncology nurse floats to an orthopedic trauma unit. Which action should the nurse manager of the orthopedic unit take to enable safe care to be given by this nurse?",
          "options": [
            "Provide a complete orientation to the functioning of the entire unit.",
            "Determine patient acuity and care the nurse can safely provide.",
            "Allow the nurse to choose which mealtime works best.",
            "Assign nursing assistive personnel to assist with care."
          ],
          "answer": "Determine patient acuity and care the nurse can safely provide.",
          "explanation": "Supervisors are liable if they give staff nurses an assignment that they cannot safely handle. Nurses who float must inform the supervisor of any lack of experience in caring for the types of patients on the nursing unit. They should request and receive an orientation to the unit. A basic orientation is needed, whereas a complete orientation of the functioning of the entire unit would take a period of time that would exceed what the nurse has to spend on orientation. Allowing nurses to choose which mealtime they would like is a nice gesture of thanks for the nurse, but it does not enable safe care. Having nursing assistive personnel may help the nurse complete basic tasks such as hygiene and turning, but it does not enable safe nursing care that the nurse and manager are ultimately responsible for.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze legal aspects of nurse-patient, nurse-health care provider, nurse-nurse, and nurse-employer relationships.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "While recovering from a severe illness, a hospitalized patient wants to change a living will, which was signed 9 months ago. Which response by the nurse is most appropriate?",
          "options": [
            "“Check with your admitting health care provider whether a copy is on your chart.”",
            "“Let me check with someone here in the hospital who can assist you.”",
            "“You are not allowed to ever change a living will after signing it.”",
            "“Your living will can be changed only once each calendar year.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Let me check with someone here in the hospital who can assist you.”",
          "explanation": "As long as the patient is not declared legally incompetent or lacks the capacity to make decisions, living wills can be changed. It is the nurse's responsibility to find an appropriate person in the facility to assist the patient. Checking with the health care provider about the presence of a living will on the chart has nothing to do with the patient's desire to change the living will. The question states that the patient wants to change a living will. A living will can be changed whenever the patient decides to change it, as long as the patient is competent.",
          "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
          "obj": "Describe the legal obligations and role of the nurse regarding federal and state laws that affect health care.",
          "top": "Communication and Documentation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A home health nurse notices that a patient's preschool children are often playing on the sidewalk and in the street unsupervised and repeatedly takes them back to the home and talks with the patient, but the situation continues. Which immediate action by the nurse is mandated by law?",
          "options": [
            "Contact the appropriate community child protection facility.",
            "Tell the parents that the authorities will be contacted shortly.",
            "Take pictures of the children to support the overt child abuse.",
            "Discuss with both parents about the safety needs of their children."
          ],
          "answer": "Contact the appropriate community child protection facility.",
          "explanation": "The nurse has a duty to report this situation to protect the children. Any health care professional who does not report suspected child abuse or neglect may be liable for civil or criminal legal action. Talking with both parents is not mandated by law. There is no obligation to tell the parents that they will be reported to authorities. There is no obligation for the nurse to take pictures of the children.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Describe the legal obligations and role of the nurse regarding federal and state laws that affect health care.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A confused patient with a urinary catheter, nasogastric tube, and intravenous line keeps touching these needed items for care. The nurse has tried to explain to the patient that these lines should not be touched, but the patient continues. Which is the best action by the nurse at this time?",
          "options": [
            "Apply restraints loosely on the patient's dominant wrist.",
            "Notify the health care provider that restraints are needed immediately.",
            "Try other approaches to prevent the patient from touching these care items.",
            "Allow the patient to pull out lines to prove that the patient needs to be restrained."
          ],
          "answer": "Try other approaches to prevent the patient from touching these care items.",
          "explanation": "Restraints can be used when less restrictive interventions are not successful. The nurse must try other approaches than just telling. The situation states that the patient is touching the items, not trying to pull them out. At this time, the patient's well-being is not at risk so restraints cannot be used at this time nor does the health care provider need to be notified. Allowing the patient to pull out any of these items to prove the patient needs to be restrained is not acceptable.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Describe the legal obligations and role of the nurse regarding federal and state laws that affect health care.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
        },
        {
          "question": "A patient has sued a post-surgical unit nurse who provided care after abdominal surgery with nursing malpractice. Which resource would be used to determine whether the nurse has acted in a prudent manner?",
          "options": [
            "Scope and Standards of Nursing Care",
            "The typical level of care provided by other unit nurses",
            "The testimony of the patient's primary health care provider",
            "Comparison of documentation of the care provided by the nurse to similar patients"
          ],
          "answer": "Scope and Standards of Nursing Care",
          "explanation": "During a malpractice suit, a nurse's actual conduct is compared to nursing standards of care (i.e., Scope and Standards of Nursing Care [ANA, 2015]) to determine whether the nurse acted as any reasonably prudent nurse would act under the same or similar circumstances. None of the other options would serve to validate the care that was appropriate for the patient at this time and by the nurse providing the care.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Describe the legal obligations and role of the nurse regarding federal and state laws that affect health care.",
          "top": "Communication and Documentation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "How can a nurse assigned to a medical unit at a local hospital best address issues related to the delivery of quality nursing care?",
          "options": [
            "Serve as a volunteer patient advocate at the local free health clinic.",
            "Become active in professional nursing organizations at the state level.",
            "Ask to be a member of the hospital's policy and procedure committee",
            "Agree to act as a preceptor for nursing students during their clinical experience"
          ],
          "answer": "Become active in professional nursing organizations at the state level.",
          "explanation": "As a professional nurse, it is important to remain aware of current issues in health care. Become involved in professional organizations and committees that define the standards of care for nursing practice. If current laws, rules and regulations, or policies under which nurses practice are not evidence based, advocate to ensure that the scope of nursing practice is defined accurately. While the other options are all associated with effecting quality nursing care, none have the degree of effectiveness as working directly with nursing organizations to define standards of nursing care.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Describe the legal obligations and role of the nurse regarding federal and state laws that affect health care.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A nursing student has been written up several times for being late with providing patient care and for omitting aspects of patient care and not knowing basic procedures that were taught in the skills course one term earlier. The nursing student says, “I don't understand what the big deal is. As my instructor, you are there to protect me and make sure I don't make mistakes.” What is the best response from the nursing instructor?",
          "options": [
            "“You are practicing under the license of the hospital's insurance.”",
            "“You are expected to perform at the level of a professional nurse.”",
            "“You are expected to perform at the level of a prudent nursing student.”",
            "“You are practicing under the license of the nurse assigned to the patient.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“You are expected to perform at the level of a professional nurse.”",
          "explanation": "Although nursing students are not employees of the health care facility where they are having their clinical experience, they are expected to perform as professional nurses would in providing safe patient care. Different levels of standards do not apply. No standard is used for nursing students other than that they must meet the standards of a professional nurse. Student nurses do not practice under anybody's license; nursing students are liable if their actions exceed their scope of practice or cause harm to patients.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze legal aspects of nurse-patient, nurse-health care provider, nurse-nurse, and nurse-employer relationships.",
          "top": "Communication and Documentation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A nurse works full time on the oncology unit at the hospital and works part time on weekends giving immunizations at the local chain pharmacy. While giving an injection on a weekend, the nurse caused injury to the patient's arm and is now being sued. What initial action should the nurse take to initiate an effective legal defense?",
          "options": [
            "Notify the hospital of the situation to secure legal counsel by the hospital's private attorney.",
            "Notify the manager of the pharmacy so that the corporation can provide legal counsel.",
            "Inform the insurance company that is providing one's professional licensure defense insurance.",
            "Immediately contact the State Board of Nursing to assure protecting the validity of the nursing license."
          ],
          "answer": "Inform the insurance company that is providing one's professional licensure defense insurance.",
          "explanation": "Nurses often presume that either their personal or their employer's malpractice insurance will include costs of defending and retaining their nursing license. In most instances this is not true. Professional licensure defense insurance is a contract between a nurse and an insurance company. When a complaint is made to the State Board of Nursing, an action is initiated that could result in a restriction, suspension, or revocation of the nurse's license to practice. When a nurse specifically has professional licensure defense insurance, the nurse notifies the company. In this situation, neither employer should be relied upon to provide effective legal counsel.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze legal aspects of nurse-patient, nurse-health care provider, nurse-nurse, and nurse-employer relationships.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A female nursing student in the final term of nursing school is overheard by a nursing faculty member telling another student that she got to insert a nasogastric tube in the emergency department while working as a nursing assistant. Which advice is best for the nursing faculty member to give to the nursing student?",
          "options": [
            "“Just be careful when you are doing new procedures and make sure you are following directions by the nurse.”",
            "“Review your procedures before you go to work, so you will be prepared to do them if you have a chance.”",
            "“The nurse should not have allowed you to insert the nasogastric tube because something bad could have happened.”",
            "“You are not allowed to perform any procedures other than those in your job description even with the nurse's permission.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“You are not allowed to perform any procedures other than those in your job description even with the nurse's permission.”",
          "explanation": "When nursing students work as nursing assistants or nurse's aides when not attending classes, they should not perform tasks that do not appear in a job description for a nurse's aide or assistant. The nursing student should always follow the directions of the nurse, unless doing so violates the institution's guidelines or job description under which the nursing student was hired, such as inserting a nasogastric tube or giving an intramuscular medication. The nursing student should be able to safely complete the procedures delegated as a nursing assistant, and reviewing those not done recently is a good idea, but it has nothing to do with the situation. The focus of the discussion between the nursing faculty member and the nursing student should be on following the job description under which the nursing student is working.",
          "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
          "obj": "List sources of standards of care for nurses.",
          "top": "Communication and Documentation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "The nurse calculates the medication dose for an infant on the pediatric unit and determines that the dose is twice what it should be based upon the drug book's information. The pediatrician is contacted and says to administer the medication as ordered. Which actions should the nurse take next? (Select all that apply.)",
          "options": [
            "Notify the nursing supervisor.",
            "Administer the medication as ordered.",
            "Give the amount listed in the drug book.",
            "Ask the mother to give the drug to her child.",
            "Check the chain of command policy for such situations."
          ],
          "answer": [
            "Notify the nursing supervisor.",
            "Check the chain of command policy for such situations."
          ],
          "explanation": "If the health care provider confirms an order and the nurse still believes that it is inappropriate, the nurse should inform the supervising nurse and follow the established chain of command. Nurses follow health care providers' orders unless they believe the orders are in error or may harm patients. Therefore, the nurse needs to assess all orders. If an order seems to be erroneous or harmful, further clarification from the health care provider is necessary. The supervising nurse should be able to help resolve the questionable order, but only the health care provider who wrote the order or a health care provider covering for the one who wrote the order can change the order. Harm to the infant could occur if the medication is given as ordered. The nurse cannot change an order by giving the amount listed in the drug book. Asking the mother to give the drug is inappropriate.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze legal aspects of nurse-patient, nurse-health care provider, nurse-nurse, and nurse-employer relationships.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "The nurse hears a health care provider say to the charge nurse that a certain nurse cannot care for patients because the nurse is stupid and won't follow orders. The health care provider also writes in the patient's medical records that the same nurse, by name, is not to care for any of the patients because of incompetence. Which torts has the health care provider committed? (Select all that apply.)",
          "options": [
            "Libel",
            "Slander",
            "Assault",
            "Battery",
            "Invasion of privacy"
          ],
          "answer": [
            "Libel",
            "Slander"
          ],
          "explanation": "Slander occurred when the health care provider spoke falsely about the nurse, and libel occurred when the health care provider wrote false information in the chart. Both of these situations could cause problems for the nurse's reputation. Invasion of privacy is the release of a patient's medical information to an unauthorized person such as a member of the press, the patient's employer, or the patient's family. Assault is any action that places a person in reasonable fear of harmful, imminent, or unwelcome contact. No actual contact is required for an assault to occur. Battery is any intentional touching without consent.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze legal aspects of nurse-patient, nurse-health care provider, nurse-nurse, and nurse-employer relationships.",
          "top": "Evaluation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A patient has approximately 6 months to live and asks about a do not resuscitate (DNR) order. Which statements by the nurse give the patient correct information? (Select all that apply.)",
          "options": [
            "“You will be resuscitated unless there is a DNR order in the chart.”",
            "“If you want certain procedures or actions taken or not taken, and you might not be able to tell anyone at the time, you need to complete documents ahead of time that give your health care provider this information.”",
            "“You will be resuscitated at any time to allow you the longest length of survival.”",
            "“If you decide you want a DNR order, you will need to talk to your health care provider.”",
            "“If you travel to another state, your living will should cover your wishes.”"
          ],
          "answer": [
            "“You will be resuscitated unless there is a DNR order in the chart.”",
            "“If you want certain procedures or actions taken or not taken, and you might not be able to tell anyone at the time, you need to complete documents ahead of time that give your health care provider this information.”",
            "“If you decide you want a DNR order, you will need to talk to your health care provider.”"
          ],
          "explanation": "Health care providers perform CPR on an appropriate patient unless a do not resuscitate (DNR) order has been placed in the patient's chart. The statutes assume that all patients will be resuscitated unless a written DNR order is found in the chart. Legally competent adult patients can consent to a DNR order verbally or in writing after receiving appropriate information from the health care provider. A health care proxy or durable power of attorney for health care (DPAHC) is a legal document that designates a person or persons of one's choosing to make health care decisions when the patient is no longer able to make decisions on his or her own behalf. This agent makes health care treatment decisions based on the patient's wishes, like a DNR. Resuscitation is performed anytime (not just for the longest length of survival) unless a DNR is written in the chart. Differences among the states have been noted regarding advance directives, so the patient should check state laws to see if a state will honor an advance directive that was originated in another state.",
          "dif": "Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Describe the nurse's role regarding a “do not resuscitate” (DNR) order.",
          "top": "Teaching/Learning",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A nurse is teaching the staff about professional negligence or malpractice. Which criteria to establish negligence will the nurse include in the teaching session? (Select all that apply.)",
          "options": [
            "Injury did not occur.",
            "That duty was breached.",
            "Nurse carried out the duty.",
            "Duty of care was owed to the patient.",
            "Patient understands benefits and risks of a procedure."
          ],
          "answer": [
            "That duty was breached.",
            "Duty of care was owed to the patient."
          ],
          "explanation": "Certain criteria are necessary to establish nursing malpractice: (1) the nurse (defendant) owed a duty of care to the patient (plaintiff), (2) the nurse did not carry out or breached that duty, (3) the patient was injured, and (4) the nurse's failure to carry out the duty caused the injury. If an injury did not occur and the nurse carried out the duty, no malpractice occurred. When a patient understands benefits and risks of the procedure that is informed consent, not malpractice.",
          "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
          "obj": "List the elements needed to establish negligence.",
          "top": "Teaching/Learning",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        },
        {
          "question": "A nurse is discussing nursing actions that can lead to breaches of nursing practice. Match the example to the term it describes.",
          "matching": [
            "Assault",
            "Battery",
            "Abandonment",
            "False imprisonment",
            "Invasion of privacy",
            "Malpractice"
          ],
          "options": [
            "Nurse posts about patient's loud and unruly family members.",
            "Nurse immediately applies restraints to make patient stay in bed.",
            "Nurse leaves bed in high position, causing patient to fall and break hip.",
            "Nurse states that she will wrap a bandage over patient's mouth if he won't be quiet.",
            "Nurse applies abdominal bandage after refusal.",
            "Nurse gets angry at patient and nurse leaves the hospital."
          ],
          "answer": {
            "Assault": "Nurse states that she will wrap a bandage over patient's mouth if he won't be quiet.",
            "Battery": "Nurse applies abdominal bandage after refusal.",
            "Abandonment": "Nurse gets angry at patient and nurse leaves the hospital.",
            "False imprisonment": "Nurse immediately applies restraints to make patient stay in bed.",
            "Invasion of privacy": "Nurse posts about patient's loud and unruly family members.",
            "Malpractice": "Nurse leaves bed in high position, causing patient to fall and break hip."
          },
          "explanation": "A nurse stating that she will wrap a bandage over a patient's mouth if they won't keep quiet is considered Assault.\nA Nurse applying an abdominal bandage after patient refusal is considered Battery.\nA nurse getting angry at a patient and leaving the hospital is considered Abandonment.\nA Nurse immediately applying restraints to make a patient stay in their bad is considered False Imprisonment.\nA Nurse posting about a patient's load and unruly family members is considered an Invasion of privacy.\nA Nurse leaving a patient's bed in high position resulting in patient falling and breaking their hip is considered Malpractice.",
          "dif":"Apply (application)",
          "obj": "Analyze nursing actions most often associated in a breach of nursing practice.",
          "top": "Implementation",
          "msc": "Management of Care"
        }
    ],
    "chapter24": [
      {
        "question": "Which characteristic tends to make a nurse the best communicators with patients?",
        "options": [
          "Effective psychomotor skills",
          "Developed critical thinking skills",
          "An interest in different kinds of people",
          "Ability to maintain perceptual biases"
        ],
        "answer": "Developed critical thinking skills",
        "explanation": "Nurses who develop critical thinking skills make the best communicators. Just liking people does not make an effective communicator because it is important to apply critical thinking standards to ensure sound effective communication. Just learning psychomotor skills does not ensure that the nurse will use those techniques, and communication involves more than psychomotor skills. Critical thinking helps the nurse overcome perceptual biases or human tendencies that interfere with accurately perceiving and interpreting messages from others. Nurses who maintain perceptual biases do not make good communicators.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify ways to apply critical thinking to the communication process.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse believes that the nurse-patient relationship is a partnership and that both are equal participants. Which term should the nurse use to describe this belief?",
        "options": [
          "Critical thinking",
          "Authentic",
          "Mutuality",
          "Attend"
        ],
        "answer": "Mutuality",
        "explanation": "Effective interpersonal communication requires a sense of mutuality, a belief that the nurse-patient relationship is a partnership and that both are equal participants. Critical thinking in nursing, based on established standards of nursing care and ethical standards, promotes effective communication and uses standards such as humility, self-confidence, independent attitude, and fairness. To be authentic (one’s self) and to respond appropriately to the other person are important for interpersonal relationships but do not mean mutuality. Attending is giving all of your attention to the patient.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Incorporate features of a helping relationship when interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse wants to present information about flu immunizations to the older adults in the community. Which type of communication should the nurse use?",
        "options": [
          "Public",
          "Small group",
          "Interpersonal",
          "Intrapersonal"
        ],
        "answer": "Public",
        "explanation": "Public communication is interaction with an audience. Nurses have opportunities to speak with groups of consumers about health-related topics, present scholarly work to colleagues at conferences, or lead classroom discussions with peers or students. When nurses work on committees or participate in patient care conferences, they use a small group communication process. Interpersonal communication is one-on-one interaction between a nurse and another person that often occurs face to face. Intrapersonal communication is a powerful form of communication that you use as a professional nurse. This level of communication is also called self-talk.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Utilize the five levels of communication with patients.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is engaged in therapeutic communication with a patient. Which technique will the nurse use to ensure effective communication?",
        "options": [
          "Interpersonal communication to change negative self-talk to positive self-talk",
          "Small group communication to present information to an audience of children",
          "Electronic communication to communicate with the health care provider",
          "Intrapersonal communication to build strong teams"
        ],
        "answer": "Electronic communication to communicate with the health care provider",
        "explanation": "Electronic communication is the use of technology to create ongoing relationships with patients and their health care team. Secure messaging provides an opportunity for frequent and timely communication with a patient’s physician or nurse via a patient portal. Intrapersonal communication is self-talk. Interpersonal communication is one-on-one interaction between a nurse and another person that often occurs face to face. Public communication is used to present information to an audience. Small group communication is interaction that occurs when a small number of persons meet. When nurses work on committees or participate in patient care conferences, they use a small group communication process.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Utilize the five levels of communication with patients.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is standing beside the patient’s bed and the following exchange occurs. Nurse: How are you doing? Patient: I don’t feel good. Which element will be identified as feedback?",
        "options": [
          "Nurse",
          "Patient",
          "How are you doing?",
          "I don’t feel good."
        ],
        "answer": "I don’t feel good.",
        "explanation": "“I don’t feel good” is the feedback because the feedback is the message the receiver returns. The sender is the person who encodes and delivers the message, and the receiver is the person who receives and decodes the message. The nurse is the sender. The patient is the receiver. “How are you doing?” is the message.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe features of the circular transactional communication process.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is sitting at the patient’s bedside taking a nursing history. Which zone of personal space is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "Socio-consultative",
          "Personal",
          "Intimate",
          "Public"
        ],
        "answer": "Personal",
        "explanation": "Personal space is 18 inches to 4 feet and involves things such as sitting at a patient’s bedside, taking a patient’s nursing history, or teaching an individual patient. Intimate space is 0 to 18 inches and involves things such as performing a physical assessment, bathing, grooming, dressing, feeding, and toileting a patient. The socio-consultative zone is 9 to 12 feet and involves things such as giving directions to visitors in the hallway and giving verbal report to a group of nurses. The public zone is 12 feet and greater and involves things such as speaking at a community forum, testifying at a legislative hearing, or lecturing.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify a nurse’s communication approaches within the four phases of a nurse-patient helping relationship.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A smiling patient angrily states, “I will not cough and deep breathe.” How will the nurse interpret this finding?",
        "options": [
          "The patient’s denotative meaning is wrong.",
          "The patient’s personal space was violated.",
          "The patient’s affect is inappropriate.",
          "The patient’s vocabulary is poor."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient’s affect is inappropriate.",
        "explanation": "An inappropriate affect is a facial expression that does not match the content of a verbal message (e.g., smiling when describing a sad situation). The patient is smiling but is angry, which indicates an inappropriate affect. The patient’s personal space was not violated. The patient’s vocabulary is not poor. Individuals who use a common language share denotative meaning: baseball has the same meaning for everyone who speaks English, but code denotes cardiac arrest primarily to health care providers. The patient’s denotative meaning is correct for cough and deep breathe.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Demonstrate qualities, behaviors, and communication techniques of professional communication while interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse asks a patient where their pain is located, and the patient responds by pointing to the area of pain. Which form of communication did the patient use?",
        "options": [
          "Verbal",
          "Nonverbal",
          "Intonation",
          "Vocabulary"
        ],
        "answer": "Nonverbal",
        "explanation": "The patient gestured (pointed), which is a type of nonverbal communication. Gestures emphasize, punctuate, and clarify the spoken word. Pointing to an area of pain is sometimes more accurate than describing its location. Verbal is the spoken word or message. Intonation or tone of voice dramatically affects the meaning of a message. Vocabulary consists of words used for verbal communication.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Demonstrate qualities, behaviors, and communication techniques of professional communication while interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has been admitted to the hospital numerous times. The nurse asks the patient to share a personal story about the care they received. Which interaction is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "Nonjudgmental",
          "Socializing",
          "Narrative",
          "SBAR"
        ],
        "answer": "Narrative",
        "explanation": "In a therapeutic relationship, nurses often encourage patients to share personal stories. Sharing stories is called narrative interaction. Socializing is an important initial component of interpersonal communication. It helps people get to know one another and relax. It is easy, superficial, and not deeply personal. Nonjudgmental acceptance of the patient is an important characteristic of the relationship. Acceptance conveys a willingness to hear a message or acknowledge feelings; it is not a technique that involves personal stories. SBAR is a popular communication tool that helps standardize communication among health care providers. SBAR stands for Situation, Background, Assessment, and Recommendation.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Incorporate features of a helping relationship when interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Before meeting the patient, a nurse talks to other caregivers about the patient. Which phase of the helping relationship is the nurse in with this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Preinteraction",
          "Orientation",
          "Working",
          "Termination"
        ],
        "answer": "Preinteraction",
        "explanation": "The time before the nurse meets the patient is called the preinteraction phase. This phase can involve things such as reviewing available data, including the medical and nursing history, talking to other caregivers who have information about the patient, or anticipating health concerns or issues that can arise. The orientation phase occurs when the nurse and the patient meet and get to know one another. This phase can involve things such as setting the tone for the relationship by adopting a warm, empathetic, caring manner. The working phase occurs when the nurse and the patient work together to solve problems and accomplish goals. The termination phase occurs during the ending of the relationship. This phase can involve things such as reminding the patient that termination is near.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify a nurse’s communication approaches within the four phases of a nurse-patient helping relationship.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "During the initial home visit, a home health nurse lets the patient know that the visits are expected to end in about a month. Which phase of the helping relationship is the nurse in with this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Preinteraction",
          "Orientation",
          "Working",
          "Termination"
        ],
        "answer": "Orientation",
        "explanation": "Letting the patient know when to expect the relationship to be terminated occurs in the orientation phase. Preinteraction occurs before the nurse meets the patient. Working occurs when the nurse and the patient work together to solve problems and accomplish goals. Termination occurs during the ending of the relationship.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify a nurse’s communication approaches within the four phases of a nurse-patient helping relationship.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse and a patient work on strategies to reduce weight. Which phase of the helping relationship is the nurse in with this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Preinteraction",
          "Orientation",
          "Working",
          "Termination"
        ],
        "answer": "Working",
        "explanation": "The working phase occurs when the nurse and the patient work together to solve problems and accomplish goals. Preinteraction occurs before the nurse meets the patient. Orientation occurs when the nurse and the patient meet and get to know each other. Termination occurs during the ending of the relationship.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify a nurse’s communication approaches within the four phases of a nurse-patient helping relationship.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse uses SBAR when providing a hands-off report to the oncoming shift. What is the rationale for the nurse’s action?",
        "options": [
          "To promote autonomy",
          "To use common courtesy",
          "To establish trustworthiness",
          "To standardize communication"
        ],
        "answer": "To standardize communication",
        "explanation": "SBAR is a popular communication tool that helps standardize communication among health care providers. Common courtesy is part of professional communication but is not the purpose of SBAR. Being trustworthy means helping others without hesitation. Autonomy is being self-directed and independent in accomplishing goals and advocating for others.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify desired outcomes of nurse-health care team member relationships.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient was admitted 2 days ago with a diagnosis of pneumonia and a history of angina. The patient is now having chest pain with a pulse rate of 108. Which piece of data will the nurse use for “B” when using SBAR?",
        "options": [
          "Having chest pain",
          "Pulse rate of 108",
          "History of angina",
          "Oxygen is needed"
        ],
        "answer": "History of angina",
        "explanation": "The B in SBAR stands for background information. The background information in this situation is the history of angina. Having chest pain is the Situation (S). Pulse rate of 108 is the Assessment (A). Oxygen is needed is the Recommendation (R).",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify desired outcomes of nurse-health care team member relationships.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient just received a diagnosis of cancer. Which statement by the nurse demonstrates empathy?",
        "options": [
          "“Tomorrow will be better.”",
          "“This must be hard news to hear.”",
          "“What’s your biggest fear about this diagnosis?”",
          "“I believe you can overcome this because I’ve seen how strong you are.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“This must be hard news to hear.”",
        "explanation": "“This must be hard” is an example of empathy. Empathy is the ability to understand and accept another person’s reality, accurately perceive feelings, and communicate this understanding to the other. An example of false reassurance is “Tomorrow will be better.” “I believe you can overcome this” is an example of sharing hope. “What is your biggest fear?” is an open-ended question that allows patients to take the conversational lead and introduces pertinent information about a topic.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify opportunities to improve communication with patients while giving care.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is taking a history on a patient who cannot speak English. Which action will the nurse take to provide effective care?",
        "options": [
          "Obtain an interpreter.",
          "Refer to a speech therapist.",
          "Let a close family member talk.",
          "Find a mental health nurse specialist."
        ],
        "answer": "Obtain an interpreter.",
        "explanation": "Interpreters are often necessary for patients who speak a foreign language. Using a family member can lead to legal issues, speech therapists help patients with aphasia, and mental health nurse specialists help angry or highly anxious patients to communicate more effectively.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Implement nursing care measures for patients with special communication needs.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using SURETY to facilitate active listening. What is the focus of the letter R?",
        "options": [
          "Projection of a sense of relaxation",
          "Demonstrating respect for the patient",
          "Implementing reminisce to support memory",
          "Continuously provide reassurance to the patient"
        ],
        "answer": "Projection of a sense of relaxation",
        "explanation": "In SURETY, the R stands for relax. It is important to communicate a sense of being relaxed and comfortable with the patient. Active listening enhances trust because the nurse communicates acceptance and respect for the patient, but it is not the R in SURETY. Reminisce is a therapeutic communication technique, especially when used with the elderly. Reassuring can be therapeutic if the nurse reassures patients that there are many kinds of hope and that meaning and personal growth can come from illness experiences. However, false reassurance can block communication.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Demonstrate qualities, behaviors, and communication techniques of professional communication while interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "An older-adult patient is wearing a hearing aid. Which technique should the nurse use to facilitate communication?",
        "options": [
          "Chew gum.",
          "Turn off the television.",
          "Speak clearly and loudly.",
          "Use at least 14-point print."
        ],
        "answer": "Turn off the television.",
        "explanation": "Turning off the television will facilitate communication. Patients who are hearing impaired benefit when the following techniques are used: check for hearing aids and glasses, reduce environmental noise, get the patient’s attention before speaking, do not chew gum, and speak at normal volume—do not shout. Using at least 14-point print is for sight/visually impaired, not hearing impaired.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Engage in effective communication techniques for older patients.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "When making rounds, the nurse finds a patient who is not able to sleep; they state, “I’m concerned about my surgery in the morning. Which therapeutic response is most appropriate?",
        "options": [
          "“You will be okay. Your surgeon will talk to you in the morning.”",
          "“Why can’t you sleep? You have the best surgeon in the hospital.”",
          "“Don’t worry. The surgeon ordered a sleeping pill to help you sleep.”",
          "“It must be difficult not to know what the surgeon will find. What can I do to help?”"
        ],
        "answer": "“It must be difficult not to know what the surgeon will find. What can I do to help?”",
        "explanation": "“It must be difficult not to know what the surgeon will find. What can I do to help?” is using therapeutic communication techniques of empathy and asking relevant questions. False reassurances (“You will be okay” and “Don’t worry”) tend to block communication. Patients frequently interpret “why” questions as accusations or think the nurse knows the reason and is simply testing them.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Demonstrate qualities, behaviors, and communication techniques of professional communication while interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which situation will cause the nurse to intervene and follow up on the nursing assistive personnel’s (NAP) behavior?",
        "options": [
          "The nursing assistive personnel is calling the older-adult patient “honey.”",
          "The nursing assistive personnel is facing the older-adult patient when talking.",
          "The nursing assistive personnel cleans the older-adult patient’s glasses gently.",
          "The nursing assistive personnel allows time for the older-adult patient to respond."
        ],
        "answer": "The nursing assistive personnel is calling the older-adult patient “honey.”",
        "explanation": "The nurse needs to intervene to correct the use of “honey.” Avoid terms of endearment such as “honey,” “dear,” “grandma,” or “sweetheart.” Communicate with older adults on an adult level, and avoid patronizing or speaking in a condescending manner. Facing an older-adult patient, making sure the older adult has clean glasses, and allowing time to respond facilitate communication with older-adult patients and should be encouraged, not stopped.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Engage in effective communication techniques for older patients.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A confused older-adult patient is wearing thick glasses and a hearing aid. Which intervention is the priority to facilitate communication?",
        "options": [
          "Focus on tasks to be completed.",
          "Allow time for the patient to respond.",
          "Limit conversations with the patient.",
          "Use gestures and other nonverbal cues."
        ],
        "answer": "Allow time for the patient to respond.",
        "explanation": "Allowing time for patients to respond will facilitate communication, especially for a confused, older patient. Focusing on tasks to be completed and limiting conversations do not facilitate communication; in fact, they block communication. Using gestures and other nonverbal cues is not effective for visually impaired (thick glasses) patients or for patients who are confused.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Engage in effective communication techniques for older patients.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The staff is having difficulty getting an older-adult patient to communicate. Which technique should the nurse suggest the staff use?",
        "options": [
          "Try changing topics often.",
          "Allow the patient to reminisce.",
          "Ask the patient for explanations.",
          "Involve only the patient in conversations."
        ],
        "answer": "Allow the patient to reminisce.",
        "explanation": "Encouraging older adults to share life stories and reminisce about the past has a therapeutic effect and increases their sense of well-being. Avoid sudden shifts from subject to subject. It is helpful to include the patient’s family and friends and to become familiar with the patient’s favorite topics for conversation. Asking for explanations is a nontherapeutic technique.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Engage in effective communication techniques for older patients.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is implementing nursing care measures for patients’ special communication needs. Which patient will need the most nursing care measures?",
        "options": [
          "The patient who is oriented, pain free, and blind",
          "The patient who is alert, hungry, and has strong self-esteem",
          "The patient who is cooperative, depressed, and hard of hearing",
          "The patient who is dyspneic, anxious, and has a tracheostomy"
        ],
        "answer": "The patient who is dyspneic, anxious, and has a tracheostomy",
        "explanation": "Facial trauma, laryngeal cancer, or endotracheal intubation often prevents movement of air past vocal cords or mobility of the tongue, resulting in inability to articulate words. An extremely breathless person needs to use oxygen to breathe rather than speak. Persons with high anxiety are sometimes unable to perceive environmental stimuli or hear explanations. People who are alert, have strong self-esteem, and are cooperative and pain free do not cause communication concerns. Although hunger, blindness, and difficulty hearing can cause communication concerns, dyspnea, tracheostomy, and anxiety all contribute to communication concerns.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Implement nursing care measures for patients with special communication needs.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is aphasic. The nurse notices that an aphasic patient demonstrates with intermittent hand tremors. Which nursing action is most appropriate to facilitate communication?",
        "options": [
          "Use a picture board.",
          "Use pen and paper.",
          "Use an interpreter.",
          "Use a hearing aid."
        ],
        "answer": "Use a picture board.",
        "explanation": "Using a pen and paper can be frustrating for a nonverbal (aphasic) patient whose handwriting is shaky; the nurse can revise the care plan to include use of a picture board instead. An interpreter is used for a patient who speaks a foreign language. A hearing aid is used for the hard of hearing, not for an aphasic patient.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Offer alternative communication devices when appropriate to promote communication with patients who have impaired communication.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which behavior indicates the nurse is using a process recording correctly to enhance communication with patients?",
        "options": [
          "Shows sympathy appropriately.",
          "Uses automatic responses fluently.",
          "Demonstrates passive remarks accurately.",
          "Self-examines personal communication habits."
        ],
        "answer": "Self-examines personal communication habits.",
        "explanation": "Analysis of a process recording enables a nurse to evaluate the following: examine whether nursing responses blocked or facilitated the patient’s efforts to communicate. Sympathy is concern, sorrow, or pity felt for the patient and is nontherapeutic. Clichés and stereotyped remarks are automatic responses that communicate the nurse is not taking concerns seriously or responding thoughtfully. Passive responses serve to avoid conflict or to sidestep issues.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify opportunities to improve communication with patients while giving care.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient says, “You are the worst nurse I have ever had.” Which response by the nurse is most assertive?",
        "options": [
          "“I think you’ve had a hard day.”",
          "“I feel uncomfortable hearing that statement.”",
          "“I don’t think you should say things like that. It is not right.”",
          "“I have been checking on you regularly. How can you say that?”"
        ],
        "answer": "“I feel uncomfortable hearing that statement.”",
        "explanation": "Assertive responses contain “I” messages such as “I want,” “I need,” “I think,” or “I feel.” While all of these start with “I,” the only one that is the most assertive is “I feel uncomfortable hearing that statement.” An assertive nurse communicates self-assurance; communicates feelings; takes responsibility for choices; and is respectful of others’ feelings, ideas, and choices. “I think you’ve had a hard day” is not addressing the problem. Arguing (“How can you say that?”) is not assertive or therapeutic. Showing disapproval (using words like right) is not assertive or therapeutic.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Demonstrate qualities, behaviors, and communication techniques of professional communication while interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which behaviors indicate the nurse is using critical thinking standards when communicating with patients? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Instills faith.",
          "Uses humility.",
          "Portrays self-confidence.",
          "Exhibits supportiveness.",
          "Demonstrates independent attitude."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Uses humility.",
          "Portrays self-confidence.",
          "Demonstrates independent attitude."
        ],
        "explanation": "A self-confident attitude is important because the nurse who conveys confidence and comfort while communicating more readily establishes an interpersonal helping-trusting relationship. In addition, an independent attitude encourages the nurse to communicate with colleagues and share ideas about nursing interventions. An attitude of humility is necessary to recognize and communicate the need for more information before making a decision. Faith and supportiveness are attributes of caring, not critical thinking standards.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify ways to apply critical thinking to the communication process.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is implementing nursing care measures for patients with challenging communication issues. Which types of patients will need these nursing care measures? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "A child who is developmentally delayed.",
          "An older-adult patient who is demanding.",
          "A female patient who is outgoing and flirty.",
          "A male patient who is cooperative with treatments.",
          "An older-adult patient who can clearly see small print.",
          "A teenager frightened by the prospect of impending surgery."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "A child who is developmentally delayed.",
          "An older-adult patient who is demanding.",
          "A female patient who is outgoing and flirty.",
          "A teenager frightened by the prospect of impending surgery."
        ],
        "explanation": "Challenging communication situations include patients who are flirtatious, demanding, frightened, or developmentally delayed. A child who has received little environmental stimulation possibly is behind in language development, thus making communication more challenging. Patients who are cooperative and have good eyesight (see small print) do not cause challenging communication situations.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Implement nursing care measures for patients with special communication needs.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using AIDET to communicate with patients and families. Match the letters of the acronym to the behavior a nurse will use.",
        "matching": [
          "A",
          "I",
          "D",
          "E",
          "T"
        ],
        "options": [
          "Nurse describes procedures and tests.",
          "Nurse lets the patient know how long the procedure will last.",
          "Nurse recognizes the person with a positive attitude.",
          "Nurse thanks the patient.",
          "Nurse tells the patient “I am an RN and will be managing your care.”"
        ],
        "answer": {
          "A": "Nurse recognizes the person with a positive attitude.",
          "I": "Nurse tells the patient “I am an RN and will be managing your care.”",
          "D": "Nurse lets the patient know how long the procedure will last.",
          "E": "Nurse describes procedures and tests.",
          "T": "Nurse thanks the patient."
        },
        "explanation": "In utilizing the AIDET communication framework, nurses employ specific behaviors corresponding to each letter of the acronym to enhance interactions with patients and families. Beginning with A, nurses acknowledge the person with a positive attitude, greeting them warmly and establishing rapport. Introducing oneself, as indicated by I, helps clarify the nurse's role in the patient's care, fostering trust and confidence. Providing information about the duration of procedures or tests, denoted by D, empowers patients by managing their expectations and promoting understanding. E stands for explaining procedures and tests in clear language, enabling patients to make informed decisions about their care. Finally, expressing gratitude to the patient, represented by T, cultivates a positive and respectful environment. Implementing AIDET facilitates professional communication, enhancing the patient experience and contributing to effective care management.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Demonstrate qualities, behaviors, and communication techniques of professional communication while interacting with patients.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      }
    ],
    "chapter25": [
        {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient's family member about permanent tube feedings at home. Which purpose of patient education is the nurse meeting?",
            "options": [
              "Health promotion",
              "Illness prevention",
              "Restoration of health",
              "Coping with impaired functions"
            ],
            "answer": "Coping with impaired functions",
            "explanation": "Teach family members to help the patient with health care management (e.g., giving medications through gastric tubes and doing passive range-of-motion exercises) when coping with impaired functions. Not all patients fully recover from illness or injury. Many have to learn to cope with permanent health alterations. Health promotion involves healthy people staying healthy, while illness prevention is prevention of diseases. Restoration of health occurs if the teaching is about a temporary tube feeding, not a permanent tube feeding.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension) ",
            "obj": "Identify the purposes of patient education.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning ",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a group of healthy adults about the benefits of flu immunizations. Which type of patient education is the nurse providing?",
            "options": [
              "Health analogies",
              "Restoration of health",
              "Coping with impaired functions",
              "Promotion of health and illness prevention"
            ],
            "answer": "Promotion of health and illness prevention",
            "explanation": "As a nurse, you are a visible, competent resource for patients who want to improve their physical and psychological well-being. In the school, home, clinic, or workplace, you promote health and prevent illness by providing information and skills that enable patients to assume healthier behaviors. Injured and ill patients need information and skills to help them regain or maintain their level of health; this is referred to as restoration of health. Not all patients fully recover from illness or injury. Many have to learn to cope with permanent health alterations; this is known as coping with impaired functions. Analogies supplement verbal instruction with familiar images that make complex information more real and understandable. For example, when explaining arterial blood pressure, use an analogy of the flow of water through a hose.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify the purposes of patient education.",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse's goal is to provide teaching for restoration of health. Which situation indicates the nurse is meeting this goal?",
            "options": [
              "Teaching a family member to provide passive range of motion for a stroke patient",
              "Teaching a woman who recently had a hysterectomy about possible adoption",
              "Teaching expectant parents about changes in childbearing women",
              "Teaching a teenager with a broken leg how to use crutches"
            ],
            "answer": "Teaching a teenager with a broken leg how to use crutches",
            "explanation": "Injured or ill patients need information and skills to help them regain or maintain their levels of health. An example includes teaching a teenager with a broken leg how to use crutches. Not all patients fully recover from illness or injury. Many have to learn to cope with permanent health alterations. New knowledge and skills are often necessary for patients and/or family members to continue activities of daily living. Teaching family members to help the patient with health care management (e.g., giving medications through gastric tubes, doing passive range-of-motion exercises) is an example of coping with long-term impaired functions. For a woman with a hysterectomy, teaching about adoption is not restoration of health; restoration of health in this situation would involve activity restrictions and incision care if needed. In childbearing classes, you teach expectant parents about physical and psychological changes in the woman and about fetal development; this is part of health maintenance.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify the purposes of patient education.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse attends a seminar on teaching/learning. Which statement indicates the nurse has a good understanding of teaching/learning?",
            "options": [
              "“Teaching and learning can be separated.”",
              "“Learning is an interactive process that promotes teaching.”",
              "“Teaching is most effective when it responds to the learner's needs.”",
              "“Learning consists of a conscious, deliberate set of actions designed to help the"
            ],
            "answer": "“Teaching is most effective when it responds to the learner's needs.”",
            "explanation": "Teaching is most effective when it responds to the learner's needs. It is impossible to separate teaching from learning. Teaching is an interactive process that promotes learning. Teaching consists of a conscious, deliberate set of actions that help individuals gain new knowledge, change attitudes, adopt new behaviors, or perform new skills.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the similarities and differences between teaching and learning.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is determining if teaching is effective. Which finding best indicates learning has occurred?",
            "options": [
              "A nurse presents information about diabetes.",
              "A patient demonstrates how to inject insulin.",
              "A family member listens to a lecture on diabetes.",
              "A primary care provider hands a diabetes pamphlet to the patient."
            ],
            "answer": "A patient demonstrates how to inject insulin.",
            "explanation": "Learning is the purposeful acquisition of new knowledge, attitudes, behaviors, and skills: patient demonstrates how to inject insulin. A new mother exhibits learning when she demonstrates how to bathe her newborn. A nurse presenting information and a primary care provider handing a pamphlet to a patient are examples of teaching. A family member listening to a lecture does not indicate that learning occurred; a change in knowledge, attitudes, behaviors, and/or skills must be evident. ",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the similarities and differences between teaching and learning.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning ",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about the Speak Up Initiatives. Which information should the nurse include in the teaching session?",
            "options": [
              "If you still do not understand, ask again.",
              "Ask a nurse to be your advocate or supporter.",
              "The nurse is the center of the health care team.",
              "Inappropriate medical tests are the most common mistakes."
            ],
            "answer": "If you still do not understand, ask again.",
            "explanation": "If you still do not understand, ask again is part of the S portion of the Speak Up Initiatives. Speak up if you have questions or concerns. You (the patient) are the center of the health care team, not the nurse. Ask a trusted family member or friend to be your advocate (advisor or supporter), not a nurse. Medication errors are the most common health care mistakes, not inappropriate medical tests. ",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension) ",
            "obj": "Identify the role of the nurse in patient education.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning ",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse teaches a patient with heart failure healthy food choices. The patient states that eating yogurt is better than eating cake. Which element represents feedback?",
            "options": [
              "The nurse",
              "The patient",
              "The nurse teaching about healthy food choices",
              "The patient stating that eating yogurt is better than eating cake"
            ],
            "answer": "The patient stating that eating yogurt is better than eating cake",
            "explanation": "Feedback needs to demonstrate the success of the learner in achieving objectives (i.e., the learner verbalizes information or provides a return demonstration of skills learned). The nurse is the sender. The patient (learner) is the receiver. The teaching is the message.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe appropriate communication principles when providing patient education.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "While preparing a teaching plan, the nurse describes what the learner will be able to accomplish after the teaching session about healthy eating. Which action is the nurse completing?",
            "options": [
              "Developing learning objectives",
              "Providing positive reinforcement",
              "Presenting facts and knowledge",
              "Implementing interpersonal communication"
            ],
            "answer": "Developing learning objectives",
            "explanation": "Learning objectives describe what the learner will exhibit as a result of successful instruction. Positive reinforcement follows feedback and reinforces good behavior and promotes continued compliance. Interpersonal communication is necessary for the teaching/learning process but describing what the learner will be able to do after successful instruction constitutes learning objectives. Facts and knowledge will be presented in the teaching session.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe appropriate communication principles when providing patient education.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "After a teaching session with a nurse, a patient learns that a normal adult heartbeat is 60 to 100 beats/min. In which domain did learning take place?",
            "options": [
              "Kinesthetic",
              "Cognitive",
              "Affective",
              "Psychomotor"
            ],
            "answer": "Cognitive",
            "explanation": "The patient acquired knowledge, which is cognitive. Cognitive learning includes all intellectual skills and requires thinking. In the hierarchy of cognitive behaviors, the simplest behavior is acquiring knowledge. Kinesthetic is a type of learner who learns best with a hands-on approach. Affective learning deals with expression of feelings and development of attitudes, beliefs, or values.Psychomotor learning involves acquiring skills that require integration of mental and physical activities, such as the ability to walk or use an eating utensil.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the domains of learning.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is trying to help a patient begin to accept the chronic nature of diabetes. Which teaching technique should the nurse use to enhance learning?",
            "options": [
              "Lecture",
              "Role play",
              "Demonstration",
              "Question and answer sessions"
            ],
            "answer": "Role play",
            "explanation": "Affective learning deals with expression of feelings and acceptance of attitudes, beliefs, or values. Role play and discussion(one-on-one and group) are effective teaching methods for the affective domain. Lecture and question and answer sessions are effective teaching methods for the cognitive domain. Demonstration is an effective teaching method for the psychomotor domain.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Describe the domains of learning.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is describing a patient's perceived ability to successfully complete a task. Which term should the nurse use to describe this attribute?",
            "options": [
              "Self-efficacy",
              "Motivation",
              "Attentional set",
              "Active participation"
            ],
            "answer": "Self-efficacy",
            "explanation": "Self-efficacy, a concept included in social learning theory, refers to a person's perceived ability to successfully complete a task.Motivation is a force that acts on or within a person (e.g., an idea, an emotion, a physical need) to cause the person to behave in a particular way. An attentional set is the mental state that allows the learner to focus on and comprehend a learning activity.Learning occurs when the patient is actively involved in the educational session.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify basic learning principles.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A toddler is going to have surgery on the right ear. Which teaching method is most appropriate for this developmental stage?",
            "options": [
              "Encourage independent learning.",
              "Develop a problem-solving scenario.",
              "Wrap a bandage around a stuffed animal's ear.",
              "Use discussion throughout the teaching session."
            ],
            "answer": "Wrap a bandage around a stuffed animal's ear.",
            "explanation": "Use play to teach a procedure or activity (e.g., handling examination equipment, applying a bandage to a doll) to toddlers.Encouraging independent learning is for the young or middle adult. Use of discussion is for older children, adolescents, and adults,not for toddlers. Use problem solving to help adolescents make choices. Problem solving is too advanced for a toddler. ",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss how to integrate education into patient-centered care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning ",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to teach a patient about smoking cessation. Which factors should the nurse assess to determine a patient's ability to learn?",
            "options": [
              "Sociocultural background and motivation",
              "Stage of grieving and overall physical health",
              "Developmental capabilities and physical capabilities",
              "Psychosocial adaptation to illness and active participation"
            ],
            "answer": "Developmental capabilities and physical capabilities",
            "explanation": "Developmental and physical capabilities reflect one's ability to learn. Sociocultural background and motivation are factors determining readiness to learn. Psychosocial adaptation to illness and active participation are factors in readiness to learn.Readiness to learn is related to the stage of grieving. Overall physical health does reflect ability to learn; however, because it is paired here with stage of grieving (which is a readiness to learn factor), this is incorrect.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Differentiate factors that determine readiness to learn from those that determine ability to learn.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about heart failure. Which environment will the nurse use?",
            "options": [
              "A darkened, quiet room",
              "A well-lit, ventilated room",
              "A private room at 85° F temperature",
              "A group room for 10 to 12 patients with heart failure"
            ],
            "answer": "A well-lit, ventilated room",
            "explanation": "The ideal environment for learning is a room that is well lit and has good ventilation, appropriate furniture, and a comfortable temperature. Although a quiet room is appropriate, a darkened room interferes with the patient's ability to watch your actions,especially when demonstrating a skill or using visual aids such as posters or pamphlets. A room that is cold, hot, or stuffy makes the patient too uncomfortable to focus on the information being presented. Learning in a group of six or less is more effective and avoids distracting behaviors.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Establish an environment that promotes learning.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which assessment finding will best indicate that the patient is ready to learn?",
            "options": [
              "The ability to grasp and apply the elastic bandage.",
              "Expresses the motivation to walk with an assistive device.",
              "Demonstrates sufficient coordination to handle a syringe safely.",
              "Has sufficient upper body strength to move from a bed to a wheelchair."
            ],
            "answer": "Expresses the motivation to walk with an assistive device.",
            "explanation": "Motivation underlies a person's desire or willingness to learn. Motivation is a force that acts on or within a person (e.g., an idea,emotion, or a physical need) to cause the person to behave in a particular way. For example, a patient with a below-the-knee amputation is motivated to learn how to walk with assistive devices, indicating a readiness to learn. Do not confuse readiness to learn with ability to learn. All the other answers are examples of ability to learn because this often depends on the patient's level of physical development and overall physical health. To learn psychomotor skills, a patient needs to possess a certain level of strength, coordination, and sensory acuity. For example, it is useless to teach a patient to transfer from a bed to a wheelchair if he or she has insufficient upper body strength. An older patient with poor eyesight or an inability to grasp objects tightly cannot learn to apply an elastic bandage or handle a syringe.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Differentiate factors that determine readiness to learn from those that determine ability to learn.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient with a risk for hypertension how to take a blood pressure. Which action by the nurse is the priority to assist learning?",
            "options": [
              "Assess laboratory results for high cholesterol and other data.",
              "Identify that teaching is the same as the nursing process.",
              "Perform nursing care therapies to address hypertension.",
              "Focus on a patient's learning needs and objectives."
            ],
            "answer": "Focus on a patient's learning needs and objectives.",
            "explanation": "The teaching process focuses on the patient's learning needs, motivation, and ability to learn; writing learning objectives and goals is also included. Nursing and teaching processes are not the same. Assessing laboratory results for high cholesterol and performing nursing care therapies are all components of the nursing process, not the teaching process.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast the nursing and teaching processes.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient diagnosed with both heart failure and kidney failure requires teaching about dialysis. Which nursing assessment is most appropriate for determining this patient's learning needs?",
            "options": [
              "Total health care needs",
              "Health literacy",
              "Sources of patient data",
              "Goals of patient care"
            ],
            "answer": "Health literacy",
            "explanation": "Because health literacy influences how you deliver teaching strategies, it is critical for you to assess a patient's health literacy before providing instruction. The nursing process requires assessment of all sources of data to determine a patient's total healthcare needs. Evaluation of the teaching process involves determining outcomes of the teaching/learning process and the achievement of learning objectives; assessing the goals of patient care is the evaluation component of the nursing process.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast the nursing and teaching processes.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about hypertension. In which order from first to last will the nurse implement the steps of the teaching process? 1. Set mutual goals for knowledge of hypertension. 2. Teach what the patient wants to know about hypertension. 3. Assess what the patient already knows about hypertension. 4. Evaluate the outcomes of patient education for hypertension.",
            "options": [
              "1, 3, 2, 4",
              "2, 3, 1, 4",
              "3, 1, 2, 4",
              "3, 2, 1, 4"
            ],
            "answer": "3, 1, 2, 4",
            "explanation": "Assessment is the first step of any teaching session, then diagnosing, planning (goals), implementation, and evaluation. ",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify the appropriate topics that address a patient's health education needs.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning ",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to teach the patient about cane use after a stroke. Which learning objective/outcome is most appropriate for the nurse to include in the teaching plan?",
            "options": [
              "The patient will walk to the bathroom and back to bed using a cane.",
              "The patient will understand the importance of using a cane.",
              "The patient will know the correct use of a cane.",
              "The patient will learn how to use a cane."
            ],
            "answer": "The patient will walk to the bathroom and back to bed using a cane.",
            "explanation": "Outcomes often describe a behavior that identifies the patient's ability to do something on completion of teaching such as will empty a colostomy bag or will administer an injection. Understand, learn, and know are not behaviors that can be observed or evaluated. ",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Write learning objectives for a teaching plan.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which learning objective/outcome has the highest priority for a patient with life-threatening, severe food allergies that requires epinephrine therapy?",
            "options": [
              "The patient will identify the main ingredients in several foods.",
              "The patient will list the side effects of epinephrine.",
              "The patient will learn about food labels.",
              "The patient will administer epinephrine."
            ],
            "answer": "The patient will administer epinephrine.",
            "explanation": "Once you assist in meeting patient needs related to basic survival (how to give epinephrine), you can discuss other topics, such as nutritional needs and side effects of medications. For example, a patient recently diagnosed with coronary artery disease has deficient knowledge related to the illness and its implications. The patient benefits most by first learning about the correct way to take nitroglycerin and how long to wait before calling for help when chest pain occurs. Thus, in this situation, the patient benefits most by first learning about the correct way to take epinephrine. “The patient will learn about food labels” is not objective and measurable and is not correctly written.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Write learning objectives for a teaching plan.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "After a teaching session on taking blood pressures, the nurse tells the patient, “You took that blood pressure like an experienced nurse.” Which type of reinforcement did the nurse use?",
            "options": [
              "Social acknowledgment",
              "Pleasurable activity",
              "Tangible reward",
              "Entrusting"
            ],
            "answer": "Social acknowledgment",
            "explanation": "Reinforcers come in the form of social acknowledgments (e.g., nods, smiles, words of encouragement), pleasurable activities (e.g.,walks or play time), and tangible rewards (e.g., toys or food). The entrusting approach is a teaching approach that provides a patient the opportunity to manage self-care. It is not a type of reinforcement.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify basic learning principles.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient diagnosed with heart failure is learning to reduce salt in the diet. When will be the best time for the nurse to address this topic?",
            "options": [
              "At bedtime, while the patient is relaxed.",
              "At bath time, when the nurse is cleaning the patient.",
              "At lunchtime, while the nurse is preparing the food tray.",
              "At medication time, when the nurse is administering patient medication."
            ],
            "answer": "At lunchtime, while the nurse is preparing the food tray.",
            "explanation": "In this situation, because the teaching is about food, coordinating it with routine nursing care that involves food can be effective.Many nurses find that they are able to teach more effectively while delivering nursing care. For example, while hanging blood, you explain to the patient why the blood is necessary and the symptoms of a transfusion reaction that need to be reported immediately.At bedtime would be a good time to discuss routines that enhance sleep. At bath time would be a good time to describe skin care and how to prevent pressure ulcers. At medication time would be a good time to explain the purposes and side effects of the medication.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Include patient teaching while performing routine nursing care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient identified as having low health literacy about chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). Which technique is most appropriate for the nurse to use?",
            "options": [
              "Use complex analogies to describe COPD.",
              "Ask for feedback to assess understanding of COPD at the end of the session.",
              "Offer pamphlets about COPD written at the eighth-grade level with large type.",
              "Include the most important information on COPD at the beginning of the session."
            ],
            "answer": "Include the most important information on COPD at the beginning of the session.",
            "explanation": "Include the most important information at the beginning of the session for patients with literacy or learning disabilities. Also, use visual cues and simple, not complex, analogies when appropriate. Another technique is to frequently ask patients for feedback to determine whether they comprehend the information. Additionally, provide teaching materials that reflect the reading level of the patient, with attention given to short words and sentences, large type, and simple format (generally, information written on a fifth-grade reading level is recommended for adult learners).",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Include patient teaching while performing routine nursing care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a culturally diverse patient with a learning disability about nutritional needs. What must the nurse do first before starting the teaching session?",
            "options": [
              "Obtain pictures of food.",
              "Get an interpreter.",
              "Establish a rapport.",
              "Refer to a dietitian."
            ],
            "answer": "Establish a rapport.",
            "explanation": "Establishing trust is important for all patients, especially culturally diverse and learning-disabled patients, before starting teaching sessions. Obtaining pictures of food, getting an interpreter, and referring to a dietitian all occur after rapport/trust is established.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss how to integrate education into patient-centered care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching an older-adult patient about strokes. Which teaching technique is most appropriate for the nurse to use?",
            "options": [
              "Speak in a high tone of voice to describe strokes.",
              "Use a pamphlet about strokes with large font in blues and greens.",
              "Provide specific information about strokes in short, small amounts.",
              "Begin the teaching session facing the teaching white board with stroke information."
            ],
            "answer": "Provide specific information about strokes in short, small amounts.",
            "explanation": "With older adults, keep the teaching session short with small amounts of information. Also, if using written material, assess the patient's ability to read and use information that is printed in large type and in a color that contrasts highly with the background(e.g., black 14-point print on matte white paper). Avoid blues and greens because they are more difficult to see. Speak in a low tone of voice (lower tones are easier to hear than higher tones). Directly face the older-adult learner when speaking.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify the appropriate topics that address a patient's health education needs.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient who is going to surgery has been taught how to cough and deep breathe. Which evaluation method will the nurse use?",
            "options": [
              "Return demonstration",
              "Computer instruction",
              "Verbalization of steps",
              "Cloze test"
            ],
            "answer": "Return demonstration",
            "explanation": "To demonstrate mastery of the skill, have the patient perform a return demonstration under the same conditions that will be experienced at home or in the place where the skill is to be performed. Computer instruction is use of a programmed instruction format in which computers store response patterns for learners and select further lessons on the basis of these patterns (program scan be individualized). Computer instruction is a teaching tool, rather than an evaluation tool. Verbalization of steps can be an evaluation tool, but it is not as effective as a return demonstration when evaluating a psychomotor skill. The Cloze test, a test of reading comprehension, asks patients to fill in the blanks that are in a written paragraph.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Use appropriate methods to evaluate learning.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient has been taught how to change a colostomy bag but is having difficulty manipulating the equipment and has many questions. To which resource should the nurse institute a referral to?",
            "options": [
              "A mental health specialist",
              "A wound care specialist",
              "An ostomy specialist",
              "A dietitian"
            ],
            "answer": "An ostomy specialist",
            "explanation": "Resources that specialize in a particular health need (e.g., wound care or ostomy specialists) are integral to successful patient education. A mental health specialist is helpful for emotional issues rather than for physical problems. A dietitian is a resource for nutritional needs. A wound care specialist provides complex wound care.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Use appropriate methods to evaluate learning.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about healthy eating habits. Which learning objective/outcome for the affective domain will the nurse add to the teaching plan?",
            "options": [
              "The patient will state three facts about healthy eating.",
              "The patient will identify two foods for a healthy snack.",
              "The patient will verbalize the value of eating healthy.",
              "The patient will cook a meal with low-fat oil."
            ],
            "answer": "The patient will verbalize the value of eating healthy.",
            "explanation": "Affective learning deals with expression of feelings and acceptance of attitudes, beliefs, or values. Having the patient value healthy eating habits falls within the affective domain. Stating three facts or identifying two foods for a healthy snack falls within the cognitive domain. Cooking falls within the psychomotor domain.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Write learning objectives for a teaching plan.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing the ability to learn of a patient who has recently experienced a stroke. Which question/statement will best assess the patient's ability to learn?",
            "options": [
              "“What do you want to know about strokes?”",
              "“Please read this handout and tell me what it means.”",
              "“Do you feel strong enough to perform the tasks I will teach you?”",
              "“On a scale from 1 to 10, tell me where you rank your desire to learn.”"
            ],
            "answer": "“Please read this handout and tell me what it means.”",
            "explanation": "A patient's reading level affects ability to learn. One way to assess a patient's reading level and level of understanding is to ask the patient to read instructions from an educational handout and then explain their meaning. Reading level is often difficult to assess because patients who are functionally illiterate are often able to conceal it by using excuses such as not having the time or not being able to see. Asking patients what they want to know identifies previous learning and learning needs and preferences; it does not assess ability to learn. Motivation (desire to learn) is related to readiness to learn, not ability to learn. Just a skin g a patient if he or she feels strong is not as effective as actually assessing the patient's strength.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Differentiate factors that determine readiness to learn from those that determine ability to learn.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to teach a kinesthetic learner about exercise. Which technique will the nurse use?",
            "options": [
              "Let the patient touch and use the exercise equipment.",
              "Provide the patient with pictures of the exercise equipment.",
              "Let the patient listen to a video about the exercise equipment.",
              "Provide the patient with a case study about the exercise equipment."
            ],
            "answer": "Let the patient touch and use the exercise equipment.",
            "explanation": "Kinesthetic learners process knowledge by moving and participating in hands-on activities. Return demonstrations and role-playing work well with these learners. Patients who are visual-spatial learners enjoy learning through pictures and visual charts to explain concepts. The verbal/linguistic learner demonstrates strength in the language arts and therefore prefers learning by listening or reading information. Patients who learn through logical-mathematical reasoning think in terms of cause and effect and respond best when required to predict logical outcomes. Specific teaching strategies could include open-ended questioning or problem-solving exercises, like a case study.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Establish an environment that promotes learning.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is asked by a co-worker why patient education/teaching is important. Which statements will the nurse share with the co-worker? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Patient education is an essential component of safe, patient-centered care.",
              "Patient education is a standard for professional nursing practice.",
              "Patient teaching falls within the scope of nursing practice.",
              "Patient teaching is documented and part of the chart.",
              "Patient education is not effective with children.",
              "Patient teaching can increase health care costs."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Patient education is an essential component of safe, patient-centered care.",
                "Patient education is a standard for professional nursing practice.",
                "Patient teaching falls within the scope of nursing practice.",
                "Patient teaching is documented and part of the chart."
            ],
            "explanation": "Patient education has long been a standard for professional nursing practice. All state Nurse Practice Acts acknowledge that patient teaching falls within the scope of nursing practice. Patient education is an essential component of providing safe, patient-centered care. It is important to document evidence of successful patient education in patients' medical records. Patient education is effective for children. Different techniques must be used with children. Creating a well-designed, comprehensive teaching plan that fits a patient's unique learning needs reduces health care costs, improves quality of care, and ultimately changes behaviors to improve patient outcomes.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify the role of the nurse in patient education.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to teach patients. Which patient finding will cause the nurse to postpone a teaching session? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "The patient's pain is not controlled.",
              "The patient is reporting being fatigued.",
              "The patient is mildly anxious about their condition.",
              "The patient is asking numerous questions about their health status.",
              "The patient is currently febrile with an oral temperature of 101.2° F.",
              "The patient is in the acceptance phase of dealing with their medical diagnosis."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "The patient's pain is not controlled.",
                "The patient is reporting being fatigued.",
                "The patient is currently febrile with an oral temperature of 101.2° F."
            ],
            "explanation": "Any condition (e.g., pain, fatigue) that depletes a person's energy also impairs the ability to learn, so the session should be postponed until the pain is relieved and the patient is rested. Postpone teaching when an illness becomes aggravated by complications such as a high fever or respiratory difficulty. A mild level of anxiety motivates learning. When patients are ready to learn, they frequently ask questions. When the patient enters the stage of acceptance, the stage compatible with learning, introduce a teaching plan.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss how to integrate education into patient-centered care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          }
    ],
    "chapter26": [
        {
            "question": "A nurse preceptor is working with a student nurse. Which behavior by the student nurse will require the nurse preceptor to intervene?",
            "options": [
              "Reading the patient's plan of care",
              "Reviewing the patient's medical record",
              "Sharing patient information with another student",
              "Documenting medication administered to the patient"
            ],
            "answer": "Sharing patient information with another student",
            "explanation": "When you are a student in a clinical setting, confidentiality and compliance with the Health Insurance Portability andAccountability Act (HIPAA) are part of professional practice. When a student nurse shares patient information with a friend,confidentiality and HIPAA standards have been violated, causing the preceptor to intervene. You can review your patients' medical records only to seek information needed to provide safe and effective patient care. For example, when you are assigned to care for a patient, you need to review the patient's medical record and plan of care. You do not share this information with classmates and you do not access the medical records of other patients on the unit.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify ways to maintain confidentiality of electronic and written records.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse exchanges information with the oncoming nurse about a patient's care. Which action did the nurse complete?",
            "options": [
              "A verbal report",
              "An electronic record entry",
              "A referral",
              "An acuity rating"
            ],
            "answer": "A verbal report",
            "explanation": "Whether the transfer of patient information occurs through verbal reports, electronic or written documents, you need to follow some basic principles. Reports are exchanges of information among caregivers. A patient's electronic medical record or chart is a confidential, permanent legal documentation of information relevant to a patient's health care. Nurses document referrals(arrangements for the services of another care provider). Nurses use acuity ratings to determine the hours of care and number of staff required for a given group of patients every shift or every 24 hours.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the different methods used in record keeping.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is auditing and monitoring patients' health records. Which action is the nurse taking?",
            "options": [
              "Determining the degree to which standards of care are met by reviewing patients' health records",
              "Realizing that care not documented in patients' health records still qualifies as care provided",
              "Basing reimbursement upon the diagnosis-related groups documented in patients' records",
              "Comparing data in patients' records to determine whether a new treatment had better outcomes than the standard treatment"
            ],
            "answer": "Determining the degree to which standards of care are met by reviewing patients' health records",
            "explanation": "The auditing and monitoring of patients' health records involve nurses periodically auditing records to determine the degree to which standards of care are met and identifying areas needing improvement and staff development. The mistakes in documentation that commonly result in malpractice include failing to record nursing actions; this is the aspect of legal documentation. The financial billing or reimbursement purpose involves diagnosis-related groups (DRGs) as the basis for establishing reimbursement for patient care. For research purposes, the researcher compares the patient's recorded findings to determine whether the new method was more effective than the standard protocol. Data analysis contributes to evidence-based nursing practice and quality health care.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Identify purposes of a health care record.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "After providing care, a nurse charts in the patient's record. Which entry will the nurse document?",
            "options": [
              "Appears restless when sitting in the chair.",
              "Drank adequate amounts of water.",
              "Apparently is asleep with eyes closed.",
              "Skin pale and cool."
            ],
            "answer": "Skin pale and cool.",
            "explanation": "A factual record contains descriptive, objective information about what a nurse observes, hears, palpates, and smells. Objective data is obtained through direct observation and measurement (skin pale and cool). For example, “B/P 80/50, patient diaphoretic,heart rate 102 and regular.” Avoid vague terms such as appears, seems, or apparently because these words suggest that you are stating an opinion, do not accurately communicate facts, and do not inform another caregiver of details regarding behaviors exhibited by the patient. Use of exact measurements establishes accuracy. For example, a description such as “Intake, 360 mL of water” is more accurate than “Patient drank an adequate amount of fluid.”",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe five quality guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse has provided care to a patient. Which entry should the nurse document in the patient's record?",
            "options": [
              "Status unchanged, doing well.",
              "Patient seems to be in pain and states, “I feel uncomfortable.”",
              "Left knee incision 1 inch in length without redness, drainage, or edema.",
              "Patient is hard to care for and refuses all treatments and medications. Family is present."
            ],
            "answer": "Left knee incision 1 inch in length without redness, drainage, or edema.",
            "explanation": "Use of exact measurements establishes accuracy. Charting that an abdominal wound is “approximated, 5 cm in length without redness, drainage, or edema,” is more descriptive than “large abdominal incision healing well.” Include objective data to support subjective data, so your charting is as descriptive as possible. Avoid using generalized, empty phrases such as “status unchanged”or “had good day.” It is essential to avoid the use of unnecessary words and irrelevant details or personal opinions. “Patient is hard to care for” is a personal opinion and should be avoided. It is also a critical comment that can be used as evidence for nonprofessional behavior or poor quality of care. Just chart, “refuses all treatments and medications.”",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe five quality guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which action by a novice nurse will cause the preceptor to provide follow up instructions?",
            "options": [
              "Documents descriptively.",
              "Charts consecutively on every other line.",
              "Ends each entry with signature and title.",
              "Uses quotations to note patients' exact words."
            ],
            "answer": "Charts consecutively on every other line.",
            "explanation": "Chart consecutively, line by line (not every other line); every other line is incorrect and must be corrected by the preceptor. If space is left, draw a line horizontally through it, and place your signature and credentials at the end. Every other line should not be left blank. All the other behaviors are correct and need no follow-up. Documenting should be as descriptive as possible. End each entry with signature and title/credentials. When recording subjective data, document a patient's exact words within quotation marks whenever possible.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss legal guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which action can the nurse take legally when charting on a patient's record?",
            "options": [
              "Charts in a legible manner.",
              "States the patient is belligerent.",
              "Writes entry for another nurse.",
              "Uses correction fluid to correct error."
            ],
            "answer": "Charts in a legible manner.",
            "explanation": "Record all entries legibly. Do not write personal opinions (belligerent). Enter only objective and factual observations of patient's behavior; quote all patient comments. Do not erase, apply correction fluid, or scratch out errors made while recording. Chart only for yourself.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss legal guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse wants to find all the pertinent patient information in one record, regardless of the number of times the patient entered the health care system. Which record should the nurse access?",
            "options": [
              "Electronic medical record",
              "Electronic health record",
              "Electronic charting record",
              "Electronic problem record"
            ],
            "answer": "Electronic health record",
            "explanation": "The term electronic health record/EHR is increasingly used to refer to a longitudinal (lifetime) record of all health care encounters for an individual patient by linking all patient data from previous health encounters. An electronic medical record (EMR) is the legal record that describes a single encounter or visit created in hospitals and outpatient health care settings that is the source of data for the EHR. There are no such terms as electronic charting record or electronic problem record that record the lifetime information of a patient.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the different methods used in record keeping.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse has instructed the patient regarding the proper use of crutches. The patient went up and down the stairs using crutches with no difficulties. Which information will the nurse use for the “I” in PIE charting?",
            "options": [
              "Patient went up and down stairs",
              "Demonstrated use of crutches",
              "Used crutches with no difficulties",
              "Deficient knowledge related to never using crutches"
            ],
            "answer": "Demonstrated use of crutches",
            "explanation": "A second progress note method is the PIE format. The narrative note includes P—Nursing diagnosis, I—Intervention, andE—Evaluation. The intervention is “Demonstrated use of crutches.” “Patient went up and down stairs” and “Used crutches with no difficulties” are examples of E. “Deficient knowledge regarding crutches” is P.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the different methods used in record keeping.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse wants to find the daily weights of a hospitalized patient. Which resource will the nurse consult?",
            "options": [
              "Database",
              "Progress notes",
              "Patient care summary",
              "Graphic record and flow sheet"
            ],
            "answer": "Graphic record and flow sheet",
            "explanation": "Within a computerized documentation system, flow sheets and graphic records allow you to quickly and easily enter assessment data about a patient, such as vital signs, admission and or daily weights, and percentage of meals eaten. In the problem-oriented medical record, the database section contains all available assessment information pertaining to the patient (e.g., history and physical examination, nursing admission history and ongoing assessment, physical therapy assessment, laboratory reports, and radiologic test results). Many computerized documentation systems have the ability to generate a patient care summary document that you review and sometimes print for each patient at the beginning and/or end of each shift; it includes information such as basic demographic data, health care provider's name, primary medical diagnosis, and current orders. Health care team members monitor and record the progress made toward resolving a patient's problems in progress notes.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the advantages of standardized documentation forms.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is a member of an interdisciplinary team that uses critical pathways. According to the critical pathway, on day 2 of the hospital stay, the patient should be sitting in the chair. It is day 3, and the patient cannot sit in the chair. What should the nurse do?",
            "options": [
              "Add this data to the problem list.",
              "Focus chart using the DAR format.",
              "Document the variance in the patients record.",
              "Report a positive variance in the next interdisciplinary team meeting."
            ],
            "answer": "Document the variance in the patients record.",
            "explanation": "A variance occurs when the activities on the critical pathway are not completed as predicted or the patient does not meet expected outcomes. An example of a negative variance is when a patient develops pulmonary complications after surgery, requiring oxygen therapy and monitoring with pulse oximetry. A positive variance occurs when a patient progresses more rapidly than expected (e.g.,use of a Foley catheter may be discontinued a day early). When a nurse is using the problem-oriented medical record, after analyzing data, health care team members identify problems and make a single problem list. A third format used for notes within a POMR is focus charting. It involves the use of DAR notes, which include D—Data (both subjective and objective), A—Action or nursing intervention, and R—Response of the patient (i.e., evaluation of effectiveness).",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relationship between documentation and financial reimbursement for health care.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse needs to begin discharge planning for a patient admitted with pneumonia and a congested cough. When is the best time the nurse should start discharge planning for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Upon admission",
              "Right before discharge",
              "After the congestion is treated",
              "When the primary care provider writes the order"
            ],
            "answer": "Upon admission",
            "explanation": "Ideally, discharge planning begins at admission. Right before discharge is too late for discharge planning. After the congestion is treated is also too late for discharge planning. Usually the primary care provider writes the order too close to discharge, and nurses do not need an order to begin the teaching that will be needed for discharge. By identifying discharge needs early, nursing and other health care professionals begin planning for discharge to the appropriate level of care, which sometimes includes support services such as home care and equipment needs.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify elements to include when documenting a patient's discharge plan.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is being discharged home. Which information should the nurse include?",
            "options": [
              "Acuity level",
              "Community resources",
              "Standardized care plan",
              "Signature for verbal order"
            ],
            "answer": "Community resources",
            "explanation": "Discharge documentation includes medications, diet, community resources, follow-up care, and who to contact in case of an emergency or for questions. A patient's acuity level, usually determined by a computer program, is based on the types and numbers of nursing interventions (e.g., intravenous [IV] therapy, wound care, or ambulation assistance) required over a 24-hour period.Many computerized documentation systems include standardized care plans or clinical practice guidelines (CPGs) to facilitate the creation and documentation of a nursing and or interprofessional plan of care. Each CPG facilitates safe and consistent care for an identified problem by describing or listing institutional standards and evidence-based guidelines that are easily accessed and included in a patient's electronic health record. Verbal orders occur when a health care provider gives therapeutic orders to a registered nurse while they are standing in proximity to one another.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify elements to include when documenting a patient's discharge plan.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse developed the following discharge summary sheet. Which critical information should the nurse add? TOPIC DISCHARGE SUMMARY Medication Diet Activity level Follow-up care Wound care Phone numbers When to call the doctor Time of discharge",
            "options": [
              "Clinical decision support system",
              "Admission nursing history",
              "Mode of transportation",
              "SOAP notes"
            ],
            "answer": "Mode of transportation",
            "explanation": "List actual time of discharge, mode of transportation, and who accompanied the patient for discharge summary information.Clinical decision support systems (CDSSs) are computerized programs used within the health care setting, to aid and support clinical decision making. The knowledge base within a CDSS contains rules and logic statements that link information required for clinical decisions in order to generate tailored recommendations for individual patients that are presented to nurses as alerts,warnings, or other information for consideration. A nurse completes a nursing history form when a patient is admitted to a nursing unit, not when the patient is discharged. SOAP notes are not given to patients who are being discharged. SOAP notes are a type of documentation style.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify elements to include when documenting a patient's discharge plan.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A home health nurse is preparing for an initial home visit. Which information should be included in the patient's home care medical record?",
            "options": [
              "Nursing process form",
              "Step-by-step skills manual",
              "A list of possible procedures",
              "Reports to third-party payers"
            ],
            "answer": "Reports to third-party payers",
            "explanation": "Information in the home care medical record includes patient assessment, referral and intake forms, interprofessional plan of care, a list of medications, and reports to third-party payers. An interprofessional plan of care is used rather than a nursing process form. A step-by-step skills manual and a list of possible procedures are not included in the record.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify important aspects of home care and long-term care documentation.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse in a long-term care setting that is funded by Medicare and Medicaid is completing standardized protocols for assessment and care planning for reimbursement. Which task is the nurse completing?",
            "options": [
              "A minimum data set",
              "An admission assessment and acuity level",
              "A focused assessment/specific body system",
              "An intake assessment form and auditing phase"
            ],
            "answer": "A minimum data set",
            "explanation": "The Resident Assessment Instrument (RAI), which includes the Minimum Data Set (MDS) and the Care Area Assessment (CAA),is the data set that is federally mandated for use in long-term care facilities by CMS. MDS assessment forms are completed upon admission, and then periodically, within specific guidelines and time frames for all residents in certified nursing homes. The MDSalso determines the reimbursement level under the prospective payment system. A focused assessment is limited to a specific body system. An admission assessment and acuity level is performed in the hospital. An intake form is for home health. There is no such thing as an auditing phase in an assessment intake.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify important aspects of home care and long-term care documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is charting. Which event is critical for the nurse to document?",
            "options": [
              "The patient had a good day with no complaints.",
              "The family is demanding and argumentative.",
              "The patient received a pain medication.",
              "The family is poor and had to go on welfare."
            ],
            "answer": "The patient received a pain medication.",
            "explanation": "Nursing interventions and treatments (e.g., medication administration) must be documented. Avoid using generalized, empty phrases such as “status unchanged” or “had good day.” Do not document retaliatory or critical comments about a patient, like demanding and argumentative. Family is poor is not critical information to chart.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe five quality guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is completing an Outcome and Assessment Information Set (OASIS) data set on a patient. The nurse works in which area of patient care?",
            "options": [
              "Home health",
              "Intensive care unit",
              "Skilled nursing facility",
              "Long-term care facility"
            ],
            "answer": "Home health",
            "explanation": "Nurses use two different data sets to document the clinical assessments and care provided in the home care setting, the Outcome and Assessment Information Set (OASIS), and the Omaha System. The intensive care unit does not use the OASIS data set. The long-term health care setting includes skilled nursing facilities (SNFs) in which patients receive 24-hour day care.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify important aspects of home care and long-term care documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to document a patient who has reported chest pain. Which information provided by the patient is critical for the nurse to include?",
            "options": [
              "“My family doesn't believe I'm in pain.”",
              "Pupils equal and reactive to light.",
              "Had poor results from the pain medication.",
              "Reports sharp pain of 8 on a scale of 1 to 10."
            ],
            "answer": "Reports sharp pain of 8 on a scale of 1 to 10.",
            "explanation": "You need to ensure the information within a recorded entry or a report is complete, containing appropriate and essential information (pain of 8). Document subjective and objective assessment. While pupils equal and reactive to light is data, it does not relate to the chest pain; this information would be critical for a head injury. Derogatory or inappropriate comments about the patient or family is not appropriate. This kind of language can be used as evidence for nonprofessional behavior or poor quality of care.Avoid using generalized, empty phrases like “poor results.” Use complete, concise descriptions.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss legal guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which action will the nurse take when taking a telephone order?",
            "options": [
              "Print out a copy of the order once entered into the electronic health record.",
              "Read back the order as written to the health care provider for verification.",
              "Ask that another registered nurse listen to the call over an extension line.",
              "Verify that the health care provider will write the order within 24 hours."
            ],
            "answer": "Read back the order as written to the health care provider for verification.",
            "explanation": "A read back of a telephone order is required and should contain all pertinent information so that verification can be secured. None of the other options provide verification of the details related to the order itself.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss legal guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation ",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse obtained a telephone order from a primary care provider for a patient in pain. Which chart entry should the nurse document?",
            "options": [
              "12/16/20XX 0915 Morphine, 2 mg, IV every 4 hours for incisional pain. VO Dr. Day/J. Winds, RN, read back.",
              "12/16/20XX 0915 Morphine, 2 mg, IV every 4 hours for incisional pain. TO J. Winds, RN, read back.",
              "12/16/20XX 0915 Morphine, 2 mg, IV every 4 hours for incisional pain. TO Dr. Day/J. Winds, RN, read back.",
              "12/16/20XX 0915 Morphine, 2 mg, IV every 4 hours for incisional pain. TO J. Winds, RN."
            ],
            "answer": "12/16/20XX 0915 Morphine, 2 mg, IV every 4 hours for incisional pain. TO Dr. Day/J. Winds, RN, read back.",
            "explanation": "The nurse receiving a TO or VO enters the complete order into the computer using the computerized provider order entry (CPOE)software or writes it out on a physician's order sheet for entry in the computer as soon as possible. After you have taken the order,read the order back, using the “read back” process, and document that you did this to provide evidence that the information received (such as call back instructions and/or therapeutic orders) was verified with the provider. An example follows: “10/16/2015(08:15), Change IV fluid to Lactated Ringers with Potassium 20 mEq/L to run at 125 mL/hr. TO: Dr. Knight/J. Woods, RN, read back.” VO stands for verbal order, not telephone order. The health care provider's name and read back must be included in the chart entry.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss legal guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching the staff about informatics. Which information from the staff indicates the nurse needs to follow up?",
            "options": [
              "To be proficient in informatics, a nurse should be able to discover, retrieve, and use information in practice.",
              "A nurse needs to know how to find, evaluate, and use information effectively.",
              "If a nurse has computer competency, the nurse is competent in informatics.",
              "Nursing informatics is a recognized specialty area of nursing practice."
            ],
            "answer": "If a nurse has computer competency, the nurse is competent in informatics.",
            "explanation": "When the staff make an incorrect statement, then the nurse needs to follow up. Competence in informatics is not the same as computer competency. All the rest are correct information, so the nurse does not need to follow up. To become competent in informatics, you need to be able to use evolving methods of discovering, retrieving, and using information in practice. This means that you learn to recognize when information is needed and have the skills to find, evaluate, and use that information effectively.Nursing informatics is a specialty that integrates the use of information and computer technology to support all aspects of nursing practice, including direct delivery of care, administration, education, and research.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relationship between informatics and quality health care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A hospital is using a computer system that allows all health care providers to use a protocol system to document the care they provide. Which type of system/design will the nurse be using?",
            "options": [
              "Clinical decision support system",
              "Nursing process design",
              "Critical pathway design",
              "Computerized provider order entry system"
            ],
            "answer": "Critical pathway design",
            "explanation": "One design model for Nursing Clinical Information Systems (NCIS) is the protocol or critical pathway design. This design facilitates interdisciplinary management of information because all health care providers use evidence-based protocols or critical pathways to document the care they provide. The knowledge base within a CDSS contains rules and logic statements that link information required for clinical decisions in order to generate tailored recommendations for individual patients, which are presented to nurses as alerts, warnings, or other information for consideration. The nursing process design is the most traditional design for an NCIS. This design organizes documentation within well-established formats such as admission and postoperative assessments, problem lists, care plans, discharge planning instructions, and intervention lists or notes. Computerized provider order entry (CPOE) systems allow health care providers to directly enter orders for patient care into the hospital's information system.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relationship between informatics and quality health care.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse wants to reduce data entry errors on the computer system. Which action should the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Use the same password all the time.",
              "Share password with only one other staff member.",
              "Print out and review computer nursing notes at home.",
              "Chart on the computer immediately after care is provided."
            ],
            "answer": "Chart on the computer immediately after care is provided.",
            "explanation": "To increase accuracy and decrease unnecessary duplication, many health care agencies keep records or computers near a patient's bedside to facilitate immediate documentation of information as it is collected. A good system requires frequent, random changes in personal passwords to prevent unauthorized persons from tampering with records. When using a health care agency computer system, it is essential that you do not share your computer password with anyone under any circumstances. You destroy all papers containing personal information immediately after you use them. Taking nursing notes home is a violation of the Health InsurancePortability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) and confidentiality.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify ways to reduce data entry errors.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which entry will require follow-up by the nurse manager? \n\n0800 Patient states, “Fell out of bed.” Patient found lying by bed on the floor. Legs equal in length bilaterally with no distortion, pedal pulses strong, leg strength equal and strong, no bruising or bleeding. Neuro checks within normal limits. States, “Did not pass out.” Assisted back to bed. Nurse call system within reach. Bed monitor on. \n--Jane More, RN \n0810 Notified primary care provider of patient's status. New orders received. \n--Jane More, RN \n0815 Portable x-ray of L hip taken in room. States, “I feel fine.” \n--Jane More, RN \n0830 Incident report completed and placed on chart. \n--Jane More, RN",
            "options": [
              "0800",
              "0810",
              "0815",
              "0830"
            ],
            "answer": "0830",
            "explanation": "Do not include any reference to an incident in the medical record; therefore, the nurse manager must follow up. A notation about an incident report in a patient's medical record makes it easier for a lawyer to argue that the reference makes the incident report part of the medical record and therefore subject to attorney review. When an incident occurs, document an objective description of what happened, what you observed, and the follow-up actions taken, including notification of the patient's health care provider in the patient's medical record. Remember to evaluate and document the patient's response to the incident.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Discuss legal guidelines for documentation.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient has a diagnosis of pneumonia. Which entry should the nurse chart to help with financial reimbursement?",
            "options": [
              "Used incentive spirometer to encourage coughing and deep breathing. Lung congested upon auscultation in lower lobes bilaterally. Pulse oximetry 86%. Oxygen per nasal cannula applied at 2 L/min per standing order.",
              "Cooperative, patient coughed and deep breathed using a pillow as a splint. Stated,“felt better.” Finally, patient had no complaints.",
              "Breathing without difficulty. Sitting up in bed watching TV. Had a good day.",
              "Status unchanged. Remains stable with no abnormal findings. Checked every 2 hours."
            ],
            "answer": "Used incentive spirometer to encourage coughing and deep breathing. Lung congested upon auscultation in lower lobes bilaterally. Pulse oximetry 86%. Oxygen per nasal cannula applied at 2 L/min per standing order.",
            "explanation": "Accurately documenting services provided, including the supplies and equipment used in a patient's care, clarifies the type of treatment a patient received. This documentation also supports accurate and timely reimbursement to a health care agency and/or patient. None of the other options had equipment or supplies listed. Avoid using generalized, empty phrases such as “status unchanged” or “had good day.” Do not enter personal opinions—stating that the patient is cooperative is a personal opinion and should be avoided. “Finally, patient had no complaints” is a critical comment about the patient and if charted can be used as evidence of nonprofessional behavior or poor quality of care.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relationship between documentation and financial reimbursement for health care.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching the staff about health care reimbursement. Which information should the nurse include in the teaching session?",
            "options": [
              "Home health, long-term care, and hospital nurses' documentation can affect reimbursement for health care.",
              "A clinical information system must be installed by 2014 to obtain health care reimbursement.",
              "A “near miss” helps determine reimbursement issues for health care.",
              "HIPAA is the basis for establishing reimbursement for health care."
            ],
            "answer": "Home health, long-term care, and hospital nurses' documentation can affect reimbursement for health care.",
            "explanation": "Nurses' documentation practices in home health, long-term care, and hospitals can determine reimbursement for health care. A“near miss” is an incident where no property was damaged and no patient or personnel were injured, but given a slight shift in time or position, damage or injury could have easily occurred. A clinical information system (CIS) does not have to be installed by 2014to obtain reimbursement. CIS programs include monitoring systems; order entry systems; and laboratory, radiology, and pharmacy systems. Diagnosis-related groups (DRGs) are the basis for establishing reimbursement for patient care, not HIPAA. Legislation to protect patient privacy regarding health information is the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relationship between documentation and financial reimbursement for health care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is discussing the advantages of a nursing clinical information system. Which advantage should the nurse describe?",
            "options": [
              "Varied clinical databases",
              "Reduced errors of omission",
              "Increased hospital costs",
              "More time to read charts"
            ],
            "answer": "Reduced errors of omission",
            "explanation": "Advantages associated with the nursing information system include reduced errors of omission; better access to information (not more time to read charts); enhanced quality of documentation; reduced, not increased, hospital costs; increased nurse job satisfaction; compliance with requirements of accrediting agencies (e.g., TJC); and development of a common, not varied, clinical database.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the advantages of a nursing information system.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which behaviors indicate the student nurse has a good understanding of confidentiality and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA)? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Writes the patient's room number and date of birth on a paper for school.",
              "Prints/copies material from the patient's health record for a graded care plan.",
              "Reviews assigned patient's record and another unassigned patient's record.",
              "Gives a change-of-shift report to the oncoming nurse about the patient.",
              "Reads the progress notes of assigned patient's record.",
              "Discusses patient care with the hospital volunteer."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Gives a change-of-shift report to the oncoming nurse about the patient.",
                "Reads the progress notes of assigned patient's record."
            ],
            "explanation": "When you are a student in a clinical setting, confidentiality and compliance with HIPAA are part of professional practice. Reading the progress notes of an assigned patient's record and giving a change-of-shift report to the oncoming nurse about the patient are behaviors that follow HIPAA and confidentiality guidelines. Do not share information with other patients or health care team members who are not caring for a patient. Not only is it unethical to view medical records of other patients, but breaches of confidentiality lead to disciplinary action by employers and dismissal from work or nursing school. To protect patient confidentiality, ensure that written materials used in your student clinical practice do not include patient identifiers (e.g., room number, date of birth, demographic information), and never print material from an electronic health record for personal use.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify ways to maintain confidentiality of electronic and written records.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is describing the purposes of a health care record to a group of nursing students. Which purposes will the nurse include in the teaching session? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Communication",
              "Legal documentation",
              "Reimbursement",
              "Nursing process",
              "Research",
              "Education"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Communication",
                "Legal documentation",
                "Reimbursement",
                "Research",
                "Education"
            ],
            "explanation": "A patient's record is a valuable source of data for all members of the health care team. Its purposes include interdisciplinary communication, legal documentation, financial billing (reimbursement), education, research, and auditing/monitoring. Nursing process is a way of thinking and performing nursing care; it is not a purpose of a health care record.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify purposes of a health care record.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is developing a plan to reduce data entry errors and maintain confidentiality. Which guidelines should the nurse include? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Bypass the firewall.",
              "Implement an automatic sign-off.",
              "Create a password with just letters.",
              "Use a programmed speed-dial key when faxing.",
              "Impose disciplinary actions for inappropriate access.",
              "Shred papers containing personal health information (PHI)."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Implement an automatic sign-off.",
                "Use a programmed speed-dial key when faxing.",
                "Impose disciplinary actions for inappropriate access.",
                "Shred papers containing personal health information (PHI)."
            ],
            "explanation": "When faxing, use programmed speed-dial keys to eliminate the chance of a dialing error and misdirected information. An automatic sign-off is a safety mechanism that logs a user off the computer system after a specified period of inactivity. Disciplinary action,including loss of employment, occurs when nurses or other health care personnel inappropriately access patient information. All papers containing PHI (e.g., Social Security number, date of birth or age, patient's name or address) must be destroyed immediately after you use or fax them. Most agencies have shredders or locked receptacles for shredding and incineration. Strong passwords use combinations of letters, numbers, and symbols that are difficult to guess. A firewall is a combination of hardware and software that protects private network resources (e.g., the information system of the hospital) from outside hackers, network damage, and theft or misuse of information and should not be bypassed.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify ways to reduce data entry errors.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is using focused charting referred to as DAR. Match the chart entry to the correct letter of the acronym.",
            "matching": [
              "D",
              "A",
              "R"
            ],
            "options": [
              "Applied oxygen, stayed with patient, and instructed to slow breathing.",
              "Patient states, “feel better,” respirations 16 with O2 saturations 96%.",
              "Patient states, “can't catch my breath and chest hurts.” Confused."
            ],
            "answer": {
              "D": "Patient states, “can't catch my breath and chest hurts.” Confused.",
              "A": "Applied oxygen, stayed with patient, and instructed to slow breathing.",
              "R": "Patient states, “feel better,” respirations 16 with O2 saturations 96%."
            },
            "explanation": "DAR stands for Data, Action, and Response.\nThe Data in this scenario would be the patients statement of \"Can't catch my breath and chest hurts\" while confused.\nThe Action would be applying oxygen, staying with the patient, and instructing them to slow their breathing.\nThe Response would be the patient stating \"I feel better\", with respirations 16 with O2 saturations at 96%.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the different methods used in record keeping.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          }
    ],
    "chapter31": [
        {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about medications. Which statement from the patient indicates teaching is effective?",
            "options": [
              "“My parenteral medication must be taken with food.”",
              "“I will rotate the sites in my left leg when I give my insulin.”",
              "“Once I start feeling better, I will stop taking my antibiotic.”",
              "“If I am 30 minutes late taking my medication, I should skip that dose.”"
            ],
            "answer": "“I will rotate the sites in my left leg when I give my insulin.”",
            "explanation": "For daily insulin, rotate site within anatomical area. Rotating injections within the same body part (instrasite rotation) provides greater consistency in absorption of medication. Parenteral medication absorption is not affected by the timing of meals. Taking a medication 30 minutes late is within the 60-minute window of the time medications should be taken. Medications are usually stopped based on the provider's orders except in extenuating circumstances. With some medications, such as antibiotics, it is crucial that the full course of medication is taken to avoid relapse of infection.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss nursing roles and responsibilities in medication administration.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to administer an injection to a patient. Which statement made by the patient is an indication for the nurse to use the Z-track method?",
            "options": [
              "“I am allergic to many medications.”",
              "“I'm really afraid that a big needle will hurt.”",
              "“The last shot really irritated my skin around the site.”",
              "“My legs are too obese for the needle to go through.”"
            ],
            "answer": "“The last shot really irritated my skin around the site.”",
            "explanation": "The Z-track is indicated when the medication being administered has the potential to irritate sensitive tissues. It is recommended that, when administering IM injections, the Z-track method be used to minimize local skin irritation by sealing the medication in muscle tissue. The Z-track method is not meant to reduce discomfort from the procedure. If a patient is allergic to a medication, it should not be administered. If a patient has additional subcutaneous tissue to go through, a needle of a different size may be selected.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe factors to consider when choosing routes of medication administration.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A 2-year-old child is ordered to have eardrops daily. Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Pull the auricle down and back to straighten the ear canal.",
              "Pull the auricle upward and outward to straighten the ear canal.",
              "Sit the child up for 2 to 3 minutes after instilling drops in ear canal.",
              "Sit the child up to insert the cotton ball into the innermost ear canal."
            ],
            "answer": "Pull the auricle down and back to straighten the ear canal.",
            "explanation": "Children up to 3 years of age should have the auricle pulled down and back, children 3 years of age to adults should have the auricle pulled upward and outward. Solution should be instilled 1 cm (1/2 in) above the opening of the ear canal. The patient should remain in the side-lying position 2 to 3 minutes. If a cotton ball is needed, place it into the outermost part of the ear canal.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient has been prescribed to receive 0.3 mL of U-500 insulin. Which syringe will the nurse use to administer the medication?",
            "options": [
              "3-mL syringe",
              "U-100 syringe",
              "Needleless syringe",
              "Tuberculin syringe"
            ],
            "answer": "Tuberculin syringe",
            "explanation": "Because there is no syringe currently designed to prepare U-500 insulin, many medication errors result with this kind of insulin. To prevent errors, ensure that the order for U-500 specifies units and volume (e.g., 150 units, 0.3 mL of U-500 insulin), and use tuberculin syringes to draw up the doses. A 3 mL and U-100 can result in inaccurate dosing. A needleless syringe will not be acceptable in this situation.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Implement nursing actions to prevent medication errors.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient has an order to receive 12.5 mg of hydrochlorothiazide. The nurse has on hand a 25 mg tablet of hydrochlorothiazide. How many tablet(s) will the nurse administer?",
            "options": [
              "1/2 tablet",
              "1 tablet",
              "1 1/2 tablets",
              "2 tablets"
            ],
            "answer": "1/2 tablet",
            "explanation": "1/2 tablet will be given. The nurse is careful to perform nursing calculations to ensure proper medication administration. The dose ordered is 12.5. The dose on hand is 25. 12.5/25 = 1/2 tablet. ",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Calculate prescribed medication doses correctly.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is to receive phenytoin at 0900. When will be the ideal time for the nurse to schedule a trough level?",
            "options": [
              "0800",
              "0830",
              "0900",
              "0930"
            ],
            "answer": "0830",
            "explanation": "Trough levels are generally drawn 30 minutes before the drug is administered. If the medication is administered at 0900, the trough should be drawn at 0830.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss factors to include in assessing a patient's needs for and response to medication therapy.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is receiving vancomycin. Which physiological function is the priority for the nurses to assess?",
            "options": [
              "Vision",
              "Hearing",
              "Heart tones",
              "Bowel sounds"
            ],
            "answer": "Hearing",
            "explanation": "A side effect of vancomycin is ototoxicity—hearing. It does not affect vision, heart tones, or bowel sounds.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Differentiate among different types of medication actions.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A health care provider orders lorazepam 1 mg orally 2 times a day. The dose available is 0.5 mg per tablet. How many tablet(s) will the nurse administer for each dose?",
            "options": [
              "1",
              "2",
              "3",
              "4"
            ],
            "answer": "2",
            "explanation": "The nurse will give 2 tablets. It will take 2 tablets (0.5) to equal 1 mg OR ordered dose (1) over dose on hand (0.5). 1/0.5 = 2 tablets.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Calculate prescribed medication doses correctly.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is preparing to administer an injection into the deltoid muscle of an adult patient weighing approximately 160 lb. Which needle size and length will the nurse choose?",
            "options": [
              "18 gauge x 1 1/2 inch",
              "23 gauge x 1/2 inch",
              "25 gauge x 1 inch",
              "27 gauge x 5/8 inch"
            ],
            "answer": "25 gauge x 1 inch",
            "explanation": "For an intramuscular injection into an adult deltoid muscle, a 25-gauge, 1-inch needle is recommended. An 18-gauge needle is too big. While a 23-gauge needle can be used, a 1/2-inch needle is too small. A 27-gauge, 5/8-inch needle is used for intradermal.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe factors to consider when choosing routes of medication administration.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "When the nurse administers an intramuscular (IM) corticosteroid injection, the nurse aspirates. What is the rationale for the nurse aspirating?",
            "options": [
              "Prevent the patient from choking.",
              "Increase the force of the injection.",
              "Ensure proper placement of the needle.",
              "Reduce the discomfort of the injection."
            ],
            "answer": "Ensure proper placement of the needle.",
            "explanation": "The purpose of aspiration is to ensure that the needle is in the muscle and not in the vascular system. Blood return upon aspiration indicates improper placement, and the injection should not be given. While a patient can aspirate fluid and food into the lungs, this is not related to the reason for why a nurse pulls back the syringe plunger after inserting the needle (aspirates) before injecting the medication. Reducing discomfort and prolonging absorption time are not reasons for aspirating medications.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Implement nursing actions to prevent medication errors.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is giving an intramuscular (IM) injection. Upon aspiration, the nurse notices blood return in the syringe. What should the nurse do?",
            "options": [
              "Administer the injection at a slower rate.",
              "Withdraw the needle and prepare the injection again.",
              "Pull the needle back slightly and inject the medication.",
              "Give the injection and hold pressure over the site for 3 minutes."
            ],
            "answer": "Withdraw the needle and prepare the injection again.",
            "explanation": "Blood return upon aspiration indicates improper placement, and the injection should not be given. Instead withdraw the needle,dispose of the syringe and needle properly, and prepare the medication again. Administering the medication into a blood vessel could have dangerous adverse effects, and the medication will be absorbed faster than intended owing to increased blood flow.Holding pressure is not an appropriate intervention. Pulling back the needle slightly does not guarantee proper placement of the needle and medication administration.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is planning to administer a tuberculin test with a 27-gauge, 5 8-inch needle. At which angle will the nurse insert the needle?",
            "options": [
              "15 degree",
              "30 degree",
              "45 degree",
              "90 degree"
            ],
            "answer": "15 degree",
            "explanation": "A 27-gauge, 58-inch needle is used for intradermal injections such as a tuberculin test, which should be inserted at a 5- to 15-degree angle, just under the dermis of the skin. Placing the needle at 30, 45, or 90 degrees will place the medication too deep.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe factors to consider when choosing routes of medication administration.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse closely monitors an older adult for signs of medication toxicity. Which physiological change is the reason for the nurse's action?",
            "options": [
              "Reduced kidney functioning",
              "Reduced esophageal stricture",
              "Increased gastric motility",
              "Increased liver mass"
            ],
            "answer": "Reduced kidney functioning",
            "explanation": "The reduced glomerular filtration rate delays excretion, increasing chance for toxicity by the kidneys. In older adults, gastricmotility and liver mass decrease. Esophageal stricture is not a physiological change associated with normal aging.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss developmental factors that influence pharmacokinetics.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A registered nurse interprets that a scribbled medication prescription reads 25 mg. The nurse administers 25 mg of the medication to a patient and then discovers that the dose was incorrectly interpreted and should have been 15 mg. Who is ultimately responsible for the error?",
            "options": [
              "Health care provider",
              "Pharmacist",
              "Hospital",
              "Nurse"
            ],
            "answer": "Nurse",
            "explanation": "Ultimately, the person administering the medication is responsible for ensuring that it is correct. The nurse administered the medication, so in this case it is the nurse. Accept full accountability and responsibility for all actions surrounding the administration of medications. Do not assume that a medication that is ordered for a patient is the correct medication or the correct dose. This is the importance of verifying the six rights of medication administration. The ultimate responsibility and accountability are with the nurse, not the health care provider, pharmacist, or hospital. ",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast the roles of the health care provider, pharmacist, and nurse in medication administration.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is to receive a proton pump inhibitor through a nasogastric (NG) feeding tube. Which nursing action is vital to ensuring effective absorption?",
            "options": [
              "Thoroughly shake the medication before administering.",
              "Position patient in the supine position for 30 minutes to 1 hour.",
              "Hold feeding for at least 30 minutes after medication administration.",
              "Flush tube with 10 to 15 mL of water, after all medications are administered."
            ],
            "answer": "Hold feeding for at least 30 minutes after medication administration.",
            "explanation": "If a medication needs to be given on an empty stomach or is not compatible with the feeding (e.g., phenytoin, carbamazepine, warfarin, fluoroquinolones, proton pump inhibitors), hold the feeding for at least 30 minutes before or 30 minutes after medication administration. Thoroughly shaking the medication mixes the medication before administration but does not affect absorption.Flushing the tube after all medications should be 30 to 60 mL of water; 15 to 30 mL of water is used for flushing between medications. Patients with NG tubes should never be positioned supine but instead should be positioned at least to a 30-degree angle to prevent aspiration, provided no contraindication condition is known.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A health care provider prescribes aspirin 650 mg every 4 hours PO when febrile. For which patient will this order be appropriate?",
            "options": [
              "A 7 year old with a bleeding disorder",
              "A 21 year old with a sprained ankle",
              "A 35 year old with a severe headache from hypertension",
              "A 62 year old with a high fever from an infection"
            ],
            "answer": "A 62 year old with a high fever from an infection",
            "explanation": "Aspirin is an analgesic, an antipyretic, and an antiinflammatory medication. The provider wrote the medication to be given for a fever (febrile). Fevers are common in infections. If a child is bleeding, aspirin would be contraindicated; aspirin increases the likelihood of bleeding. Although it can be used for inflammatory problems (sprained ankle) and pain/analgesia (severe headache),this is not how the order was written.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Discuss factors to include in assessing a patient's needs for and response to medication therapy.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is in need of immediate pain relief for a severe headache. Which medication will the nurse administer to be absorbed the quickest?",
            "options": [
              "Acetaminophen 650 mg PO",
              "Hydromorphone 4 mg IV",
              "Ketorolac 8 mg IM",
              "Morphine 6 mg SQ"
            ],
            "answer": "Hydromorphone 4 mg IV",
            "explanation": "IV is the fastest route for absorption owing to the increase in blood flow. The richer the blood supply to the site of administration,the faster a medication is absorbed. Medications administered intravenously enter the bloodstream and act immediately, whereas those given in other routes take time to enter the bloodstream and have an effect. Oral, subcutaneous (SQ), and intramuscular (IM)are other ways to deliver medication but with less blood flow, slowing absorption.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss factors that influence medication actions.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "While preparing medications, the nurse knows one of the drug is an acidic medication. In which area does the nurse anticipate the drug will be absorbed?",
            "options": [
              "Stomach",
              "Mouth",
              "Small intestine",
              "Large intestine"
            ],
            "answer": "Stomach",
            "explanation": "Acidic medications pass through the gastric mucosa rapidly. Medications that are basic are not absorbed before reaching the small intestine.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe factors to consider when choosing routes of medication administration.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse administers a central nervous system stimulant to a patient. Which assessment finding indicates to the nurse that an idiosyncratic event is occurring?",
            "options": [
              "Falls asleep during daily activities.",
              "Presents with a pruritic rash.",
              "Develops restlessness.",
              "Experiences alertness."
            ],
            "answer": "Falls asleep during daily activities.",
            "explanation": "An idiosyncratic event is a reaction opposite to what the effects of the medication normally are, or the patient overreacts or under reacts to the medication. Falls asleep is an opposite effect of what a central nervous system stimulant should do. A stimulant should make a patient restless and alert. A pruritic (itch) rash could indicate an allergic reaction.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Differentiate among different types of medication actions.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A prescription is written for phenytoin 500 mg IM q3-4h prn for pain. The nurse recognizes that treatment of pain is not a standard therapeutic indication for this drug. The nurse believes that the health care provider meant to write hydromorphone. What action should the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Call the health care provider to clarify the order.",
              "Give the patient hydromorphone, as it was meant to be written.",
              "Administer the medication and monitor the patient frequently.",
              "Refuse to give the medication and notify the nurse supervisor."
            ],
            "answer": "Call the health care provider to clarify the order.",
            "explanation": "If there is any question about a medication order because it is incomplete, illegible, vague, or not understood, contact the healthcare provider before administering the medication. The nurse cannot change the order without the prescriber's consent; this is out of the nurse's scope of practice. Ultimately, the nurse can be held responsible for administering an incorrect medication. If the prescriber is unwilling to change the order and does not justify the order in a reasonable and evidence-based manner, the nurse may refuse to give the medication and notify the supervisor.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast the roles of the health care provider, pharmacist, and nurse in medication administration.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient needs assistance in eliminating an anesthetic gaseous medication (nitrous oxide). Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Encourage the patient to cough and deep-breathe.",
              "Suction the patient's respiratory secretions.",
              "Suggest voiding every 2 hours.",
              "Increase fluid intake."
            ],
            "answer": "Encourage the patient to cough and deep-breathe.",
            "explanation": "Gaseous and volatile medications are excreted through gas exchange (lungs). Deep breathing and coughing will assist in clearing the medication more quickly. It is a gaseous medication and cannot be suctioned out of the lungs. It is not excreted through the kidneys, so fluids and voiding will not help. ",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the physiological mechanisms of medication action.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse has withdrawn a narcotic from the medication dispenser and must waste a portion of the medication. What should the nurse do?",
            "options": [
              "Have another nurse witness the wasted medication.",
              "Return the wasted medication to the medication dispenser.",
              "Place the wasted portion of the medication in the sharps container.",
              "Exit the medication room to call the health care provider to request an order that matches the dosages."
            ],
            "answer": "Have another nurse witness the wasted medication.",
            "explanation": "The nurse should follow Nurse Practice Acts and safe narcotic administration guidelines by having a nurse witness the “wasted”medication. The nurse cannot return the wasted medication to the medication dispenser. Wasted portions of medications are not placed in sharps containers. The nurse should not leave the narcotic unattended and call the health care provider to obtain matching dosages; the nurse is expected to obtain the correct dose.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse teaches the patient about the prescribed buccal medication. Which statement by the patient indicates teaching by the nurse is successful?",
            "options": [
              "“I should let the medication dissolve completely.”",
              "“I will place the medication in the same location.”",
              "“I can only drink water, not juice, with this medication.”",
              "“I better chew my medication first for faster distribution.”"
            ],
            "answer": "“I should let the medication dissolve completely.”",
            "explanation": "Buccal medications should be placed in the side of the cheek and allowed to dissolve completely. Buccal medications act with the patient's saliva and mucosa. The patient should not chew or swallow the medication or take any liquids with it. The patient should rotate sides of the cheek to avoid irritating the mucosal lining.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss methods used to educate patients about prescribed medications.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "What is the nurse's priority action to protect a patient from medication error?",
            "options": [
              "Reading medication labels at least 3 times before administering",
              "Administering as many of the medications as possible at one time",
              "Asking anxious family members to leave the room before giving a medication",
              "Checking the patient's room number against the medication administration record"
            ],
            "answer": "Reading medication labels at least 3 times before administering",
            "explanation": "One step to take to prevent medication errors is to read labels at least 3 times before administering the medication. The nurse should address the family's concerns about medications before administering them. Do not discount their anxieties. The medication administration record should be checked against the patient's hospital identification band; a room number is not an acceptable identifier. Medications should be given when scheduled, and medications with special assessment indications should be separated.Giving medications at one time can cause the patient to aspirate.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Implement nursing actions to prevent medication errors.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse has prepared a pain injection for a patient but was called to check on another patient. When asked to give the medication what action by the new nurse is best?",
            "options": [
              "Refuse to give the medication.",
              "Administer the medication just this once.",
              "Give the medication if the pain score greater than 8.",
              "Avoid the issue and pretend to not hear the request."
            ],
            "answer": "Refuse to give the medication.",
            "explanation": "Because the nurse who administers the medication is responsible for any errors related to it, nurses administer only the medications they prepare. You cannot delegate preparation of medication to another person and then administer the medication to the patient.The right medication cannot be verified by the new nurse; do not violate the six rights. Do not administer the medication even onetime. Do not administer the medication regardless of the pain rating. Avoiding the issue is not appropriate or safe.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Identify the six rights of medication administration and apply them in clinical settings.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is at risk for aspiration. Which nursing action is most appropriate?",
            "options": [
              "Give the patient a straw to control the flow of liquids.",
              "Have the patient self-administer the medication.",
              "Thin out liquids so they are easier to swallow.",
              "Turn the head toward the stronger side."
            ],
            "answer": "Have the patient self-administer the medication.",
            "explanation": "Aspiration occurs when food, fluid, or medication intended for GI administration inadvertently enters the respiratory tract. To minimize aspiration risk, allow the patient, if capable, to self-administer medication. Patients should also hold their own cup to control how quickly they take in fluid. Some patients at risk for aspiration may require thickened liquids; thinning liquids does not decrease aspiration risk. Patients at risk for aspiration should not be given straws because use of a straw decreases the control the patient has over volume intake. Turning the head toward the weaker side helps the medication move down the stronger side of the esophagus.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss factors to include in assessing a patient's needs for and response to medication therapy.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient refuses medication. Which is the nurse's first action?",
            "options": [
              "Educate the patient about the importance of the medication.",
              "Discreetly hide the medication in the patient's favorite gelatin.",
              "Agree with the patient's decision and document it in the chart.",
              "Explore with the patient reasons for not wanting to take the medication."
            ],
            "answer": "Explore with the patient reasons for not wanting to take the medication.",
            "explanation": "The first response is to explore reasons the patient does not want the medication. After the assessment, the nurse can decide what todo next. Educating is important, but it is not the first action. Ultimately, the patient does have the right to refuse the medication;however, the nurse should first try to find out reasons for the refusal and provide education if needed based upon the assessment findings. Hiding medication and deceiving a patient into taking a medication is unethical and violates right to autonomy.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss methods used to educate patients about prescribed medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient who is being discharged today is going home with an inhaler. The patient is to administer 2 puffs of the inhaler twice daily. The inhaler contains 200 puffs. When should the nurse appropriately advise the patient to refill the medication?",
            "options": [
              "6 weeks from the start of using the inhaler.",
              "As soon as the patient leaves the hospital.",
              "When the inhaler is half empty.",
              "50 days after discharge."
            ],
            "answer": "6 weeks from the start of using the inhaler.",
            "explanation": "Six weeks will be about the time the inhaler will need to be refilled. The inhaler should last the patient 50 days (2 puffs x 2/twice daily = 4; 200/4 = 50); the nurse should advise the patient to refill the prescription when there are 7 to 10 days of medication remaining. Refilling it as soon as the patient leaves the hospital or when the inhaler is half empty is too early. If the patient waits 50days, the patient will run out of medication before it can be refilled.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Calculate prescribed medication doses correctly.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The supervising nurse is watching nurses prepare medications. Which action by one of the nurses will result in the supervising nurse to intervene immediately?",
            "options": [
              "Rolls insulin vial between hands.",
              "Administers a dose of correction insulin.",
              "Draws up glargine (Lantus) in a syringe by itself.",
              "Prepares NPH insulin to be given intravenously (IV)."
            ],
            "answer": "Prepares NPH insulin to be given intravenously (IV).",
            "explanation": "The only insulin that can be given IV is regular. NPH cannot be given IV and must be stopped. All the rest demonstrate correct practice. Insulin is supposed to be rolled, not shaken. Glargine is supposed to be given by itself; it cannot be mixed with another medication. Correction insulin, also known as sliding-scale insulin, provides a dose of insulin based on the patient's blood glucose level. The term correction insulin is preferred because it indicates that small doses of rapid- or short-acting insulins are needed to correct a patient's elevated blood sugar.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which patient does the nurse most closely monitor for an unintended synergistic effect?",
            "options": [
              "The 4 year old who has mistakenly taken a half bottle of vitamins.",
              "The 35 year old who has ingested meth mixed with several household chemicals.",
              "The 50 year old who is prescribed a second blood pressure medication.",
              "The 72 year old who is seeing four different specialists."
            ],
            "answer": "The 72 year old who is seeing four different specialists.",
            "explanation": "The 72 year old seeing four different providers is likely to experience polypharmacy. Polypharmacy places the patient at risk for unintended mixing of medications that potentiate each other. When two medications have a synergistic effect, their combined effect is greater than the effect of the medications when given separately. The child taking too much of a medication by mistake could experience overdose or toxicity. The 50 year old is prescribed two different blood pressure medications for their synergistic effect,but this is a desired, intended event. A patient taking meth and mixing chemicals can be toxic.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Differentiate among different types of medication actions.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which patient using an inhaler would benefit most from using a spacer?",
            "options": [
              "A 15 year old with a repaired cleft palate who is alert",
              "A 25 year old with limited coordination of the extremities",
              "A 50 year old with hearing impairment who uses a hearing aid",
              "A 72 year old with left-sided hemiparesis using a dry powder inhaler"
            ],
            "answer": "A 25 year old with limited coordination of the extremities",
            "explanation": "A spacer is indicated for a patient who has difficulty coordinating the steps, like patients with limited mobility/coordination. An alert adolescent with a repaired cleft palate would not need a spacer. Hearing impairment may make teaching the patient to use the inhaler difficult, but it does not indicate the need for a spacer. Although a patient with left-sided hemiparesis could have coordination problems, a patient using a dry powder inhaler does not require the use of spacers.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Describe factors to consider when choosing routes of medication administration.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The prescriber wrote for a 40-kg child to receive 25 mg of medication 4 times a day. The therapeutic range is 5 to 10 mg/kg/day. What is the nurse's priority?",
            "options": [
              "Change the dose to one that is within range.",
              "Administer the medication because it is within the therapeutic range.",
              "Notify the health care provider that the prescribed dose is in the toxic range.",
              "Notify the health care provider that the prescribed dose is below the therapeutic range."
            ],
            "answer": "Notify the health care provider that the prescribed dose is below the therapeutic range.",
            "explanation": "The dosage range is 200 to 400 mg a day (5 x 40 = 200 and 10 x 40 = 400). The prescribed dose is 100 mg/day (4 x 25 = 100),which is below therapeutic range. The nurse should notify the health care provider first and ask for clarification on the order. The dose is not above the therapeutic range and is not at a toxic level. The nurse should never alter an order without the prescriber's approval and consent.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Calculate prescribed medication doses correctly.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The supervising nurse is observing several different nurses. Which action will cause the supervising nurse to intervene?",
            "options": [
              "A nurse administers a vaccine without aspirating.",
              "A nurse gives an IV medication through a 22-gauge IV needle without blood return.",
              "A nurse draws up the NPH insulin first when mixing a short-acting and intermediate-acting insulin.",
              "A nurse calls the health care provider for a patient with nasogastric suction and orders for oral meds."
            ],
            "answer": "A nurse draws up the NPH insulin first when mixing a short-acting and intermediate-acting insulin.",
            "explanation": "The supervising nurse must intervene with the nurse who is drawing up the NPH insulin first; if regular and intermediate-acting(NPH) insulin is ordered, prepare the regular insulin first to prevent the regular insulin from becoming contaminated with the intermediate-acting insulin. All the other actions are appropriate and do not need follow-up. The CDC no longer recommends aspiration when administering immunizations to reduce discomfort. In some cases, especially with a smaller gauge (22) IV needle,blood return is not aspirated, even if the IV is patent. If the IV site shows no signs of infiltration and IV fluid is infusing without difficulty, proceed with IV push slowly. Oral meds are contraindicated in patients with nasogastric suction.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who is receiving pain medication through a saline lock. After flushing the patient's peripheral IV and obtaining a good blood return, the patient reports pain. Upon assessment, the nurse notices a red streak that is warm and tender to the touch. What is the nurse's initial action?",
            "options": [
              "Do not administer the pain medication.",
              "Administer the pain medication slowly.",
              "Apply a warm compress to the site.",
              "Apply a cool compress to the site."
            ],
            "answer": "Do not administer the pain medication.",
            "explanation": "The patient has phlebitis; the initial nursing action is do not administer the medication. The medication should not be given slowly.A cool or warm compress may be used later depending upon protocol, but it is not the first action.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss factors to include in assessing a patient's needs for and response to medication therapy.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is preparing to administer medications to two patients with the same last name. After the administration, the nurse realizes that did not check the identification of the patient before administering medication. Which action should the nurse complete first?",
            "options": [
              "Return to the room to check and assess the patient.",
              "Administer the antidote to the patient immediately.",
              "Alert the charge nurse that a medication error has occurred.",
              "Complete proper documentation of the medication error in the patient's chart."
            ],
            "answer": "Return to the room to check and assess the patient.",
            "explanation": "When an error occurs, the patient's safety and well-being are the top priorities. You first assess and examine the patient's condition and notify the health care provider of the incident as soon as possible. The nurse's first priority is to establish the safety of the patient by assessing the patient. Second, notify the charge nurse and the health care provider. Administer antidote if required.Finally, the nurse needs to complete proper documentation.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Implement nursing actions to prevent medication errors.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for two patients with the same last name. In this situation which right of medication administration is the priority to reduce the chance of an error?",
            "options": [
              "Right medication",
              "Right patient",
              "Right dose",
              "Right route"
            ],
            "answer": "Right patient",
            "explanation": "The nurse should ask the patient to verify identity and should check the patient's ID bracelet against the medication record to ensure right patient. Acceptable patient identifiers include the patient's name, an identification number assigned by a health care facility, or a telephone number. Do not use the patient's room number as an identifier. To identify a patient correctly in an acute care setting, compare the patient identifiers on the MAR with the patient's identification bracelet while at the patient's bedside.Right medication, right dose, and right route are equally as important, but in this situation, right patient is the priority (two patients with the same last name).",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Identify the six rights of medication administration and apply them in clinical settings.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient prefers not to take the daily allergy pill this morning because it causes drowsiness throughout the day. Which response by the nurse is best?",
            "options": [
              "The physician ordered it; therefore, you must take your medication every morning at the same time whether you're drowsy or not.",
              "Let's see if we can change the time you take your pill to 9 PM, so the drowsiness occurs when you would normally be sleeping.",
              "You can skip this medication on days when you need to be awake and alert.",
              "Try to get as much done as you can before you take your pill, so you can sleep in the afternoon."
            ],
            "answer": "Let's see if we can change the time you take your pill to 9 PM, so the drowsiness occurs when you would normally be sleeping.",
            "explanation": "The nurse should use knowledge about the medication to educate the patient about potential response to medications. Then the medication schedule can be altered based on that knowledge. It is the patient's right to refuse medication; however, the nurse should educate the patient on the importance and effects of the medication. Asking a patient to fit a schedule around a medication is unreasonable and will decrease compliance. The nurse should be supportive and should offer solutions to manage medication effects.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss factors to include in assessing a patient's needs for and response to medication therapy.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to administer a medication from a vial. In which order will the nurse perform the steps, starting with the first step?\n\n1. Invert the vial.\n2. Fill the syringe with medication.\n3. Inject air into the airspace of the vial.\n4. Clean with alcohol swab and allow to dry.\n5. Pull back on the plunger the amount to be drawn up.\n6. Tap the side of the syringe barrel to remove air bubbles.",
            "options": [
              "4, 1, 5, 3, 6, 2",
              "1, 4, 5, 3, 2, 6",
              "4, 5, 3, 1, 2, 6",
              "1, 4, 5, 3, 6, 2"
            ],
            "answer": "4, 5, 3, 1, 2, 6",
            "explanation": "When preparing medication from a vial, the steps are as follows: Firmly and briskly wipe the surface of the rubber seal with an alcohol swab and allow to dry; pull back on the plunger to draw an amount of air into the syringe equal to the volume of medication to be aspirated from the vial; inject air into the airspace of the vial; invert the vial while keeping firm hold on the syringe and plunger; fill the syringe with medication; and tap the side of the syringe barrel carefully to dislodge any air bubbles. ",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is attempting to administer an oral medication to a child, but the child refuses to take the medication. A parent is in the room. Which statement by the nurse to the parent is best?",
            "options": [
              "Please hold your child's arms down, so I can give the full dose.",
              "I will prepare the medication for you and observe if you would like to try to administer the medication.",
              "Let's turn the lights off and give your child a moment to fall asleep before administering the medication.",
              "Since your child loves applesauce, let's add the medication to it, so your child doesn't resist."
            ],
            "answer": "I will prepare the medication for you and observe if you would like to try to administer the medication.",
            "explanation": "Children often have difficulties taking medication, but it can be less traumatic for the child if the parent administers the medication and the nurse supervises. Another nurse should help restrain a child if needed; the parent acts as a comforter, not a restrainer.Holding down the child is not the best option because it may further upset the child. Never administer an oral medication to a sleeping child. Don't mix medications into the child's favorite foods, because the child might start to refuse the food.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss developmental factors that influence pharmacokinetics.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "An older-adult patient needs an intramuscular (IM) injection of antibiotic. Which site is best for the nurse to use?",
            "options": [
              "Deltoid",
              "Dorsal gluteal",
              "Ventrogluteal",
              "Vastus lateralis"
            ],
            "answer": "Ventrogluteal",
            "explanation": "The ventrogluteal site is the preferred and safest site for all adults, children, and infants. While the vastus lateralis is a large muscle that could be used, it is not the preferred and safest. The dorsal gluteal site is a location for a subcutaneous injection, and this patient requires an IM injection. The deltoid is easily accessible, but this muscle is not well developed and is not the preferred site.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss factors that influence medication actions.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing an intravenous (IV) piggyback infusion. In which order will the nurse perform the steps, starting with the first one?\n\n1. Compare the label of the medication with the medication administration record at the patient's bedside.\n2. Connect the tubing of the piggyback infusion to the appropriate connector on the upper Y-port.\n3. Hang the piggyback medication bag above the level of the primary fluid bag.\n4. Clean the main IV line port with an antiseptic swab.\n5. Connect the infusion tubing to the medication bag.\n6. Regulate flow.",
            "options": [
              "5, 2, 1, 4, 3, 6",
              "5, 2, 1, 3, 4, 6",
              "1, 5, 4, 3, 2, 6",
              "1, 5, 3, 4, 2, 6"
            ],
            "answer": "1, 5, 3, 4, 2, 6",
            "explanation": "When preparing and administering IV piggybacks, use the following steps: Compare the label of medication with the medication administration record at the patient's bedside; connect the infusion tubing to the medication bag; hang the piggyback medication bag above the level of the primary fluid bag; clean the main IV-line port with an antiseptic swab; connect the tubing of the piggyback infusion to the appropriate connector on the upper Y-port; and regulate flow.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is administering oral medications to patients. Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Remove the medication from the wrapper and place it in a cup labeled with the patient's information.",
              "Place all of the patient's medications in the same cup, except medications with assessments.",
              "Crush enteric-coated medication and place it in a medication cup with water.",
              "Measure liquid medication by bringing liquid medication cup to eye level."
            ],
            "answer": "Place all of the patient's medications in the same cup, except medications with assessments.",
            "explanation": "Placing medications that require pre-administration assessment in a separate cup serves as a reminder to check before the medication is given, making it easier for the nurse to withhold medication if necessary. Medications should not be removed from their package until they are in the patient's room because this makes identification of the pill easier and reduces contamination.When measuring a liquid, the nurse should use the meniscus level to measure; make sure it is at eye level on a hard surface like a counter top. Enteric coated medications should not be crushed.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is performing the three accuracy checks before administering an oral liquid medication to a patient. When will the nurse perform the second accuracy check?",
            "options": [
              "At the patient's bedside",
              "Before going to the patient's room",
              "When checking the medication order",
              "When selecting medication from the unit-dose drawer"
            ],
            "answer": "Before going to the patient's room",
            "explanation": "Before going to the patient's room, compare the patient's name and name of medication on the label of prepared drugs with MARfor the second accuracy check. Selecting the correct medication from the stock supply, unit-dose drawer, or automated dispensing system (ADS) is the first check. The third accuracy check is comparing names of medications on labels with MAR at the patient's bedside. Checking the orders is not one of the three accuracy checks but should be done if there is any confusion about an order.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to administer an antibiotic medication at 1000 to a patient but gets busy in another room. When should the nurse give the antibiotic medication?",
            "options": [
              "By 1030",
              "By 1100",
              "By 1130",
              "By 1200"
            ],
            "answer": "By 1030",
            "explanation": "Give time-critical scheduled medications (e.g., antibiotics, anticoagulants, insulin, anti convulsants, and immunosuppressive agents)at the exact time ordered (within 30 minutes before or after scheduled dose). Give non-time critical scheduled medications within a range of either 1 or 2 hours of scheduled dose. 1100, 1130, and 1200 are too late.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is administering medications to several patients. Which action should the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Advise a patient to wait 2 minutes after a corticosteroid inhaler treatment to rinse mouth with water.",
              "Administer an intravenous medication through tubing that is infusing blood.",
              "Pinch up the deltoid muscle of an adult patient receiving a vaccination.",
              "Aspirate before administering a subcutaneous injection in the abdomen."
            ],
            "answer": "Advise a patient to wait 2 minutes after a corticosteroid inhaler treatment to rinse mouth with water.",
            "explanation": "If the patient uses a corticosteroid, have him or her wait 2 minutes and then rinse the mouth out with water or salt water or brush teeth after inhalation to reduce risk of fungal infection. Piercing a blood vessel during a subcutaneous injection is very rare.Therefore, aspiration is not necessary when administering subcutaneous injections. When giving immunizations to adults: to avoid injection into subcutaneous tissue, spread the skin of the selected vaccine administration site taut between the thumb and forefinger,isolating the muscle. Never administer IV medications through tubing that is infusing blood, blood products, or parenteral nutrition solutions.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is following safety principles to reduce the risk of needle stick injury. Which actions will the nurse take? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Recap the needle after giving an injection.",
              "Remove needle and dispose in sharps box.",
              "Never force needles into the sharps disposal.",
              "Use clearly marked sharps disposal containers.",
              "Use needleless devices whenever possible."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Never force needles into the sharps disposal.",
                "Use clearly marked sharps disposal containers.",
                "Use needleless devices whenever possible."
            ],
            "explanation": "Needles should not be forced into the box. Clearly mark receptacles to warn of danger. Using needleless systems when possible will further reduce the risk of needle stick injury. To prevent the risk of needle sticks, the nurse should never recap needles. The syringe and sheath are disposed of together in a receptacle.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which methods will the nurse use to administer an intravenous (IV) medication that is incompatible with the patient's IV fluid? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Start another IV site.",
              "Administer slowly with the IV fluid.",
              "Do not give the medication and chart.",
              "Flush with 10 mL of sterile water before and after administration.",
              "Flush with 10 mL of normal saline before and after administration."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Start another IV site.",
                "Flush with 10 mL of sterile water before and after administration.",
                "Flush with 10 mL of normal saline before and after administration."
            ],
            "explanation": "When IV medication is incompatible with IV fluids, stop the IV fluids, clamp the IV line above the injection site, flush with 10 mLof normal saline or sterile water, give the IV bolus over the appropriate amount of time, flush with another 10 mL of normal saline or sterile water at the same rate as the medication was administered, and restart the IV fluids at the prescribed rate. Do not administer the drug slowly with the IV; this is contraindicated when incompatibility exist. Not giving the medication and charting is inappropriate; this is not a prudent or safe action by the nurse.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Correctly and safely prepare and administer medications.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is taking 1 tablet of hydrocodone bitartrate 5 mg and acetaminophen 500 mg every 4 hours. The patient is also taking 2 tablets of acetaminophen 325 mg every 12 hours. How many grams of acetaminophen is the patient taking daily? Record your answer using one decimal place. ______ g",
            "options": [
                "3",
                "3.7",
                "3.3",
                "4.1"
            ],
            "answer": "3.3",
            "explanation": "The nurse should calculate the dosage taken via the first medication and add it to the daily intake of the second medication. Then,convert milligrams to grams.500 mg x 6 doses a day = 3000 mg/day + (2 tablets x 325 mg) x 2 doses a day = 1300 mg/day = 3300 mg/day total of acetaminophen; 3300 mg converted to grams = 3.3 g.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Calculate prescribed medication doses correctly.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The Nurse is administering 250 mg of a medication elixir to the patient. The medication comes in a dose of 1000 mg/5 mL. How many milliliters should the nurse administer? Record your answer using two decimal places. ____ mL",
            "options": [
                "1.15",
                "1.54",
                "1.25",
                "1.34"
            ],
            "answer": "1.25",
            "explanation": "The nurse needs to first determine how many milligrams are in each milliliter of the elixir. Then the nurse calculates how many milliliters would contain 250 mg.1000 mg/5 mL = 200 mg/1 mL250 mg/(X mL) = 200 mg/mL = 1.25 mL. OR Dose ordered over dose on hand (250/1000) x volume or amount on hand (5).250/1000 = 0.25 x 5 = 1.25 mL.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Calculate prescribed medication doses correctly.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is to receive amoxicillin 500 mg q8h; the medication is dispensed at 250 mg/5 mL. How many milliliters will the nurse administer for one dose? Record your answer using a whole number. ___ mL",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "8",
                "12",
                "9"
            ],
            "answer": "10",
            "explanation": "The drug is dispensed at 250 mg/5 mL. The nurse is to give 500 mg, which is 10 mL. OR Dose ordered over dose on hand(500/250) x volume or amount on hand (5). 500/250 x 5 = 10 mL.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Calculate prescribed medication doses correctly.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          }
    ],
    "chapter32": [
        {
            "question": "A patient describes practicing a complementary and alternative therapy involving breathwork and yoga. The nurse also recommends using energy field therapies. Which techniques did the nurse suggest?",
            "options": [
              "Prayer and tai chi",
              "The “zone” and acupressure",
              "Massage therapy and ayurveda",
              "Reiki therapy and therapeutic touch"
            ],
            "answer": "Reiki therapy and therapeutic touch",
            "explanation": "Both yoga and breathwork are mind-body therapies, whereas both reiki and therapeutic touch therapies are energy field therapies.Tai chi is mind-body intervention. Acupressure and massage are body-based methods. Ayurvedic is a type of whole medical system.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the methods of and the psychophysiological responses to therapeutic touch.",
            "top": "Implementation ",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A teen diagnosed with an anxiety disorder is referred for biofeedback training because the parents do not want their child to take anxiolytics. Which statement from the teen indicates successful learning?",
            "options": [
              "Biofeedback will help me with my thoughts and physiological responses to stress.",
              "Biofeedback will direct my energies in an intentional way when stressed.",
              "Biofeedback will allow me to manipulate my stressed-out joints.",
              "Biofeedback will let me assess and redirect my energy fields."
            ],
            "answer": "Biofeedback will help me with my thoughts and physiological responses to stress.",
            "explanation": "By using electromechanical instruments, a person can receive information or feedback on his or her stress level. Having this knowledge allows the patient to develop awareness and voluntary control over his or her physiological symptoms. Biofeedback does not address energy fields; healing touch, reiki, and therapeutic touch are energy fields. Directing energies is therapeutic touch.Manipulation of body alignment and joints is done by a chiropractor.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the purpose and principles of biofeedback.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "An older-adult patient is newly admitted to a skilled nursing facility. Medications brought on admission included lisinopril, hydrochlorothiazide, warfarin, low-dose aspirin, Ginkgo biloba, and echinacea. Which potential interaction will cause the nurse to notify the patient's health care provider?",
            "options": [
              "Echinacea and warfarin",
              "Lisinopril and echinacea",
              "Warfarin and G. biloba",
              "Lisinopril and hydrochlorothiazide"
            ],
            "answer": "Warfarin and G. biloba",
            "explanation": "Warfarin and blood thinners interact with G. biloba (designed to improve memory). All herbal supplements should be evaluated with current pharmacological medications. The other options do not have interactions with each other.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe safe and unsafe herbal therapies.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient asks the nurse for a nonmedical approach for excessive worry and work stress. Which therapy should the nurse recommend?",
            "options": [
              "Meditation",
              "Acupuncture",
              "Ayurvedic herbs",
              "Chiropractic care"
            ],
            "answer": "Meditation",
            "explanation": "Meditation is indicated for stress-related illness and is a nonmedical approach. In addition, meditation increases productivity,improves mood, increases sense of identity, and lowers irritability. Acupuncture, ayurvedic, and chiropractic are all medical approaches. The use of ayurvedic herbs has been available for centuries to treat illness and is a type of whole medical system.Acupuncture focuses on redirecting vital energy (qi) in the body's meridian energy lines to influence deeper internal organs.Chiropractic therapy involves manipulation of the spinal column and includes physiotherapy and diet therapy.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Describe the clinical applications of relaxation therapies.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching about the therapy that is more effective in treating physical ailments than in preventing disease or managing chronic illness. Which therapy is the nurse describing?",
            "options": [
              "Complementary",
              "Allopathic",
              "Alternative",
              "Mind-body"
            ],
            "answer": "Allopathic",
            "explanation": "Despite the success of allopathic or biomedicine (conventional Western medicine), many conditions such as chronic back and neck pain, arthritis, gastrointestinal problems, allergies, headache, and anxiety continue to be difficult to treat. Complementary,alternative, and mind-body types of medicines can be used in tandem with allopathic medicines but are distinctly different.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Differentiate between complementary and alternative therapies.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "During a relaxation therapy skills group, the instructor discusses the cognitive skill of learning to tolerate uncertain and unfamiliar experiences. Which skill is the nurse describing?",
            "options": [
              "Passivity",
              "Focusing",
              "Mindfulness",
              "Receptivity"
            ],
            "answer": "Receptivity",
            "explanation": "Receptivity is defined as the ability to tolerate and accept experiences that are uncertain, unfamiliar, or paradoxical. Passivity is the ability to stop unnecessary goal-directed and analytical activity. Focusing is the ability to identify, differentiate, maintain attention on, and return attention to simple stimuli for an extended period. Mindfulness is not a cognitive skill needed in relaxation therapy but is needed for meditation.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relaxation response and its effect on somatic ailments.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient asks about the new clinic in town that is staffed by allopathic and complementary practitioners. Which term would best describe this type of clinic?",
            "options": [
              "Ayurvedic",
              "Homeopathic",
              "Integrative medical",
              "Naturopathic medical"
            ],
            "answer": "Integrative medical",
            "explanation": "An integrative medical program allows health care consumers to be treated by a team of providers consisting of both allopathic and complementary practitioners. Several therapies are always considered alternative because they are based on completely different philosophies and life systems from those used by allopathic medicine. Alternative therapies include ayurvedic, homeopathic, and naturopathic.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Differentiate between complementary and alternative therapies.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The group leader is overheard saying to the gathering of patients, “Focus on your breathing once again .... Notice how it is regular .... Now focus on your left arm .... Notice how relaxed your left arm feels .... Notice the relaxation going down the left arm to the hand.” A patient asks the nurse what the group is doing. What is the nurse's best response?",
            "options": [
              "Progressive relaxation training",
              "Group biofeedback",
              "Guided imagery",
              "Meditation"
            ],
            "answer": "Progressive relaxation training",
            "explanation": "Progressive relaxation training teaches the individual how to effectively rest and reduce tension in the body. The technique used in this scenario involves the use of slow, deep abdominal breathing while tightening and relaxing an ordered succession of muscle groups. Although meditation does include abdominal breathing, along with guided imagery and biofeedback, it does not include tightening and relaxing of muscle groups in an ordered succession.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the clinical applications of relaxation therapies.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A therapeutic touch practitioner scans the patient's body for the purpose of identifying what?",
            "options": [
              "Blocked moxibustion",
              "Universal life energy",
              "Energy field obstructions",
              "Structural and functional imbalance"
            ],
            "answer": "Energy field obstructions",
            "explanation": "The practitioner scans the body of the patient with the palms (roughly 2 to 6 inches [5 to 15 cm] from the body) from head to toe.While assessing the energetic biofield of the patient, the practitioner focuses on the quality of the qi and areas of energy obstructions, redirecting the energy to harmonize and move. Chiropractic therapy involves balancing structural and functional imbalance through spinal manipulation. Moxibustion is a traditional Chinese medicine technique that involves burning moxa, a cone or stick of dried herbs that have healing properties, on or near the skin. Reiki therapy transfers “universal life energy.”",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the methods of and the psychophysiological responses to therapeutic touch.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about meridians. Which technique is the nurse preparing the patient to receive?",
            "options": [
              "Acupuncture",
              "Naturopathic",
              "Latin American traditional healing",
              "Native American traditional healing"
            ],
            "answer": "Acupuncture",
            "explanation": "Acupuncture regulates or realigns the vital energy (qi), which flows like a river through the body in channels that form a system of20 pathways called meridians. Naturopathic therapeutics include herbal medicine, nutritional supplementation, physical medicine,homeopathy, lifestyle counseling, and mind-body therapies with an orientation toward assisting the person's internal capacity for self-healing (vitalism). Tribal traditions are individualistic, but similarities across traditions include the use of sweating and purging, herbal remedies, and ceremonies in which a shaman (a spiritual healer) makes contact with spirits to ask their direction in bringing healing to people to promote wholeness and healing. Curanderismo is a Latin American traditional healing system that includes a humoral model for classifying food, activity, drugs, and illnesses and a series of folk illnesses. The goal is to create a balance between the patient and his or her environment, thereby sustaining health.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Differentiate between complementary and alternative therapies.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A Native American patient is asking for a spiritual healer. Which person should the nurse try to contact for the patient?",
            "options": [
              "Shaman",
              "Vitalist",
              "Ayurvedic",
              "Curanderismo"
            ],
            "answer": "Shaman",
            "explanation": "Tribal traditions are individualistic, but similarities across traditions include the use of sweating and purging, herbal remedies, and ceremonies in which a shaman (a spiritual healer) makes contact with spirits to ask their direction in bringing healing to people to promote wholeness and healing. Naturopathic therapeutics include herbal medicine, nutritional supplementation, physical medicine, homeopathy, lifestyle counseling, and mind-body therapies with an orientation toward assisting the person's internal capacity for self-healing (vitalism). One of the oldest systems of medicine (Ayurvedic) has been practiced in India since the first century AD. Curanderismo is a Latin American traditional healing system that includes a humoral model for classifying food,activity, drugs, and illnesses and a series of folk illnesses.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Differentiate between complementary and alternative therapies.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is using the holistic approach to care. Which goal is the priority?",
            "options": [
              "Integrate spiritual treatments.",
              "Join physical care with a vegan diet.",
              "Incorporate the mind-body-spirit connection.",
              "Use complementary and alternative therapies."
            ],
            "answer": "Incorporate the mind-body-spirit connection.",
            "explanation": "Beliefs and values that are consistent with an approach to health that incorporates the mind, body, and spirit comprise the holistic approach. Holistic nursing treats the mind-body-spirit of the patient, using interventions such as relaxation therapy, music therapy,touch therapies, and guided imagery. Spiritual treatments are a part of holistic care but not the priority. A vegan diet is an aspect of dietary treatment, but it does not allow for alternative viewpoints or well-rounded care. A holistic nurse may use complementary and alternative therapies to meet the priority goal of incorporating body-mind-spirit.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Differentiate between complementary and alternative therapies.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is using caring-healing relationships to support whole person/whole systems healing. Which type of nursing is the nurse using?",
            "options": [
              "Holistic nursing",
              "Integrative nursing",
              "Interprofessional nursing",
              "Complementary and alternative nursing"
            ],
            "answer": "Integrative nursing",
            "explanation": "Grounded in six principles, integrative nursing is defined as “a way of being-knowing-doing that advances the health and well-being of persons, families, and communities through caring-healing relationships.” Integrative nurses use evidence to inform traditional and emerging interventions that support whole person/whole systems healing. Holistic nursing treats the mind-body-spirit of the patient, using interventions such as relaxation therapy, music therapy, touch therapies, and guided imagery.Integrative health care, a strategy that is gaining popularity, involves interprofessional group practices where patients receive care simultaneously from more than one type of practitioner; nurses must interact with other health care professionals for any type of nursing. An integrative nurse will use complementary and alternative therapies to provide integrative nursing.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Differentiate between complementary and alternative therapies.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient relaxation techniques to decreases stress. Which finding will support the nurse's evaluation that the therapy is effective?",
            "options": [
              "Dilated pupils",
              "Increased blood sugar",
              "Decreased heart rate",
              "Elevated blood pressure"
            ],
            "answer": "Decreased heart rate",
            "explanation": "Decreased heart and respiratory rates, blood pressure, and oxygen consumption and increased alpha brain activity and peripheral skin temperature characterize the relaxation response. The physiological cascade of changes associated with the stress response includes increased heart and respiratory rates, muscle tightening, increased metabolic rate, a sense of foreboding, fear, nervousness,irritability, and a negative mood. Other physiological responses include elevated blood pressure; dilated pupils; stronger cardiac contractions; and increased levels of blood glucose, serum cholesterol, circulating free fatty acids, and triglycerides.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relaxation response and its effect on somatic ailments.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is providing different types of therapies to a patient with excessive fatigue. Which technique will cause the nurse manager to intervene?",
            "options": [
              "Meditation",
              "Guided imagery",
              "Passive relaxation",
              "Active progressive relaxation"
            ],
            "answer": "Active progressive relaxation",
            "explanation": "The nurse manager needs to intervene if the nurse uses active progressive relaxation. Active progressive relaxation is not appropriate for patients with advanced disease or decreased energy reserves. Passive relaxation or guided imagery or meditation is more appropriate for these individuals.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the relaxation response and its effect on somatic ailments.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is emphasizing the use of touch to decrease “skin hunger” in caring for patients. Which age-group is the nurse primarily describing?",
            "options": [
              "Infants",
              "Children",
              "Middle age",
              "Older adults"
            ],
            "answer": "Older adults",
            "explanation": "Touch is a primal need, as necessary as food, growth, or shelter. Touch is like a nutrient transmitted through the skin, and “skin hunger” is like a form of malnutrition that has reached epidemic proportions in the United States, especially among older adults. While infants, children, and middle age may be affected, it is the older adult who is most affected.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the methods of and the psychophysiological responses to therapeutic touch.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is proficient at meditation from long-time use of the technique. Which finding in the medication history will cause the nurse to follow up?",
            "options": [
              "Thyroid-regulating medication",
              "Corticosteroid medication",
              "Loop diuretic medication",
              "Anticoagulant medication"
            ],
            "answer": "Thyroid-regulating medication",
            "explanation": "Prolonged practice of meditation techniques sometimes reduces the need for antihypertensive, thyroid-regulating, and psychotropic medications (e.g., antidepressants and antianxiety agents). In these cases, adjustment of the medication is necessary. Corticosteroid,loop diuretic, and anticoagulant medications are not affected by meditation.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify the principles and effectiveness of imagery, meditation, and breathwork.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is taking an antidepressant medication. The nurse discovers that the patient uses herbs. Which herb will cause the nurse to intervene?",
            "options": [
              "Aloe",
              "Garlic",
              "Chamomile",
              "Saw palmetto"
            ],
            "answer": "Chamomile",
            "explanation": "Potential drug interactions with chamomile include drugs that cause drowsiness like antidepressants. Aloe, garlic, and saw palmetto do not interfere with antidepressants.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe safe and unsafe herbal therapies.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about the use of biofeedback. Which goal should the nurse add to the care plan?",
            "options": [
              "Opens emotional channels.",
              "Uses music to calm the mind.",
              "Holds various postures with breathing.",
              "Controls autonomic physiological functions."
            ],
            "answer": "Controls autonomic physiological functions.",
            "explanation": "Biofeedback is a process providing a person with visual or auditory information about autonomic physiological functions of the body such as muscle tension, skin temperature, and brain wave activity through the use of instruments. Breathwork can open emotional channels. Music therapy uses music to address physical, psychological, cognitive, and social needs of certain individuals.Yoga focuses on body musculature, holding of postures, and proper breathing mechanisms.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the purpose and principles of biofeedback.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which medical diagnosis will cause the nurse to question an order for acupuncture?",
            "options": [
              "Acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)",
              "Osteoarthritis",
              "Low back pain",
              "Migraine headaches"
            ],
            "answer": "Acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)",
            "explanation": "You need to exercise caution when using acupuncture with pregnant patients and those who have a history of seizures, are carriers of hepatitis, or are immune compromised (AIDS). Acupuncture is a safe therapy for low back pain, migraine headaches, and osteoarthritis.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Differentiate between complementary and alternative therapies.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is describing the therapeutic effects of imagery. Which information should the nurse include in the teaching session? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Controls pain.",
              "Decreases nightmares.",
              "Improves social anxiety disorders.",
              "Helps with irritable bowel syndrome.",
              "Reduces relapses in alcohol treatment."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Controls pain.",
                "Decreases nightmares.",
                "Helps with irritable bowel syndrome."
            ],
            "explanation": "Imagery helps control or relieve pain, decrease nightmares, and improve sleep. It also aids in the treatment of chronic conditions such as irritable bowel syndrome. Increased anxiety and fear sometimes occur when imagery is used to treat posttraumatic stress disorders and social anxiety disorders. Meditation successfully reduces relapses in alcohol treatment programs.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify the principles and effectiveness of imagery, meditation, and breathwork.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a class over herbs and their uses. Which condition will the nurse match to its specific herb for the teaching session?",
            "matching": [
              "Aloe",
              "Garlic",
              "Valerian",
              "Ginger",
              "Saw palmetto",
              "Chaparral"
            ],
            "options": [
              "Elevated cholesterol levels",
              "Nausea and vomiting",
              "Benign prostatic hyperplasia",
              "Skin inflammation",
              "Mild anxiety",
              "Unsafe and should not be used"
            ],
            "answer": {
              "Aloe": "Skin inflammation",
              "Garlic": "Elevated cholesterol levels",
              "Valerian": "Mild anxiety",
              "Ginger": "Nausea and vomiting",
              "Saw palmetto": "Benign prostatic hyperplasia",
              "Chaparral": "Unsafe and should not be used"
            },
            "explanation": "Aloe would be the best match for skin inflammation.\nGarlic would be best for elevated cholestoral levels.\nValerian is best for mild anxiety.\nGinger is suited for nausea and vomiting.\nSaw palmetto would be used for Benign prostatic hyperplasia.\nChaparral is unsafe and should never be used.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe safe and unsafe herbal therapies.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          }
    ],
    "chapter33": [
      {
        "question": "When caring for an older-adult patient, which technique will the nurse use to enhance an older-adult patient’s self-concept?",
        "options": [
          "Discussing current weather",
          "Encouraging patients to sing",
          "Reviewing old photos with patients",
          "Allowing patients extra computer time"
        ],
        "answer": "Reviewing old photos with patients",
        "explanation": "Nurses can improve self-concept by reviewing old photographs when working with older-adult patients. This form of life review is helpful to older adults in remembering positive life events and people. Discussing weather does not involve personal reflection. Singing does not improve self-concept. Giving patients extra computer time is not applicable to improving self-concept but may help with learning.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "While gathering an adolescent’s health history, the nurse recognizes that the patient began to act out behaviorally and engaged in risky behavior when the patient’s parents divorced. Which information will the nurse gather to help in determining situational low self-esteem?",
        "options": [
          "How long the parents were married?",
          "How the patient views behaviors?",
          "Why the parents are divorcing?",
          "Why the patient is acting out of control?"
        ],
        "answer": "How the patient views behaviors?",
        "explanation": "A nurse can identify situational life stressors that can impact a person’s self-concept. By asking about a patient’s thoughts and feelings, the nurse will be able to use communication skills in a therapeutic manner. This will facilitate the patient’s insight into behaviors and will enable the nurse to make referrals or provide needed health teaching. The length of time married and the reason for the parents’ divorce do not explain the patient’s behaviors. Why the patient is acting out of control is not as important as how the patient views actions when out of control.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a group of adolescents. Which person is most likely to have the highest self-esteem?",
        "options": [
          "Latino adolescent female who has strong ethnic pride.",
          "Caucasian boy who lives below federal poverty level.",
          "African-American adolescent male who has severe acne.",
          "Adolescent who was suspended twice from high school."
        ],
        "answer": "Latino adolescent female who has strong ethnic pride.",
        "explanation": "When cultural identity is central to self-concept and is positive, cultural pride and self-esteem tend to be strong. Environmental stressors such as low-income, body image stressors such as acne, and role performance failure often influence self-esteem negatively.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Examine cultural considerations that affect self-concept.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who is dealing with the developmental task known as initiative versus guilt. The nurse is providing care to which patient?",
        "options": [
          "A 3-week-old neonate",
          "A 5-year-old kindergarten student",
          "An 11-year-old student",
          "A 15-year-old high school student"
        ],
        "answer": "A 5-year-old kindergarten student",
        "explanation": "The initiative versus guilt developmental stage occurs between the ages of 3 and 6 years. The patient is a 5-year-old kindergarten student. If a child shows initiative, the outcome of this developmental task is to develop purpose. A neonate developmental task is to develop trust. An 11-year-old student is into new skill mastery (industry), and a 15-year-old student is struggling with identity versus role confusion.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the components of self-concept as related to psychosocial and cognitive developmental stages.",
        "top": "",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A verbally abusive partner has told a significant other many negative comments over the years. In the crisis center, the nurse would anticipate that the patient may have which self-concept deficits?",
        "options": [
          "Body image",
          "Role confusion",
          "Rigidity",
          "Yearning"
        ],
        "answer": "Body image",
        "explanation": "Over the years of marriage, the significant other incorporates this devaluation into his or her own self-concept, negatively affecting body image. The way others view a person’s body and the feedback offered are also influential on body image and self-concept. Role confusion is part of a developmental task (identity versus role confusion) for adolescents. Rigidity and yearning are not components of self-concept.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss factors that influence the components of self-concept.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Two 50-year-old men are discussing their Saturday activities. The first man describes how he tutors children as a volunteer at a community center. The other man says that he would never work with children and that he prefers to work out at the gym to meet young women to date. Which developmental stage is the second man exhibiting?",
        "options": [
          "Mistrust",
          "Inferiority",
          "Generativity",
          "Self-absorption"
        ],
        "answer": "Self-absorption",
        "explanation": "In the generativity versus self-absorption developmental task, a self-absorbed person is concerned about own personal wants and desires in a self-centered manner. Generativity is the first man’s developmental stage. Trust versus mistrust occurs in the first year of life. Industry versus inferiority commonly occurs in school children. Identity versus role confusion commonly occurs at the start of adolescence into young adulthood.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the components of self-concept as related to psychosocial and cognitive developmental stages.",
        "top": "",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "An adult son is adjusting to the idea of his chronically ill parents moving into his family home. The community health nurse is assessing the adult son for potential stressors secondary to the new family living arrangement. Which stressor will the nurse assess for in this adult son?",
        "options": [
          "Role confusion",
          "Role ambiguity",
          "Role performance",
          "Role overload"
        ],
        "answer": "Role overload",
        "explanation": "Role overload involves having more roles or responsibilities within a role than are manageable. Role overload is common in individuals who unsuccessfully attempt to meet the demands of work and family while trying to find some personal time. Role confusion is an aspect of the developmental task of adolescence and young adulthood (identity versus role confusion). Role ambiguity involves unclear role expectations. Role performance is the way in which individuals perceive their ability to carry out significant roles; it is not a stressor unless it is judged ineffective. There is no data in the question to indicate this.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify stressors that affect self-concept and self-esteem.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse grimaces while changing a patient’s colostomy bag. Which effect will the nurse’s behavior most likely have on the patient?",
        "options": [
          "Assist recovery by using honest communication.",
          "Motivate the patient to increase physical activity.",
          "Promote development of a negative body image.",
          "Develop a kind nickname for the colostomy bag."
        ],
        "answer": "Promote development of a negative body image.",
        "explanation": "Negative nonverbal reactions by a nurse to a patient’s scar or surgical alterations contribute to the patient’s developing a negative body image. Nurses who have shocked or disgusted facial expressions contribute to patients’ developing a negative body image. Expressions of distaste by the nurse will not facilitate recovery or ongoing communication, encourage physical activity, or promote acceptance of the colostomy bag by adopting a positive nickname.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explore ways in which a nurse’s self-concept and nursing actions affect a patient’s self-concept and self-esteem.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A male patient states, “I’m such a loser. I only had that job for a month.” Which outcome criteria will the nurse add to the patient’s care plan?",
        "options": [
          "The patient will verbalize two life areas in which he functions well.",
          "The patient will find new employment before the next clinic visit.",
          "The patient will confront a former boss about previous work problems.",
          "The patient will identify two reasons why he is considered a bad employee."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient will verbalize two life areas in which he functions well.",
        "explanation": "Verbalizing two life areas in which a person functions well is an individualized measurable outcome that is realistic. Confronting a former boss could have physical and emotional repercussions for the patient. If the patient is voicing that he has problems obtaining employment, then putting extra pressure to obtain employment would be detrimental to the patient and does not reflect a supportive and caring nursing outcome. Focusing on the negative of why the patient is considered a bad employee is not as beneficial as focusing on strengths.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about self-concept. Which information from the patient indicates the nurse needs to follow up about components of self-concept?",
        "options": [
          "One component is identity.",
          "One component is coping.",
          "One component is body image.",
          "One component is role performance."
        ],
        "answer": "One component is coping.",
        "explanation": "The nurse will need to follow up for the information that a component of self-concept is coping; this is a misconception and must be corrected. The components of self-concept are identity, body image, and role performance. While self-concept may affect coping, coping is not a component of self-concept.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the components of self-concept as related to psychosocial and cognitive developmental stages.",
        "top": "",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which individual is most likely to need the nurse’s assistance in coping with identity confusion?",
        "options": [
          "A 49-year-old male with stable employment",
          "A 35-year-old recently divorced mother of twins",
          "A 22-year-old in the third year of college",
          "A 50-year-old self-employed woman"
        ],
        "answer": "A 35-year-old recently divorced mother of twins",
        "explanation": "Identity confusion results when people do not maintain a clear, consistent, and continuous consciousness of personal identity. A newly divorced woman would be trying to adapt to a new lifestyle of being single while handling parenting of twins as a single parent. This situation could lead to identity confusion. A college sophomore would have had at least 2 years to adjust to the new life setting, and a self-employed woman would likely be content with creating her own employment opportunity. There is no indication that the middle-aged man with stable employment should have identity confusion.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss evidence-based practice applicable for identity confusion, disturbed body image, low self-esteem, and role conflict.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a patient for possible altered self-concept. Which assessment finding is consistent with altered self-concept?",
        "options": [
          "Appropriately dressed in clean clothes",
          "Hesitant to express opinions",
          "Independent attitude",
          "Holds eye contact"
        ],
        "answer": "Hesitant to express opinions",
        "explanation": "Hesitant to express views or opinions is a behavior suggestive of altered self-concept. Holds eye contact, independent attitude, and appropriate appearance are all signs of normal self-concept.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a postoperative mastectomy patient. Which action is a priority for increasing self-awareness?",
        "options": [
          "Solving problems for the patient before developing insight",
          "Using communication skills to clarify family and patient expectations",
          "Telling the patient that it will be fine because many others have survived",
          "Rotating nursing personnel in the patient’s care, so the patient can talk to many people"
        ],
        "answer": "Using communication skills to clarify family and patient expectations",
        "explanation": "Increase the patient’s self-awareness by allowing him or her to openly explore thoughts and feelings. A priority nursing intervention is the expert use of therapeutic communication skills to clarify the expectations of a patient and family. Interventions designed to help a patient reach the goal of adapting to changes in self-concept or attaining a positive self-concept are based on the premise that the patient first develops insight and self-awareness concerning problems and stressors and then acts to solve the problems and cope with the stressors. Reassurance that a person will do fine dismisses any potential concerns the patient may have. Rotating nursing personnel does not allow time for the patient to build rapport with any one nurse.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse in an addictions clinic is working with a patient on priority setting before the patient’s discharge from residential treatment. Which goal is a priority at this time?",
        "options": [
          "Identifying local self-help groups before being discharged from the program",
          "Stating a plan to never be tempted by illicit substances after discharge",
          "Staying away from all triggers that cause substance abuse",
          "Recognizing personal areas of weakness to grow stronger"
        ],
        "answer": "Identifying local self-help groups before being discharged from the program",
        "explanation": "Look for strengths in both the individual and the family and provide resources and education to turn limitations into strengths, such as local self-help groups. It is not realistic to avoid ALL triggers that can result in addictive behaviors. It is unrealistic to believe that the patient will never be tempted because temptation can arise from multiple sources. On the other hand, an appropriate priority would be to recognize that triggers will arise and that the patient should learn how to handle being confronted in the post-discharge setting. Having a person talk about weaknesses without recognizing a person’s strengths could be a trigger to return to an addictive lifestyle, so this would not be the most appropriate priority.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about self-concept. Which information from the patient indicates a correct understanding of the teaching?",
        "options": [
          "Self-concept is how a person feels about others.",
          "Self-concept is how a person thinks about others.",
          "Self-concept is how a person feels about oneself.",
          "Self-concept is how a person thinks about oneself."
        ],
        "answer": "Self-concept is how a person thinks about oneself.",
        "explanation": "Self-concept, or how a person thinks about oneself, directly affects self-esteem, or how one feels about oneself. While others may influence self-concept, self-concept is not how one feels or thinks about others.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss factors that influence the components of self-concept.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is evaluating a patient’s self-concept. Which key indicator will the nurse use?",
        "options": [
          "Drug abuse history",
          "Nonverbal behavior",
          "Personal journal entries",
          "Posts on social media"
        ],
        "answer": "Nonverbal behavior",
        "explanation": "Key indicators of a patient’s self-concept are nonverbal behaviors. A history of drug abuse does not necessarily indicate current self-concept, and people who do not have a drug abuse history may have a low self-concept. It would be an invasion of privacy and trust for a nurse to read a patient’s personal journal or social media posts.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a patient’s self-concept. Which area should the nurse assess first?",
        "options": [
          "Role performance",
          "Vital signs",
          "Anxiety",
          "Morals"
        ],
        "answer": "Role performance",
        "explanation": "In assessing self-concept and self-esteem, first focus on each component of self-concept (identity, body image, and role performance). Self-concept is a psychological/emotional issue, not a physical issue for vital signs. Anxiety may be a stressors or a sign of low self-concept. Self-concept is not a moral issue.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A 9 year old is proudly telling the nurse about mastering the yellow belt in a martial arts class. Which developmental stage is the child exhibiting?",
        "options": [
          "Initiative versus guilt",
          "Industry versus inferiority",
          "Identity versus role confusion",
          "Autonomy versus shame and doubt"
        ],
        "answer": "Industry versus inferiority",
        "explanation": "Industry versus inferiority occurs between the ages of 6 and 12 years. It is during this developmental task that a person gains self-esteem through new skill mastery. Initiative versus guilt is for 3 to 6 years, focusing on increasing language skills with identification of feelings. Identity versus role confusion is 12 to 20 years, focusing on finding a sense of self. Autonomy versus shame and doubt is 1 to 3 years, focusing on becoming more independent.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the components of self-concept as related to psychosocial and cognitive developmental stages.",
        "top": "",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is developing a drinking prevention presentation for adolescents. Which areas should the nurse include in the teaching session?",
        "options": [
          "Stressful life events and scholarships",
          "Very high self-esteem and work failure",
          "Health problems and avoidance of conflict",
          "Stress management and improving self-esteem"
        ],
        "answer": "Stress management and improving self-esteem",
        "explanation": "Drinking prevention efforts should include stress management and improving self-esteem. High self-esteem decreases risk of drinking. Stressful life events when balanced with positive issues, such as receipt of a scholarship, are less likely to induce drinking. Conflict resolution can strengthen adolescent coping strategies to decrease drinking.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss evidence-based practice applicable for identity confusion, disturbed body image, low self-esteem, and role conflict.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is completing a history on a patient with role conflict. Which finding is consistent with role conflict?",
        "options": [
          "A patient is unsure about job expectations in a fast-paced company.",
          "A patient has to travel for work and misses children’s birthdays.",
          "A patient feels less of a man after a leg amputation.",
          "A patient loses a job from the company’s downsizing."
        ],
        "answer": "A patient has to travel for work and misses children’s birthdays.",
        "explanation": "Role conflict results when a person has to simultaneously assume two or more roles that are inconsistent, contradictory, or mutually exclusive—for example, when a patient has to travel for work and misses children’s birthdays. Role ambiguity is also common in employment situations. In complex, rapidly changing, or highly specialized organizations, employees often become unsure about job expectations. Feeling less of a man after a leg amputation is a body image and self-concept/self-esteem problem. Losing a job can lead to low self-esteem or loss of job identity.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss evidence-based practice applicable for identity confusion, disturbed body image, low self-esteem, and role conflict.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a patient’s self-concept. Which areas will the nurse include? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Identity",
          "Body image",
          "Coping behaviors",
          "Significant others’ support",
          "Availability of insurance"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Identity",
          "Body image",
          "Coping behaviors",
          "Significant others’ support"
        ],
        "explanation": "Assessment of self-concept includes identity, body image, coping behaviors, and significant others’ support. Availability of insurance is not a component of self-concept.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process to promote a patient’s self-concept.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a group of patients. Match the assessment finding to the area the nurse is assessing.",
        "matching": [
          "Identity confusion",
          "Disturbed body image",
          "Role performance",
          "Low self-esteem"
        ],
        "options": [
          "I am ugly with all these burn scars.",
          "I am one with the universe.",
          "I am good for nothing.",
          "I am a good mother."
        ],
        "answer": {
          "Identity confusion": "I am one with the universe.",
          "Disturbed body image": "I am ugly with all these burn scars.",
          "Role performance": "I am a good mother.",
          "Low self-esteem": "I am good for nothing."
        },
        "explanation": "Identity confusion, characterized by a lack of clear self-concept, is reflected in a patient's statement, \"I am one with the universe.\" This suggests a blurring of personal boundaries and a struggle with identity clarity. Disturbed body image, indicating dissatisfaction or discomfort with one's physical appearance, is evident when a patient expresses, \"I am ugly with all these burn scars.\" This statement highlights a negative perception of one's body, possibly stemming from physical trauma or disfigurement. Assessing role performance involves evaluating how individuals perceive their effectiveness in fulfilling social roles. When a patient states, \"I am a good mother,\" it indicates a positive self-assessment of their role as a parent, suggesting healthy role performance. Lastly, low self-esteem, characterized by feelings of worthlessness or inadequacy, is illustrated by a patient's declaration, \"I am good for nothing.\" This reflects a negative self-evaluation and diminished sense of self-worth. By recognizing and interpreting these assessment findings, nurses can address psychosocial issues effectively, promoting holistic patient care and psychosocial integrity.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss evidence-based practice applicable for identity confusion, disturbed body image, low self-esteem, and role conflict.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      }
    ],
    "chapter34": [
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a 15 year old who in the past 6 months has had multiple male and female sexual partners. Which response by the nurse will be most effective?",
        "options": [
          "“Sexually transmitted infections and unwanted pregnancy are a real risk. Let’s discuss what you think is the best method for protecting yourself.”",
          "“Having sexual interaction with both males and females places you at higher risk for STIs. To protect yourself, you need to decide which orientation you are.”",
          "“Your current friends are leading you to make poor choices. You should find new friends to hang out with.”",
          "“I think it’s best to notify your parents. They know what’s best for you and can help make sure you practice safe sex.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Sexually transmitted infections and unwanted pregnancy are a real risk. Let’s discuss what you think is the best method for protecting yourself.”",
        "explanation": "Some adolescents participate in risky behaviors. The nurse should acknowledge this feeling to the patient and offer education and alternatives while giving the patient the autonomy to make his or her own decisions. Adolescents who engage in sexual risk behaviors experience negative health outcomes such as STIs and unintended pregnancy. In addition, the pattern of risk-taking behavior tends to be established and continue throughout life. The nurse should not force the patient to make a choice of orientation and should not pass judgment on a patient’s sexual orientation or social network; this would make the patient feel defensive and would eliminate the trust in the relationship. Involving parents is not the first line of action; parents should be notified only if the child is in a life or death situation.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify patient risk factors in the area of sexual health.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who expresses a desire to have an elective abortion. The nurse’s religious and ethical values are strongly opposed. How should the nurse best handle the situation?",
        "options": [
          "Attempt to educate the patient about the consequences of abortion.",
          "Refer the patient to a family planning center or another health professional.",
          "Continue to care for the patient, and limit conversation as much as possible.",
          "Inform the patient that, because of immoral issues, another nurse will have to care for her."
        ],
        "answer": "Refer the patient to a family planning center or another health professional.",
        "explanation": "The nurse must be aware of personal beliefs and values and is not required to participate in counseling or procedures that compromise those values. However, the patient is entitled to nonjudgmental care and should be referred to someone who can create a trusting environment. The nurse should not care for a patient if the quality of care could be jeopardized. The nurse should not attempt to push personal values onto a patient. The nurse also should not create tension by informing the patient that he or she does not have the same morals; this could cause the patient to feel guilty or defensive when receiving care from any health care professional.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify personal attitudes, beliefs, and biases related to sexuality.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which patient is most in need of a nurse’s referral to adoption services?",
        "options": [
          "A woman considering abortion for an unwanted pregnancy",
          "An infertile couple religiously opposed to artificial insemination",
          "A woman who suffered miscarriage during her first pregnancy",
          "An infertile couple who has been attempting conception for 3 months"
        ],
        "answer": "An infertile couple religiously opposed to artificial insemination",
        "explanation": "Adoption is an option for someone with infertility, especially if infertility treatments are unavailable owing to religious or financial constraints. A patient who wishes to have an elective abortion may be educated about all the possibilities, but the nurse should approach the patient in a nonjudgmental manner and should accept the patient’s decision. When a patient has recently miscarried, the nurse should assess the patient’s feelings about the loss and should address any concerns the patient may have about fertility. Infertility is the inability to conceive after 1 year of unprotected intercourse; therefore, talking about adoption after one miscarriage or after only 3 months of attempting conception would be too soon.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify health care providers and community resources available to help patients resolve sexual concerns that are outside the nurse’s",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who recently had unprotected sex with a partner who has been diagnosed with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). Which response by the nurse concerning initial medical care is best?",
        "options": [
          "“You should have your blood drawn today to see if you were infected.”",
          "“If you have the virus, you will have flulike symptoms in 6 months.”",
          "“Highly active antiretroviral therapy has been shown effective in slowing the disease process.”",
          "“I will set you up with a support group to help you cope with dying within the next 10 years.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Highly active antiretroviral therapy has been shown effective in slowing the disease process.”",
        "explanation": "Highly active retroviral therapy increases the survival time of a person with HIV or AIDS. HIV antibodies will not show up in blood work for 6 weeks to 3 months. The infection stage of HIV lasts for about a month after the virus is contracted; during that time, the patient may experience flulike symptoms. A support group may be beneficial for a patient who contracts HIV; however, it is unknown whether the patient has contracted HIV, and antiretroviral therapy has helped people live beyond the 10 years expected if HIV goes untreated.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify and describe nursing interventions to promote sexual health.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A 16-year-old male patient informs the nurse that he isn’t sure if he is homosexual because he is attracted to both genders. Which response by the nurse will help establish a trusting relationship?",
        "options": [
          "“Don’t worry. It’s just a phase you will grow out of.”",
          "“Those are abnormal impulses. You should seek therapy.”",
          "“At your age, it is normal to be curious about both genders.”",
          "“Having questions about sexuality is normal but if these sexual activities make you feel bad you should stop.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“At your age, it is normal to be curious about both genders.”",
        "explanation": "During adolescence, it is not unusual to have questions about sexuality. The patient will feel most comfortable discussing his sexual concerns further if the nurse establishes that it is normal to ask questions about sexuality. The nurse can then discuss in greater detail. Although it is normal for young adults to be curious about sexuality, the nurse should use caution in giving advice on taking sexual action. The nurse should promote safe sex practices. Telling the patient not to worry dismisses his concern. Telling the patient that he is abnormal might offend the patient and prevent him from establishing an open relationship.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe key concepts of sexual development across the life span.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a 35-year-old female patient who recently started taking antidepressants after repeated failed attempts at fertility treatment. The patient tells the nurse, “I feel happier, but my sex drive is gone.” Which nursing diagnosis has the highest priority?",
        "options": [
          "Sexual dysfunction",
          "Difficulty coping",
          "Risk for self-directed violence",
          "Deficient knowledge about contraception"
        ],
        "answer": "Sexual dysfunction",
        "explanation": "Antidepressants have adverse effects on sexual desire and response. The nurse should be sure to educate the patient on the potential for these side effects and how to correct for them, for example, using lubricant to ease discomfort. The patient has taken steps toward effective coping by seeking therapy. The patient has not expressed a reason for the nurse to be concerned about contraceptives. The nurse should always assess for concerns about violence in a patient’s life. Although some antidepressants have been related to self-directed violence, this patient focus is on becoming pregnant (fertility treatments) but sex drive is gone.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Formulate appropriate nursing diagnoses for patients with alterations in sexuality.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is using the PLISSIT model when caring for a patient with dyspareunia from diminished vaginal secretions. The nurse suggests using water-soluble lubricants. Which component of PLISSIT is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "P",
          "LI",
          "SS",
          "IT"
        ],
        "answer": "SS",
        "explanation": "The nurse is using the specific suggestions (SS). The PLISSIT model is as follows: Permission to discuss sexuality issues Limited Information related to sexual health problems being experienced Specific Suggestions—only when the nurse is clear about the problem Intensive Therapy—referral to professional with advanced training if necessary",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify and describe nursing interventions to promote sexual health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient who has had several sexual partners in the past month expresses a desire to use a barrier contraceptive that will protect against pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections (STIs). Which contraceptive method should the nurse recommend?",
        "options": [
          "Condom",
          "Diaphragm",
          "Spermicide",
          "Oral contraceptive"
        ],
        "answer": "Condom",
        "explanation": "Condoms are both a contraceptive and a barrier against sexually transmitted infections (STIs), pregnancy, and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV); proper use will greatly reduce the risk. Spermicides and diaphragms protect against pregnancy; however, they are not a barrier since they do not prevent bodily fluids from coming in contact with the patient during sexual intercourse. Oral contraceptives will only be effective in preventing pregnancy.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Use critical thinking skills when helping patients meet their sexual needs.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A woman who has been in a monogamous relationship for the past 6 months presents to clinic with herpes on her labia. The patient is distraught because her partner must have cheated on her. Which response by the nurse is most effective in establishing an open rapport with a patient?",
        "options": [
          "Share a story.",
          "Inform the patient that all encounters are confidential.",
          "Encourage the patient to break up with her partner for cheating.",
          "Tell the patient that she must be honest about every sexual experience she has had."
        ],
        "answer": "Inform the patient that all encounters are confidential.",
        "explanation": "If open communication is to be established with the patient, the patient must know that she can trust health care team members. By telling the patient that all encounters are confidential, the nurse establishes trust. Sharing a story brings the focus to the nurse, inhibiting open rapport. The nurse does not tell the patient what to do, because that should be the patient’s decision. Forcing the patient to confide by sharing every sexual encounter may hinder a trusting relationship.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess a patient’s sexuality.",
        "top": "Communication and Documentation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is preparing a community class about sexually transmitted infections. Which primary group will the nurse focus on for this class?",
        "options": [
          "Bisexual women",
          "Men who have sex with men",
          "Youths between the ages of 24 and 27",
          "Pregnant women and their partners"
        ],
        "answer": "Men who have sex with men",
        "explanation": "About 20 million people in the United States are diagnosed with an STI each year, with the highest incidence occurring in men who have sex with men, bisexual men, and youths between the ages of 15 and 24. While bisexual women, youths between the ages of 24 and 27, and pregnant women and their partners are important, they are not the primary groups affected by STIs.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the nurse’s role in maintaining or enhancing a patient’s sexual health.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is leading a seminar about menopause and age-related changes. Which response from a group member indicates the nurse needs to follow up?",
        "options": [
          "“Hormones of sexual regulation decrease with aging.”",
          "“Orgasms are no longer achievable after menopause.”",
          "“The excitement phase is prolonged as we age.”",
          "“As men age, their erection may be less firm.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Orgasms are no longer achievable after menopause.”",
        "explanation": "Believing that orgasms are no long achievable requires follow-up to correct this misconception. Orgasms are achievable at any age; however, it may take longer with aging. All other statements indicate that the patient does have an understanding of age-related changes and needs no follow-up. Both genders experience a reduced availability of sex hormones. The excitement phase prolongs in both men and women. Men often have erections that are less firm and shorter acting.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Evaluate patient outcomes related to sexual health needs.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient who had a colostomy placed 1 month ago is feeling depressed and does not want to participate in sexual activities anymore. The patient is afraid that the partner does not want sex. The patient is afraid the ostomy is physically unattractive. Which initial nursing intervention will be most effective in helping this patient resume sexual activity?",
        "options": [
          "Inform the patient about a support group for people with colostomies.",
          "Reassure the patient that lots of people resume sex the same week the colostomy is placed.",
          "Teach the patient about intimate activities that can be done to incorporate the ostomy.",
          "Discuss ways to adapt to new body image so the patient will be comfortable in resuming intimacy."
        ],
        "answer": "Discuss ways to adapt to new body image so the patient will be comfortable in resuming intimacy.",
        "explanation": "The nurse should first address the patient’s need to be comfortable with his or her own body image; once the patient’s issues related to body image are resolved, intimacy may follow. Reassuring the patient that others manage to have sexual intercourse with an ostomy may help to decrease anxiety but may have the unintended effect of making the patient feel abnormal because he or she has not yet resumed sexual activity. Support groups may be helpful for the patient, but this is not the most effective initial intervention a nurse can provide; this may be helpful later. The patient is worried about the ostomy; incorporating it into intimate activities is insensitive and can even be damaging to the stoma.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify and describe nursing interventions to promote sexual health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A mother brings her 12-year-old daughter into a clinic and asks about getting a human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine that day. Which information will the nurse share with the mother and daughter about the HPV vaccine?",
        "options": [
          "Protects against human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).",
          "Protects against cervical cancer.",
          "Protects against chlamydia.",
          "Protects against pregnancy."
        ],
        "answer": "Protects against cervical cancer.",
        "explanation": "The HPV vaccine is effective against the four most common types of HPVs that can cause cervical cancer. It is not effective against HIV, chlamydia, or pregnancy.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the nurse’s role in maintaining or enhancing a patient’s sexual health.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A parent asks about the human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine. Which information will the nurse include in the teaching session?",
        "options": [
          "It is recommended for girls 6 to 9 years old.",
          "It is recommended for females ages 11 to 26.",
          "It is recommended that booster injections be given.",
          "It is recommended to receive four required injections."
        ],
        "answer": "It is recommended for females ages 11 to 26.",
        "explanation": "The vaccine is safe for girls as young as 9 years old and is recommended for females ages 11 to 26 if they have not already completed the three required injections. Booster doses currently are not recommended. The vaccine is most effective if administered before sexual activity or exposure.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify and describe nursing interventions to promote sexual health.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nursing student is providing education to a group of older adults who are in an independent living retirement village. Which statement made by the nursing student requires the nurse to intervene?",
        "options": [
          "“Avoiding alcohol use will enhance your sexual functioning.”",
          "“You need to tell your partner how you feel about sex and any fears you may have.”",
          "“You do not need to worry about getting a sexually transmitted infection at this point in your life.”",
          "“Using pillows and taking pain medication if needed before having sexual intercourse often help alleviate pain and improve sexual functioning.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“You do not need to worry about getting a sexually transmitted infection at this point in your life.”",
        "explanation": "Research indicates many older adults are more sexuality active than previously thought and engage in high-risk sexual encounters, resulting in a steady increase HIV and STI rates over the past 12 years. Therefore, the nurse needs to intervene when the student tells the older adults that they are not at risk for developing an STI. Avoiding the use of alcohol; using pillows; taking pain medications before having intercourse if needed; and communicating thoughts, fears, and feelings about sex all enhance sexual functioning.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe key concepts of sexual development across the life span.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is interviewing a woman who uses a diaphragm. Which information from the patient will require the nurse to follow up?",
        "options": [
          "“I have lost 12 lb on this diet.”",
          "“I use the diaphragm to prevent pregnancy.”",
          "“I use a contraceptive cream with my diaphragm.”",
          "“I know this provides a barrier over the cervical opening.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“I have lost 12 lb on this diet.”",
        "explanation": "The woman needs to be refitted after a significant change in weight (10-lb gain or loss) or pregnancy. The diaphragm is a round, rubber dome that has a flexible spring around the edge. It is used with a contraceptive cream or jelly and is inserted in the vagina, so it provides a contraceptive barrier over the cervical opening.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify and describe nursing interventions to promote sexual health.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is conducting a sexual assessment. Which question is appropriate for the nurse to ask?",
        "options": [
          "Have you noticed any changes in the way you feel about yourself?",
          "What is your favorite sex position with men and with women?",
          "Do you think your partner is attractive?",
          "Why do you like men over women?"
        ],
        "answer": "Have you noticed any changes in the way you feel about yourself?",
        "explanation": "Asking about any changes in the way you feel about yourself is an appropriate question to ask during a sexual assessment. Asking about favorite sex position with men and/or women is inappropriate and invasive. The assessment needs to focus on the patient, not the partner. Asking “why” questions is nontherapeutic and is judgmental in this scenario.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess a patient’s sexuality.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A 15-year-old patient is concerned because her mother wants her to receive the human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccination, but the patient is unsure if she wants it. Which response by the nurse is most therapeutic?",
        "options": [
          "Ask the patient what concerns she may have about the vaccination.",
          "Inquire about how many sexual partners she has had in the past year.",
          "Remind her that her mother knows best and that she should respect her parents’ wishes.",
          "Promote the importance of the vaccine and recommend that the patient get the vaccine as soon as possible."
        ],
        "answer": "Ask the patient what concerns she may have about the vaccination.",
        "explanation": "The nurse should encourage health promotion behaviors but first must consider the autonomy of the patient and assess the patient for more data. The nurse should value the input of the patient in making a decision and assess what the patient is thinking to address any concerns the patient may have. The HPV vaccine is a preventative treatment; whether or not the patient is sexually active (asking about how many sexual partners) does not matter in this case. The nurse should not make assumptions about a patient’s home life (mother knows best); instead, the nurse should ask questions while establishing a therapeutic relationship. Recommending the patient get the vaccine as soon as possible is in violation of the patient’s rights.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify and describe nursing interventions to promote sexual health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is reviewing a patient’s history. Which priority finding will alert the nurse to assess the patient for possible sexual dysfunction?",
        "options": [
          "Takes vacations out of the country.",
          "Takes an anxiolytic medication.",
          "Takes exercise classes.",
          "Takes afternoon naps."
        ],
        "answer": "Takes an anxiolytic medication.",
        "explanation": "Medications that can affect sexual functioning include antihypertensive, antipsychotics, antidepressants, and antianxiety (anxiolytic). Taking vacations out of the country, exercise classes, and afternoon naps are not as priority for sexual functioning as medications.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify causes of sexual dysfunction.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assessing a child for sexual abuse. Which assessment findings will the nurse expect?",
        "options": [
          "Physical aggression and sleep disturbances",
          "A few good friends and no drug usage",
          "Panic attacks and anorexia",
          "Anxiety and depression"
        ],
        "answer": "Physical aggression and sleep disturbances",
        "explanation": "Behavioral signs of sexual abuse in a child include physical aggression, sleep disturbance, poor peer relationships, and substance abuse. Panic attacks, anorexia, anxiety, and depression are behavioral signs for adults.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess a patient’s sexuality.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is teaching a patient how to use a condom. Which instructions will the nurse provide?",
        "options": [
          "Store in a warm lit space.",
          "Use massage oils for lubrication.",
          "Rinse and reuse the condom if needed.",
          "Hold onto the condom when pulling out."
        ],
        "answer": "Hold onto the condom when pulling out.",
        "explanation": "Teach patients to pull out right after ejaculating and to hold onto the condom when pulling out. Store condoms in a cool, dry place away from sunlight. Instruct patient to never reuse a condom or use a damaged condom. Instruct patient to only use water-based lubricants (e.g., K-Y jelly) to prevent the condom from breaking; do not use petroleum jelly, massage oils, body lotions, or cooking oil.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the nurse’s role in maintaining or enhancing a patient’s sexual health.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient with dyspareunia. In which order will the nurse provide care, starting with the first step? 1. Determine which signs and symptoms of dyspareunia the patient has. 2. Mutually decide upon goals and objectives for dyspareunia. 3. Ask the patient if the dyspareunia is improving. 4. Develop a nursing diagnosis for the patient. 5. Use resources to help resolve the problem.",
        "options": [
          "5, 3, 1, 4, 2",
          "1, 4, 2, 5, 3",
          "3, 1, 4, 2, 5",
          "4, 2, 5, 3, 1"
        ],
        "answer": "1, 4, 2, 5, 3",
        "explanation": "The nurse should use the nursing process when caring for patients with sexual dysfunction. Determine signs and symptoms (assessment); develop a nursing diagnosis (diagnosis); mutually decide upon goals (planning); use resources to help resolve the problem (implementation); and ask if the dyspareunia is improving (evaluation).",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Use critical thinking skills when helping patients meet their sexual needs.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "An older couple expresses concern because they are easily fatigued during sexual intercourse and cannot reach climax. Which strategies to increase sexual stamina will the nurse offer? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Plan sexual activity around a time when the couple feels rested.",
          "Encourage intimate touching, such as hugging and kissing.",
          "Use extra lubrication to decrease discomfort.",
          "Take pain medication before intercourse.",
          "Avoid alcohol and tobacco.",
          "Eat well-balanced meals."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Plan sexual activity around a time when the couple feels rested.",
          "Avoid alcohol and tobacco.",
          "Eat well-balanced meals."
        ],
        "explanation": "Alcohol, tobacco, and certain medications (such as narcotics for pain) may cause drowsiness and fatigue and negatively affect sexual stamina. Eating well-balanced meals can help to increase energy levels. Planning sexual activity when the couple is well rested will help them not get fatigued as quickly. Encouraging intimate touching may help increase libido but not energy levels. Extra lubrication and taking pain medications may ease the discomfort of sexual intercourse but are not appropriate interventions for fatigue.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Use critical thinking skills when helping patients meet their sexual needs.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      }
    ],
    "chapter35": [
      {
        "question": "A co-worker asks the nurse to explain spirituality. What is the nurse’s best response?",
        "options": [
          "It has a minor effect on health.",
          "It is awareness of one’s inner self.",
          "It is not as essential as physical needs.",
          "It refers to fire or giving of life to a person."
        ],
        "answer": "It is awareness of one’s inner self.",
        "explanation": "Spirituality is often defined as an awareness of one’s inner self and a sense of connection to a higher being, to nature, or to some purpose greater than oneself. Spirituality is an important factor that helps individuals achieve the balance needed to maintain health and well-being and to cope with illness. Florence Nightingale believed that spirituality was a force that provided energy needed to promote a healthy hospital environment and that caring for a person’s spiritual needs was just as essential as caring for his or her physical needs. The word spirituality comes from the Latin word spiritus, which refers to breath or wind. The spirit gives life to a person.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the influence of spirituality on patients’ health practices.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who is professes to being an agnostic. Which information should the nurse consider when planning care for this patient belief system?",
        "options": [
          "The patient is devoid of spirituality.",
          "Is certain there is no such entity as God.",
          "Believes there is no known ultimate reality.",
          "Finds no meaning through relationship with others."
        ],
        "answer": "Believes there is no known ultimate reality.",
        "explanation": "Some people do not believe in the existence of God (atheist), or they believe that there is no known ultimate reality (agnostic). Nonetheless, spirituality is important regardless of a person’s religious beliefs. Agnostics discover meaning in what they do or how they live because they find no ultimate meaning for the way things are. They believe that people bring meaning to what they do.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the influence of spirituality on patients’ health practices.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for an Islamic patient who wants a snack. Offering sandwich is most appropriate?",
        "options": [
          "Ham",
          "Beef",
          "Kosher",
          "Bacon"
        ],
        "answer": "Beef",
        "explanation": "Islam religion does allow beef. Islam does not allow pork or alcohol. Ham and bacon are pork. Kosher is allowed for Judaism.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing interventions designed to promote a patient’s spiritual health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient how to meditate. Which behavior presented by the patient indicates effective learning?",
        "options": [
          "Lying on the floor",
          "Breathing quickly",
          "Focusing on an particular image",
          "Engaging for 10 minutes every day"
        ],
        "answer": "Focusing on an particular image",
        "explanation": "The steps of meditation include sitting in a comfortable position with the back straight; breathe slowly; and focus on a sound, prayer, or image. Meditation should occur for 10 to 20 minutes twice a day.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing interventions designed to promote a patient’s spiritual health.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is admitting a patient to the hospital. The patient is a very spiritual person but does not practice any specific religion. How will the nurse interpret this finding?",
        "options": [
          "This indicates a strong religious affiliation.",
          "This statement is contradictory.",
          "This statement is reasonable.",
          "This indicates a lack of hope."
        ],
        "answer": "This statement is reasonable.",
        "explanation": "The patient’s statement is reasonable and is not contradictory. Many people tend to use the terms spirituality and religion interchangeably. Although closely associated, these terms are not synonymous. Religious practices encompass spirituality, but spirituality does not need to include religious practice. When a person has the attitude of something to live for and look forward to, hope is present.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast the concepts of religion and spirituality.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which patient comment should the nurse identify as a demonstration of faith?",
        "options": [
          "I go to church every Sunday.",
          "I believe there is life after death.",
          "I have something to look forward to each day.",
          "I get a feeling of awe when looking at the sunset."
        ],
        "answer": "I believe there is life after death.",
        "explanation": "Faith allows people to have firm beliefs despite lack of physical evidence (life after death). Religion refers to the system of organized beliefs and worship that a person practices to outwardly express spirituality (go to church). When a person has the attitude of something to live for and look forward to, hope is present (look forward to each day). Self-transcendence is the belief that there is a force outside of and greater than the person (awe when looking at a sunset).",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe the relationship among faith, hope, and spiritual well-being.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a Roman Catholic patient. Which action will the nurse plan time for?",
        "options": [
          "Practice the Five Pillars.",
          "Practice Blessingway.",
          "Avoiding meat on Fridays.",
          "The purity rituals."
        ],
        "answer": "The purity rituals.",
        "explanation": "Fasting on Fridays is practiced by some Roman Catholics. Hindus practice prayer and purity rituals. Blessingway is a practice of the Navajos that attempts to remove ill health by means of stories, songs, rituals, prayers, symbols, and sand paintings. Islams must be able to practice the Five Pillars of Islam.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing interventions designed to promote a patient’s spiritual health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with a chronic illness who is having conflicts with beliefs. Which health care team member will the nurse ask to see this patient?",
        "options": [
          "The clergy",
          "A psychiatrist",
          "A social worker",
          "An occupational therapist"
        ],
        "answer": "The clergy",
        "explanation": "Other important resources to patients are spiritual advisors and members of the clergy. Spiritual care helps people identify meaning and purpose in life, look beyond the present, and maintain personal relationships, as well as a relationship with a higher being or life force. A psychiatrist is for emotional health. A social worker focuses on social, financial, and community resources. An occupational therapist provides care with vocational issues and functioning within physical limitations.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Explain the importance of establishing caring relationships with patients to provide spiritual care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse caring for a terminally ill patient sits down and lightly touches the patient’s hand. Which technique is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "“Doing for”",
          "Establishing presence",
          "Offering transcendence",
          "Providing health promotion"
        ],
        "answer": "Establishing presence",
        "explanation": "Establishing presence by sitting with a patient to attentively listen to his or her feelings and situation, talking with the patient, crying with the patient, and simply offering time are powerful spiritual care approaches. Benner explains that presence involves “being with” a patient versus “doing for” a patient. Transcendence is the belief that a force outside of and greater than the person exists beyond the material world. In settings where health promotion activities occur, patients often need information, counseling, and guidance to make the necessary choices to remain healthy.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify approaches for establishing presence with patients.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse and the patient have the same religious affiliation. Which action will the nurse take to support the patient spiritually?",
        "options": [
          "Must use a formal assessment tool to determine patient’s beliefs.",
          "Assume that both have the same spiritual beliefs.",
          "Do not impose personal values on the patient.",
          "Skip the spiritual belief assessment."
        ],
        "answer": "Do not impose personal values on the patient.",
        "explanation": "It is important not to impose personal value systems on the patient. This is particularly true when the patient’s values and beliefs are similar to those of the nurse because it then becomes very easy to make false assumptions. It is not a must to use a formal assessment tool when assessing a patient’s beliefs. It is important to conduct the spiritual belief assessment; conducting an assessment is therapeutic because it expresses a level of caring and support.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Explain the importance of establishing caring relationships with patients to provide spiritual care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse makes a connection with the patient when providing spiritual care. Which type of connectedness did the nurse experience?",
        "options": [
          "Intrapersonal",
          "Interpersonal",
          "Transpersonal",
          "Multipersonal"
        ],
        "answer": "Interpersonal",
        "explanation": "Interpersonal means connected with others and the environment. Intrapersonal means connected within oneself. Transpersonal means connected with God or an unseen higher power. There is no such term as multipersonal for connectedness.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the importance of establishing caring relationships with patients to provide spiritual care.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Psychosocial"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is admitted with a diagnosis of chronic anxiety. Which action is most appropriate for the nurse to take when providing holistic care?",
        "options": [
          "Focusing on finding quick remedies for the anxiety",
          "Realizing that the patient’s only goal is relief of the anxiety",
          "Looking at how worry influences the patient’s ability to function",
          "Helping the patient realize that there is little hope of relief from anxiety"
        ],
        "answer": "Looking at how worry influences the patient’s ability to function",
        "explanation": "Do not just look at the patient’s anxiety as a problem to solve with quick remedies, but rather look at how the anxiety influences the patient’s ability to function and achieve goals established in life (not just anxiety relief). Mobilizing the patient’s hope is central to a healing relationship.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess a patient’s spirituality.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "In caring for the patient’s spiritual needs, the nurse asks 20 questions to assess the patient’s relationship with God and a sense of life purpose and satisfaction. Which method is the nurse using?",
        "options": [
          "The spiritual well-being scale",
          "The FICA assessment tool",
          "Belief tool",
          "Hope scale"
        ],
        "answer": "The spiritual well-being scale",
        "explanation": "The spiritual well-being scale (SWB) has 20 questions that assess a patient’s relationship with God and his or her sense of life purpose and life satisfaction. The FICA assessment tool evaluates spirituality and is closely correlated to quality of life. This does not describe belief or hope.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Assess a patient’s spirituality.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A male patient in stable condition is in the intensive care unit (ICU) and is asking to see his spouse and two daughters. What should the nurse be prepared to plan for?",
        "options": [
          "5 to 10 minutes for the family visit",
          "Complying with the patient’s request",
          "Arranging for the two daughters to visit, then the wife",
          "Asking the family to decide which two persons will visit"
        ],
        "answer": "Complying with the patient’s request",
        "explanation": "Use of support systems is important in any health care setting. Allowing the family to visit is appropriate since the patient is in stable condition. When patients depend on family and friends for support, encourage them to visit the patient. As long as no interference with active patient care is involved, there is no reason to limit visitation. Limiting the visit is not necessary since the patient is stable. Breaking the family apart is not needed; the patient is stable and can see all three at once.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing interventions designed to promote a patient’s spiritual health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has been diagnosed with a terminal illness. The patient states, “I just don’t feel like going to work. I have no energy, and I can’t eat or sleep.” The patient shows no interest in taking part in the care by saying, “What’s the use?” Which response by the nurse is best?",
        "options": [
          "It sounds like you have lost hope.",
          "It sounds like you have lost energy.",
          "It sounds like you have lost your appetite.",
          "It sounds like you have lost the ability to sleep."
        ],
        "answer": "It sounds like you have lost hope.",
        "explanation": "All of the patient’s description are describing a loss of hope. While losses of energy, appetite, and sleep are indicated, they only address a part of patient’s problems. A loss of hope encompasses the holistic view of the patient.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Explain the importance of establishing caring relationships with patients to provide spiritual care.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Psychosocial"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is having a difficult time dealing with an AIDS diagnosis. The patient states, “It’s not fair. I’m totally isolated from God and my family because of this. Even my father hates me for this. He won’t even speak to me.” What should the nurse do?",
        "options": [
          "Tell the patient to move on and focus on getting better.",
          "Use therapeutic communication to establish trust and caring.",
          "Assure the patient that the father will accept this situation soon.",
          "Point out that the patient has no control and that he or she must face the consequences."
        ],
        "answer": "Use therapeutic communication to establish trust and caring.",
        "explanation": "Application of therapeutic communication principles and caring helps you establish therapeutic trust with patients. The nurse should not offer false hope (father will accept the situation soon). The nurse should help the patient maintain feelings of control, not no control. The nurse should encourage renewing relationships if possible and establishing connections with self, significant others, and God.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing interventions designed to promote a patient’s spiritual health.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a group of patients. Which patient will the nurse see first?",
        "options": [
          "A patient saying that God has left and there is no reason for living",
          "A patient refusing treatment on the Sabbath",
          "A patient having a folk healer in the room",
          "A patient praying to Allah"
        ],
        "answer": "A patient saying that God has left and there is no reason for living",
        "explanation": "A patient saying that God has left and there is no reason for living must be seen first for safety reasons. It must be determined by the nurse if the patient is planning suicide or is just angry and frustrated. A patient refusing treatment on the Sabbath is within that patient’s right and doesn’t need to be seen first. A patient with a folk healer is within the patient’s right and does not need to be seen first. A patient praying to Allah is within the patient’s right and does not need to be seen first.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Assess a patient’s spirituality.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is providing spiritual care to patients. Which action is essential for the nurse to take?",
        "options": [
          "Knowing one’s own personal beliefs",
          "Learning about other religions",
          "Visit churches, temples, mosques, or synagogues",
          "Travel to other areas that do not have the same beliefs"
        ],
        "answer": "Knowing one’s own personal beliefs",
        "explanation": "Because each person has a unique spirituality, you need to know your own beliefs, so you are able to care for each patient without bias. While learning about religions, visiting other religious areas of worship, and traveling to areas that do not have the same beliefs are beneficial, they are not essential.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the importance of establishing caring relationships with patients to provide spiritual care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is evaluating a patient’s spiritual care. Which areas will the nurse include in the evaluation process? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Review the patient’s view of the purpose in life.",
          "Ask whether the patient’s expectations were met.",
          "Discuss with family and friends the patient’s connectedness.",
          "Review the patient’s self-perception regarding spiritual health.",
          "Impress on the patient that spiritual health is permanent once obtained."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Review the patient’s view of the purpose in life.",
          "Ask whether the patient’s expectations were met.",
          "Discuss with family and friends the patient’s connectedness.",
          "Review the patient’s self-perception regarding spiritual health."
        ],
        "explanation": "In evaluating care include a review of the patient’s self-perception regarding spiritual health, the patient’s view of his or her purpose in life, discussion with the family and friends about connectedness, and determining whether the patient’s expectations were met. Attainment of spiritual health is a lifelong goal; it is not permanent once obtained.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Evaluate patient outcomes related to spiritual health.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Spiritual distress has been identified in a patient who has been diagnosed with a chronic illness. Which interventions will the nurse add to the care plan? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Being supportive of a patient’s wish to pray",
          "Encouraging time with the support group",
          "Arranging for a clergy member to visit the patient",
          "Developing activities to heal body, mind, and spirit",
          "Teaching relaxation, guided imagery, and meditation"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Being supportive of a patient’s wish to pray",
          "Developing activities to heal body, mind, and spirit",
          "Teaching relaxation, guided imagery, and meditation"
        ],
        "explanation": "Interventions that are appropriate for spiritual distress include: (1) helping the patient develop/identify activities to heal body, mind, and spirit; (2) supporting the patient’s desire to pray; (3) encourage attendance with an appropriate support group; and (4) teaching relaxation, guided imagery, and medication. Clergy consults should be made only with the patient’s permission.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing interventions designed to promote a patient’s spiritual health.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is providing spiritual care to a group of patients. Match the group to their belief.",
        "matching": [
          "Hinduism",
          "Buddhism",
          "Islam",
          "Judaism",
          "Mormonism"
        ],
        "options": [
          "Avoid caffeine.",
          "Says prayers five times a day.",
          "Shellfish is not eaten.",
          "Often follow a vegetarian diet.",
          "Generally fast on religious Holy days."
        ],
        "answer": {
          "Hinduism": "Often follow a vegetarian diet.",
          "Buddhism": "Generally fast on religious Holy days.",
          "Islam": "Says prayers five times a day.",
          "Judaism": "Shellfish is not eaten.",
          "Mormonism": "Avoid caffeine."
        },
        "explanation": "",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the influence of spirituality on patients’ health practices.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      }
    ],
    "chapter36": [
      {
        "question": "A nurse encounters a family who experienced the death of their adult child last year. The parents are talking about the upcoming anniversary of their child’s death. The nurse spends time with them discussing their child’s life and death. Which nursing principle does the nurse’s action best demonstrate?",
        "options": [
          "Facilitation of normal mourning",
          "Pain-management technique",
          "Grief evaluation",
          "Palliative care"
        ],
        "answer": "Facilitation of normal mourning",
        "explanation": "Anniversary reactions can reopen grief processes. A nurse should openly acknowledge the loss and talk about the common renewal of grief feeling around the anniversary of the individual’s death; this facilitates normal mourning. The nurse is not attempting to alleviate a physical pain. The actions are of open communication, not evaluation. Palliative care refers to comfort measures for symptom relief.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify the nurse’s role when caring for patients who are experiencing loss, grief, or death.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient diagnosed with terminal cancer asks the nurse what the criteria are for hospice care. Which information should the nurse share with the patient?",
        "options": [
          "It is for those needing assistance with pain management.",
          "It is for those having a terminal illness, such as cancer.",
          "It is for those with completion of an advance directive.",
          "It is for those expected to live less than 6 months."
        ],
        "answer": "It is for those expected to live less than 6 months.",
        "explanation": "Patients accepted into a hospice program usually have less than 6 months to live. Patients with a terminal illness are not eligible until that point. Palliative care provides assistance with pain management when a patient is not eligible for hospice care. An advance directive can be completed by any person, even those who are healthy.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the criteria for hospice care.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A terminally ill patient is experiencing constipation secondary to pain medication. Which is the best method for the nurse to improve the patient’s constipation problem?",
        "options": [
          "Contact the health care provider to discontinue pain medication.",
          "Administer enemas twice daily for 7 days.",
          "Massage the patient’s abdomen.",
          "Use a laxative."
        ],
        "answer": "Use a laxative.",
        "explanation": "Opioid medication is known to slow peristalsis, which places the patient at high risk for constipation. Laxatives are indicated for opioid-induced constipation. Massaging the patient’s abdomen may cause further discomfort. Discontinuing pain medication is inappropriate for a terminally ill patient. Enema administration twice a day is not the best step in the treatment of opioid-induced constipation.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe interventions for symptom management in patients at the end of life.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "A severely depressed patient cannot state any positive attributes to life. The nurse patiently sits with this patient and assists the patient to identify several activities the patient is actually looking forward to in life. Which spiritual concept is the nurse trying to promote?",
        "options": [
          "Time management",
          "Reminiscence",
          "Hope",
          "Faith"
        ],
        "answer": "Hope",
        "explanation": "Hope gives a person the ability to see life as enduring or having meaning or purpose. The nurse’s actions do not address time management, reminiscence, or faith. Time management is organizing and prioritizing activities to be completed in a timely manner. Reminiscence is the relationship by mentally or verbally anecdotally relieving and remembering the person and past experiences. Faith is belief in a higher power.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Develop a nursing care plan for a patient and family experiencing loss and grief.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "In preparation for the eventual death of a hospice patient, the nurse organizes a meeting of all hospice caregivers. A plan of care to be followed when this patient dies is prepared. Which information will be included in the plan?",
        "options": [
          "Avoid discussing the death with immediate family members.",
          "Discuss expectations of normal grieving with the family and friends.",
          "Encourage the patient’s family and friends to verbally express their needs.",
          "Assure family members they will not be expected to assist with postmortem care."
        ],
        "answer": "Encourage the patient’s family and friends to verbally express their needs.",
        "explanation": "Families and friends should be encouraged to express both their concerns and needs so the staff can effectively care for them. Avoiding the discussion of death-related issues, reinforcing expected grieving behaviors and in any way limiting contact with the patient during or after the death process is inappropriate.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Develop a nursing care plan for a patient and family experiencing loss and grief.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Family members gather in the emergency department after learning that a family member was involved in a motor vehicle accident. After learning of the family member’s unexpected death, the surviving family members begin to cry and scream in despair. Which phase does the nurse determine the family is in according to the Attachment Theory?",
        "options": [
          "Numbing",
          "Reorganization",
          "Yearning and searching",
          "Disorganization and despair"
        ],
        "answer": "Yearning and searching",
        "explanation": "Yearning and searching characterize the second bereavement phase in the Attachment Theory. Emotional outbursts of tearful sobbing and acute distress are common in this phase. During the numbing phase, the family is protected from the full impact of the loss. During disorganization and despair, the reason why the loss occurred is constantly examined. Reorganization is the last stage of the Attachment Theory in which the person accepts the change and builds new relationships.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss grief theories.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nursing assistive personnel (NAP) is caring for a dying patient. Which action by the NAP will cause the nurse to intervene?",
        "options": [
          "Elevating head of bed",
          "Making the patient eat",
          "Giving mouth care every 2 to 4 hours",
          "Keeping skin clean, dry, and moisturized"
        ],
        "answer": "Making the patient eat",
        "explanation": "Patients should never be forced to eat so the nurse will intervene to correct this inappropriate behavior. Eating in the last days of life often causes the patient pain and discomfort. Equally, as the body is shutting down the nutrients in food are not able to be absorbed. Therefore, forcing patients to eat serves no beneficial purpose for the patient. All the rest are correct and do not need the nurse to intervene. Elevating the head of the bed is appropriate and will promote ease of breathing and lung expansion and facilitate postural drainage. Giving mouth care will protect membranes if dehydrated, nauseated, or vomiting. Keeping skin clean, dry, and moisturized will decrease skin discomfort and prevent skin breakdown.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify ways to collaborate with family members and the interdisciplinary team to provide palliative care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "An Orthodox Jewish rabbi has been pronounced dead. The nursing assistive personnel respectfully ask family members to leave the room and go home as postmortem care is provided. Which statement from the supervising nurse is best?",
        "options": [
          "“I should have called a male colleague to handle the body.”",
          "“Family members stay with the body as part of the mourning ritual.”",
          "“I wish they would go home because we have work to do here.”",
          "“Family will quietly leave after praying and touching the rabbi’s head.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Family members stay with the body as part of the mourning ritual.”",
        "explanation": "Jewish culture calls for family members or religious officials to stay with the body until the time of burial. A male provider is unnecessary. Requesting or expecting the family to go home is not providing culturally sensitive care. Hindus and Muslims usually have persons of the same gender handle the body after death. Buddhists often say prayers while touching and standing at the head of the deceased.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe care of the body after death.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A palliative team is caring for a dying patient in severe pain. Which action is the priority?",
        "options": [
          "Provide postmortem care for the patient.",
          "Support the patient’s nurse in grieving.",
          "Teach the patient the stages of grief.",
          "Enhance the patient’s quality of life."
        ],
        "answer": "Enhance the patient’s quality of life.",
        "explanation": "The primary goal of palliative care is to help patients and families achieve the best quality of life. Providing support for the patient’s nurse is not the primary obligation when the patient is experiencing severe pain. Not all collaborative team members on the palliative team would be able to provide postmortem care, as is the case for nutritionists, social workers, and pharmacists. Teaching about stages of grief should not be the focus when severe pain is present.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify ways to collaborate with family members and the interdisciplinary team to provide palliative care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A veteran is hospitalized after surgical amputation of both lower extremities owing to injuries sustained during military service. Which type of loss will the nurse focus the plan of care on for this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Perceived loss",
          "Situational loss",
          "Maturational loss",
          "Uncomplicated loss"
        ],
        "answer": "Situational loss",
        "explanation": "Loss of a body part from injury is a situational loss. Maturational losses occur as part of normal life transitions across the life span. A perceived loss is uniquely defined by the person experiencing the loss and is less obvious to other people. Uncomplicated loss is not a type of loss; it is a description of normal grief.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the types of loss experienced throughout life.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "“I know it seems strange, but I feel guilty being pregnant after the death of my son last year,” said a woman during her routine obstetrical examination. The nurse spends extra time with this woman, helping her realize bonding with this unborn child will not mean she is replacing the one who died. Which nursing technique does this demonstrate?",
        "options": [
          "Providing curative therapy",
          "Promoting spirituality",
          "Facilitating mourning",
          "Eradicating grief"
        ],
        "answer": "Facilitating mourning",
        "explanation": "The nurse facilitates mourning in family members who are still surviving. By acknowledging the pregnant woman’s emotions, the nurse helps the mother bond with her fetus and recognizes the emotions that still exist for the deceased child. The nurse is not attempting to help the patient eradicate grief, which would be unrealistic. Curative therapy (curing a disease) and spiritual promotion (belief in a higher power or in the meaning of life) are not addressed by the nurse’s statement.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Develop a nursing care plan for a patient and family experiencing loss and grief.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has had two family members die during the past 2 days. Which coping strategy is most appropriate for the nurse to suggest to the patient?",
        "options": [
          "Writing in a journal",
          "Drinking a little alcohol to go to sleep",
          "Exercising vigorously rather than sleeping",
          "Avoiding talking about the deaths with friends"
        ],
        "answer": "Writing in a journal",
        "explanation": "Coping strategies may be healthy and effective like talking, journaling, and sharing emotions with others. They may also be unhealthy and ineffective like increased use of alcohol, drugs, and violence. Although exercise is important for self-care, sleep is also important. Shutting oneself away from friends and family by not talking about the sadness is not effective; the patient should spend time with people who are nurturing.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify the nurse’s role when caring for patients who are experiencing loss, grief, or death.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is called into the supervisor’s office regarding deteriorating work performance since the loss of a spouse 2 years ago. The nurse begins sobbing and says, “I’m falling apart at home as well”. Which type of grief is the nurse experiencing?",
        "options": [
          "Normal grief",
          "Perceived grief",
          "Complicated grief",
          "Disenfranchised grief"
        ],
        "answer": "Complicated grief",
        "explanation": "In complicated grief, a person has a prolonged or significantly difficult time moving forward after a loss. Normal grief is the most common reaction to death; it involves a complex range of normal coping strategies. Disenfranchised grief involves a relationship that is not socially sanctioned. Perceived grief is not a type of grief; perceived loss is a loss that is less obvious to other people.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify types of grief.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient in the last stages of dying. Which finding indicates the nurse needs to prepare the family for death?",
        "options": [
          "Redness of skin",
          "Clear-colored urine",
          "Tense muscles tone",
          "Cheyne-Stokes breathing"
        ],
        "answer": "Cheyne-Stokes breathing",
        "explanation": "Altered breathing such as Cheyne-Stokes pattern, apnea, labored, or irregular breathing is a sign of impending death. Cyanotic, pallor, or mottling of skin occurs. Urine is decreased and a dark color. Decreased muscle tone, relaxed jaw muscles, and sagging mouth also occur.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe interventions for symptom management in patients at the end of life.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The mother of a child who died recently keeps the child’s room intact. Family members are encouraging her to redecorate and move forward in life. Which type of grief will the home health nurse recognize the mother is experiencing?",
        "options": [
          "Normal",
          "End-of-life",
          "Abnormal",
          "Complicated"
        ],
        "answer": "Normal",
        "explanation": "Family members will grieve differently. One sign of normal grief is keeping the deceased individual’s room intact as a way to keep that person alive in the minds of survivors. This is happening after the family member is deceased, so it is not end-of-life grief. It is not abnormal or complicated grief; the child died recently.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify types of grief.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a dying patient. One of the nurse’s goals is to promote dignity and validation of the dying person’s life. Which action will the nurse take to best achieve this goal?",
        "options": [
          "Take pictures of visitors.",
          "Provide quiet visiting time.",
          "Call the organ donation coordinator.",
          "Listen to family stories about the person."
        ],
        "answer": "Listen to family stories about the person.",
        "explanation": "Listening to family members’ stories validates the importance of the dying individual’s life and reinforces the dignity of the person’s life. Taking pictures of visitors does not address the value of a person’s life. Calling organ donation and providing private visiting time are components of the dying process, but they do not validate a dying person’s life.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify ways to collaborate with family members and the interdisciplinary team to provide palliative care.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a dying patient. When is the best time for the nurse to discuss end-of-life care?",
        "options": [
          "During assessment",
          "During planning",
          "During implementation",
          "During evaluation"
        ],
        "answer": "During assessment",
        "explanation": "Because most deaths are now “negotiated” among patients, family members, and the health care team, discuss end-of-life care preferences early in the assessment phase of the nursing process. Doing so during the planning, implementation, and evaluation phases is too late.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify the nurse’s role when caring for patients who are experiencing loss, grief, or death.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is providing postmortem care. Which action will the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Leave dentures in the mouth.",
          "Lower the head of the bed.",
          "Cover the body with a sterile sheet.",
          "Remove all tubes for an autopsy."
        ],
        "answer": "Leave dentures in the mouth.",
        "explanation": "Leave dentures in the mouth to maintain facial shape. Raise the head of the bed as soon as possible after death to prevent discoloration of the face. Cover the body with a clean sheet. Autopsy often does not allow removal of tubes, equipment, and indwelling lines.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe care of the body after death.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse facilitates the transplant coordinator in make a request for organ and tissue donation from the patient’s family. What is the primary rationale for the nurse’s action?",
        "options": [
          "The nurse is not as knowledgeable as the coordinator.",
          "The nurse is uncomfortable asking the family.",
          "The nurse does not want to upset the family.",
          "The nurse is following a federal law."
        ],
        "answer": "The nurse is following a federal law.",
        "explanation": "In accordance with federal law, a specially trained professional (e.g., transplant coordinator or social worker) makes requests for organ and tissue donation at the time of every death. Given the complex and sensitive nature of such requests, only specially trained personnel make the requests. Although the nurse may be less knowledgeable than the coordinator, uncomfortable asking the family, or not wanting to upset the family, the primary rationale is to be in accordance with federal law.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify the nurse’s role when caring for patients who are experiencing loss, grief, or death.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient cancels a scheduled appointment because they will be attending a Shivah for a family member. Which response by the nurse is best?",
        "options": [
          "“When families come together for end-of-life decisions, it provides connections.”",
          "“We will reschedule so the appointment does not fall on the Sabbath.”",
          "“Missionary outreach is so important for spiritual comfort.”",
          "“I’m so sorry for your loss.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“I’m so sorry for your loss.”",
        "explanation": "A death has occurred and saying that you are sorry for their loss is appropriate. The Jewish mourning ritual of Shivah is a time period when normal life activities come to a stop. Those mourning welcome friends into the home as a way of honoring the dead and receive support during the mourning period. Cultural variables can influence a person’s response to grief. It is not when families come together for end-of-life decisions. It is not because the appointment fell on the Sabbath. It is not about missionary outreach.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss variables that influence a person’s response to grief.",
        "top": "Caring",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "During a follow-up visit, a female patient is describing new onset of marital discord with her terminally ill spouse to the hospice nurse. Which Kübler-Ross stage of dying is the patient experiencing?",
        "options": [
          "Denial",
          "Anger",
          "Bargaining",
          "Depression"
        ],
        "answer": "Anger",
        "explanation": "Kübler-Ross’s traditional theory involves five stages of dying. The anger stage of adjustment to an impending death can involve resistance, anger at God, anger at people, and anger at the situation. Denial would involve failure to accept a death. Bargaining is an action to delay acceptance of death by bartering. Depression would present as withdrawal from others.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss grief theories.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A previously toilet trained toddler has started wetting again. A nurse is gathering a health history from the grandparent. Which health history finding will the nurse most likely consider as the cause of the wetting?",
        "options": [
          "Dietary changes",
          "Recent parental death",
          "Playmate moved away",
          "Sibling was sick 2 days"
        ],
        "answer": "Recent parental death",
        "explanation": "A child’s stage of development and chronological age will influence grieving. Toddlers can show grief from a loss of parent(s) through changes in their eating patterns, changes in their sleeping patterns, fussiness, and changes in their bowel and bladder habits. It is common for younger children to regress when under increased stress. Siblings being sick, dietary changes, and playmates moving away are unlikely to cause wetting.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss variables that influence a person’s response to grief.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient’s father died a week ago. Both the patient and the patient’s spouse talk about the death. The patient’s spouse is experiencing headaches and fatigue. The patient is having trouble sleeping, has no appetite, and gets choked up most of the time. How should the nurse interpret these findings as the basis for a follow-up assessment?",
        "options": [
          "The patient is dying and the spouse is angry.",
          "The patient is ill and the spouse is malingering.",
          "Both the patient and the spouse are likely in denial.",
          "Both the patient and the spouse are likely grieving."
        ],
        "answer": "Both the patient and the spouse are likely grieving.",
        "explanation": "Both are likely grieving from the loss of the patient’s father. Symptoms of normal grief include headache, fatigue, insomnia, appetite disturbance, and choking sensation. Different people manifest different symptoms. There is no data to support the spouse is angry or malingering. There is no data to support the patient is dying or ill. Denial is assessed when the person cannot accept the loss; both talked about the loss.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe characteristics of a person experiencing grief.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is documenting end-of-life care. Which information will the nurse include in the patient’s electronic medical record? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Reason for the death",
          "Time and date of death",
          "Special preparations of the body",
          "Location of body identification tags",
          "Time of body transfer and destination"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Time and date of death",
          "Location of body identification tags",
          "Time of body transfer and destination"
        ],
        "explanation": "Documentation of end-of-life care includes the following: time and date of death, location of body identification tags, if special body preparation occurred, time of body transfer and destination and personal articles left on and secured to the body. Reason for the death is not appropriate; this is a medical judgment and not a nursing judgment.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify the nurse’s role when caring for patients who are experiencing loss, grief, or death.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      }
    ],
    "chapter37": [
        {
            "question": "In a natural disaster relief facility, the nurse observes that an older-adult male has a recovery plan, while a 25-year-old male is still overwhelmed by the disaster situation. A nurse is planning care for both patients. Which factors will the nurse consider about the different coping reactions?",
            "options": [
              "Restorative care factors",
              "Strong financial resource factors",
              "Maturational and situational factors",
              "Immaturity and intelligence factors"
            ],
            "answer": "Maturational and situational factors",
            "explanation": "Maturational factors and situational factors can affect people differently depending on their life experiences. An older individual would have more life experiences to draw from and to analyze on why he was successful, whereas a younger individual would have fewer life experiences based on chronological age to analyze for patterns of previous success. Nothing in the scenario implies that either man is in restorative care, has strong financial resources, or is immature or intelligent.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the integration of stress theory with nursing theories.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A woman who was sexually assaulted a month ago presents to the emergency department with reports of recurrent nightmares, fear of going to sleep, repeated vivid memories of the sexual assault, and inability to feel much emotion. Which medical problem will the nurse expect to see documented in the chart?",
            "options": [
              "General adaptation syndrome (GAS)",
              "Posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD)",
              "Acute stress disorder",
              "Alarm reaction"
            ],
            "answer": "Posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD)",
            "explanation": "Posttraumatic stress disorder is characterized by vivid recollections of the traumatic event and emotional detachment and often is accompanied by nightmares. General adaptation syndrome is the expected reaction to a major stressor. Acute stress disorder is a similar diagnosis that differs from PTSD in duration of symptoms. Alarm reaction involves physiological events such as increased activation of the sympathetic nervous system that would have occurred at the time of the sexual assault.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe characteristics of post-traumatic stress disorder.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse teaches stress-reduction and relaxation training to a health education group of patients after cardiac bypass surgery. Which level of intervention is the nurse using?",
            "options": [
              "Primary",
              "Secondary",
              "Tertiary",
              "Quad"
            ],
            "answer": "Tertiary",
            "explanation": "Tertiary-level interventions assist the patient in readapting and can include relaxation training and time-management training. At the primary level of prevention, you direct nursing activities to identifying individuals and populations who are possibly at risk for stress. Nursing interventions at the secondary level include actions directed at symptoms such as protecting the patient from self-harm. Quad level does not exist.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the integration of stress theory with nursing theories.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching guided imagery to a prenatal class. Which technique did the nurse describe?",
            "options": [
              "Singing",
              "Massaging back",
              "Listening to music",
              "Visualizing peaceful settings"
            ],
            "answer": "Visualizing peaceful settings",
            "explanation": "Guided imagery is used as a means to create a relaxed state through the person's imagination. Imagination allows the person to create a soothing and peaceful environment. Singing, back massage, and listening to music are other types of stress management techniques.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe stress management techniques beneficial for coping with stress.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "After a natural disaster occurred, an emergency worker referred a family for crisis intervention services. One family member refused to attend the services, stating, “No way, I'm not crazy.” What is the nurse's best response?",
            "options": [
              "“Many times, disasters can create mental health problems, so you really should participate with your family.”",
              "“Seeking this kind of help does not mean that you have a mental illness; it is a short-term problem-solving technique.”",
              "“Don't worry now. The psychiatrists are well trained to help.”",
              "“This will help your family communicate better.”"
            ],
            "answer": "“Seeking this kind of help does not mean that you have a mental illness; it is a short-term problem-solving technique.”",
            "explanation": "Crisis intervention is a type of brief therapy that is more directive than traditional psychotherapy or counseling. It focuses on problem solving and involves only the problem created by the crisis. The other options do not properly reassure the patient and build trust. Giving advice in the form of “you really should participate” is inappropriate. “Don't worry now” is false reassurance. While crisis intervention may help families communicate better, the goal is to return to pre-crisis level of functioning; family therapy will focus on helping families communicate better.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the process of crisis intervention.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A preadolescent patient is experiencing maturational stress. Which area will the nurse focus on when planning care?",
            "options": [
              "Identity issues",
              "Self-esteem issues",
              "Physical appearance",
              "Major changing life events"
            ],
            "answer": "Self-esteem issues",
            "explanation": "Preadolescents experience stress related to self-esteem issues, changing family structure as a result of divorce or death of a parent, or hospitalizations. Adolescent stressors include identity issues with peer groups and separation from their families. Children identify stressors related to physical appearance, families, friends, and school. Adult stressors centralize around major changes in life circumstances.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the integration of stress theory with nursing theories.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient experiencing stress and is in the evaluation stage of the critical thinking model. Which actions will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Select nursing interventions and promote patient's adaptation to stress.",
              "Establish short- and long-term goals with the patient experiencing stress.",
              "Identify stress management interventions and achieve expected outcomes.",
              "Reassess patient's stress-related symptoms and compare with expected outcomes."
            ],
            "answer": "Reassess patient's stress-related symptoms and compare with expected outcomes.",
            "explanation": "During the evaluation stage, the nurse compares current stress-related symptoms against established measurable outcomes to evaluate the effectiveness of the intervention. Selecting appropriate interventions and establishing goals are part of the planning process.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a care plan for patients who are experiencing stress.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "An adult male reports new-onset, seizure-like activity. An EEG and a neurology consultant's report rule out a seizure disorder. It is determined the patient is using conversion. Which action should the nurse take next?",
            "options": [
              "Suggest acupuncture.",
              "Confront the patient on malingering.",
              "Obtain history of any recent life stressors.",
              "Recommend a regular exercise program."
            ],
            "answer": "Obtain history of any recent life stressors.",
            "explanation": "Unconsciously repressing an anxiety-producing emotional conflict and transforming it into nonorganic symptoms (e.g., difficulty sleeping, loss of appetite) describes conversion defense mechanism. The nurse must assess the patient fully for emotional conflict and stress before implementing any nursing interventions (acupuncture or exercise program). Although the patient may be malingering, confrontation is nontherapeutic because the patient is using this type of defense mechanism in response to some type of stressor.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a care plan for patients who are experiencing stress.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A senior college student visits the college health clinic about a freshman student living on the same dormitory floor. The senior student reports that the freshman is crying and is not adjusting to college life. The clinic nurse recognizes this as a combination of situational and maturational stress factors. Which is the best response by the nurse?",
            "options": [
              "“Let's call 9-1-1 because this freshman student is suicidal.”",
              "“Give the freshman student this list of university and community resources.”",
              "“I recommend that you help the freshman student start packing bags to go home.”",
              "“You must make an appointment for the freshman student to obtain medications.”"
            ],
            "answer": "“Give the freshman student this list of university and community resources.”",
            "explanation": "A nurse can help reduce situational stress factors for individuals. Inform the patient about potential resources. Providing the student with a list of resources is one way to begin this process, as part of secondary prevention strategies. This is not a medical or psychiatric emergency, so calling 9-1-1 is not necessary. Not everyone who has sadness needs medications; some need counseling only. Not enough information is given to know whether the student would be best suited to leave college.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a care plan for patients who are experiencing stress.",
            "top": "Communication and Documentation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "Despite working in a highly stressful nursing unit and accepting additional shifts, a new nurse has a strategy to prevent burnout. Which strategy will be best for the nurse to use?",
            "options": [
              "Delegate complex nursing tasks to nursing assistive personnel.",
              "Strengthen friendships outside the workplace.",
              "Write for 10 minutes in a journal every day.",
              "Use progressive muscle relaxation."
            ],
            "answer": "Strengthen friendships outside the workplace.",
            "explanation": "Strengthening friendships outside of the workplace, arranging for temporary social isolation for personal “recharging” of emotional energy, and spending off-duty hours in interesting activities all help reduce burnout. Journaling and muscle relaxation are good stress-relieving techniques but are not directed at the cause of the workplace stress. Delegating complex nursing tasks to nursing assistive personnel is an inappropriate.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss how stress in the workplace affects nurses.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A female teen with celiac disease continues to eat food she knows will make her ill several hours after ingestion. While planning care, the nurse considers maturational and tertiary-level interventions. Which intervention will the nurse add to the care plan?",
            "options": [
              "Teach the teen about the food pyramid.",
              "Administer antidiarrheal medications with meals.",
              "Gently admonish the teen and her parents regarding the consistently poor diet choices.",
              "Assist the teen in meeting dietary restrictions while eating foods similar to those eaten by her friends."
            ],
            "answer": "Assist the teen in meeting dietary restrictions while eating foods similar to those eaten by her friends.",
            "explanation": "Tertiary-level interventions assist the patient in readapting to life with an illness. By adjusting the diet to meet dietary guidelines and also addressing adolescent maturational needs, the nurse will help the teen to eat an appropriate diet without health complications and see herself as a “typical and normal” teenager. Teaching about the food pyramid will not address the real issue, which is that the teen is still eating what she knows will make her ill and the food pyramid is usually a primary intervention. Administering antidiarrheal medications may help but is not a tertiary-level or maturational intervention. Admonishing the teen and parents is not a tertiary-level intervention, and because this approach is nontherapeutic, it may cause communication problems.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Develop a care plan for patients who are experiencing stress.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A trauma survivor is requesting sleep medication because of “bad dreams.” The nurse is concerned that the patient may be experiencing posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Which question is a priority for the nurse to ask the patient?",
            "options": [
              "“Are you reliving your trauma?”",
              "“Are you having chest pain?”",
              "“Can you describe your phobias?”",
              "“Can you tell me when you wake up?”"
            ],
            "answer": "“Are you reliving your trauma?”",
            "explanation": "People who have PTSD often have flashbacks, recurrent and intrusive recollections of the event. The other answers involve assessment of problems not specific to PTSD.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe characteristics of post-traumatic stress disorder.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient in a motor vehicle accident states, “I did not run the red light,” despite very clear evidence on the street surveillance tape. Which defense mechanism is the patient using?",
            "options": [
              "Denial",
              "Conversion",
              "Dissociation",
              "Compensation"
            ],
            "answer": "Denial",
            "explanation": "Denial consists of avoiding emotional conflicts by refusing to consciously acknowledge anything that causes intolerable emotional pain. Dissociation involves creating subjective numbness and less awareness of surroundings. Conversion involves repressing anxiety and manifesting it into nonorganic symptoms. Compensation occurs when an individual makes up for a deficit by strongly emphasizing another feature.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the integration of stress theory with nursing theories.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching the staff about the general adaptation syndrome. In which order will the nurse list the stages, beginning with the first stage?\n\n1. Resistance\n2. Exhaustion\n3. Alarm",
            "options": [
              "3, 1, 2",
              "3, 2, 1",
              "1, 3, 2",
              "1, 2, 3 "
            ],
            "answer": "3, 1, 2",
            "explanation": "The general adaptation syndrome (GAS), a three-stage reaction to stress, describes how the body responds physiologically to stressors through stages of alarm, resistance, and exhaustion.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the three stages of the general adaptation syndrome.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A young male patient is diagnosed with testicular cancer. Which action will the nurse take first?",
            "options": [
              "Provide information to the patient.",
              "Allow time for the patient's friends.",
              "Ask about the patient's priority needs.",
              "Find support for the family and patient."
            ],
            "answer": "Ask about the patient's priority needs.",
            "explanation": "Take time to understand a patient's meaning of the precipitating event and the ways in which stress is affecting his life. For example, in the case of a woman who has just been told that a breast mass was identified on a routine mammogram, it is important to know what the patient wants (priority needs) and needs most from the nurse. Providing information, allowing time with friends, and finding support may be implemented after finding out what the patient wants or needs.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a care plan for patients who are experiencing stress.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching the staff about a nursing theory that views a person, family, or community developing a normal line of defense. Which theory is the nurse describing?",
            "options": [
              "Ego defense model",
              "Immunity model",
              "Neuman Systems Model",
              "Pender's Health Promotion Model"
            ],
            "answer": "Neuman Systems Model",
            "explanation": "The Neuman Systems Model uses a systems approach, and it helps you understand your patients' individual responses to stressors and also families' and communities' responses. Every person develops a set of responses to stress that constitute the “normal line of defense.” This line of defense helps to maintain health and wellness. Ego defense mechanisms are unconscious coping mechanisms. Immunity is a body's natural protection mechanism. Pender's Health Promotion Model focuses on promoting health and managing stress.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the integration of stress theory with nursing theories.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "An adult who was in a motor vehicle accident is brought into the emergency department by paramedics, who report the following in-transit vital signs:\n\nOral temperature: 99.0° F\nPulse: 102 beats/min\nRespiratory rate: 26 breaths/min\nBlood pressure: 140/106\n\nWhich hormones should the nurse consider as the most likely causes of the abnormal vital signs?",
            "options": [
              "ADH and ACTH",
              "ACTH and epinephrine",
              "ADH and norepinephrine",
              "Epinephrine and norepinephrine"
            ],
            "answer": "Epinephrine and norepinephrine",
            "explanation": "During the alarm stage, rising hormone levels result in increased blood volume, blood glucose levels, epinephrine and norepinephrine amounts, heart rate, blood flow to muscles, oxygen intake, and mental alertness. ACTH originates from the anterior pituitary gland and stimulates cortisol release; ADH originates from the posterior pituitary and increases renal reabsorption of water. ACTH, cortisol, and ADH do not increase heart rate.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the three stages of the general adaptation syndrome.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is planning care for a patient that uses displacement as a defense mechanism. Which information should the nurse consider when planning interventions?",
            "options": [
              "This copes with stress directly.",
              "This evaluates an event for its personal meaning.",
              "This protects against feelings of worthlessness and anxiety.",
              "This triggers the stress control functions of the medulla oblongata."
            ],
            "answer": "This protects against feelings of worthlessness and anxiety.",
            "explanation": "Ego defense mechanisms, like displacement, regulate emotional distress and thus give a person protection from anxiety and stress. Everyone uses them unconsciously to protect against worthlessness and feelings of anxiety. Ego-defense mechanisms help a person cope with stress indirectly and offer psychological protection from a stressful event. Evaluation of an event for its personal meaning is primary appraisal. The medulla oblongata controls heart rate, blood pressure, and respirations and is not triggered by ego defense mechanisms.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the integration of stress theory with nursing theories.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which sociocultural finding in the history of a patient will alert the nurse to a possible developmental problem?",
            "options": [
              "Family relocation",
              "Childhood obesity",
              "Prolonged poverty",
              "Loss of stamina"
            ],
            "answer": "Prolonged poverty",
            "explanation": "Environmental and social stressors often lead to developmental problems. Sociocultural refers to societal or cultural factors; poverty is a sociocultural factor. Stamina loss and obesity are health problems, and family relocation is a situational factor.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the integration of stress theory with nursing theories.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is helping parents who have a child with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Which strategy will the nurse share with the parents to reduce stress regarding homework assignments?",
            "options": [
              "Time-management skills",
              "Speech articulation skills",
              "Routine preventative health visits",
              "Assertiveness training for the family"
            ],
            "answer": "Time-management skills",
            "explanation": "Time-management skills are most related to homework assignment completion. Time-management techniques include developing lists of prioritized tasks. Routine health visits are important but do not directly affect ability to complete homework. Speech and other developmental aspects need to be developed if the child is to be successful, but skill development will not directly reduce homework-related stress. Assertiveness includes skills for helping individuals communicate effectively regarding their needs and desires, but it does not help with homework assignments.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe stress management techniques beneficial for coping with stress.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing a patient with prolonged stress. Which conditions will the nurse monitor for in this patient? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Cancer",
              "Diabetes",
              "Infections",
              "Allostasis",
              "Low blood pressure"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Cancer",
                "Diabetes",
                "Infections"
            ],
            "explanation": "Stress causes prolonged changes in the immune system, which can result in impaired immune function, and this increases the person's susceptibility to changes in health, such as increased risk for infection, high blood pressure, diabetes, and cancers. Allostasis is a return to a state of balance; allostatic load occurs with prolonged stress.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a care plan for patients who are experiencing stress.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          }
    ],
    "chapter38": [
        {
            "question": "A nurse observes a patient rising from a chair slowly by pushing on the chair arms. Which type of tension and contraction did the nurse observe?",
            "options": [
              "Eccentric tension and isotonic contraction",
              "Eccentric tension and isometric contraction",
              "Concentric tension and isotonic contraction",
              "Concentric tension and isometric contraction"
            ],
            "answer": "Eccentric tension and isotonic contraction",
            "explanation": "This movement causes eccentric tension and isotonic contraction. Eccentric tension helps control the speed and direction of movement. For example, when using an overhead trapeze, the patient slowly lowers himself to the bed. The lowering is controlled when the antagonistic muscles lengthen. By pushing on the chair arms and rising eccentric tension and isotonic contraction occurred. In concentric tension, increased muscle contraction causes muscle shortening, resulting in movement such as when a patient uses an overhead trapeze to pull up in bed. Concentric and eccentric muscle actions are necessary for active movement and therefore are referred to as dynamic or isotonic contraction. Isometric contraction (static contraction) causes an increase in muscle tension or muscle work but no shortening or active movement of the muscle (e.g., instructing the patient to tighten and relax a muscle group, as in quadriceps set exercises or pelvic floor exercises).",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the role of the musculoskeletal and nervous systems in the regulation of activity and exercise.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse notices that a patient has a structural curvature of the spine associated with vertebral rotation. Which condition will the nurse most likely find documented in the patient's medical record?",
            "options": [
              "Scoliosis",
              "Arthritis",
              "Osteomalacia",
              "Osteogenesis"
            ],
            "answer": "Scoliosis",
            "explanation": "Scoliosis is a structural curvature of the spine associated with vertebral rotation. Osteogenesis imperfecta is an inherited disorder that makes bones porous, short, bowed, and deformed. Osteomalacia is an uncommon metabolic disease characterized by inadequate and delayed mineralization, resulting in compact and spongy bone. Arthritis is an inflammatory joint disease characterized by inflammation or destruction of the synovial membrane and articular cartilage and by systemic signs of inflammation.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the role of the musculoskeletal and nervous systems in the regulation of activity and exercise.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who is experiencing some symptoms related to arthritis. The nurse is teaching the patient about this process. Which information will the nurse include in the teaching session?",
            "options": [
              "This will affect synovial fluid.",
              "This will affect the body systemically.",
              "This involves mostly non-weight-bearing joints.",
              "This involves an increased risk for impaired weight bearing."
            ],
            "answer": "This involves an increased risk for impaired weight bearing.",
            "explanation": "Joint degeneration, which can occur with inflammatory and noninflammatory disease, is marked by changes in articular cartilage combined with overgrowth of bone at the articular ends. Degenerative changes commonly affect weight-bearing joints. Synovial fluid is normal in noninflammatory diseases. Inflammatory joint disease (e.g., arthritis) is characterized by inflammation or destruction of the synovial membrane and articular cartilage and by systemic signs of inflammation.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the influence of immobility on body alignment, joint movement, and activity.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse providing care to a bedridden patient raises the height of the bed. What is the rationale for the nurse's action?",
            "options": [
              "Narrows the nurse's base of support.",
              "Allows the nurse to bring feet closer together.",
              "Prevents a shift in the nurse's base of support.",
              "Shifts the nurse's center of gravity farther away from the base of support."
            ],
            "answer": "Prevents a shift in the nurse's base of support.",
            "explanation": "Raising the height of the bed when performing a procedure prevents bending too far at the waist and shifting the base of support.Balance is maintained by proper body alignment and posture through two simple techniques. First, widen the base of support by separating the feet to a comfortable distance. Second, increase balance by bringing the center of gravity closer to the base of support.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe how to maintain and use proper body mechanics.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is following the no-lift policy when working to prevent personal injury from twisting. Which type of personal back injury is the nurse most likely trying to prevent?",
            "options": [
              "Thoracic",
              "Cervical",
              "Lumbar",
              "Sacral"
            ],
            "answer": "Lumbar",
            "explanation": "The most common back injury for nurses is strain on the lumbar muscle group, which includes the muscles around the lumbar vertebrae that are commonly injured by twisting during the lifting of patients. While cervical, thoracic, and sacral can occur, lumbar is the most common.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe how to maintain and use proper body mechanics.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient in the emergency department with an injured shoulder. Which type of joint will the nurse assess?",
            "options": [
              "Fibrous",
              "Synovial",
              "Synergistic",
              "Cartilaginous"
            ],
            "answer": "Synovial",
            "explanation": "Synovial joints, or true joints, such as the hinge type at the elbow, are freely movable and the most mobile, numerous, and anatomically complex body joints. Fibrous joints fit closely together and are fixed, permitting little, if any, movement such as the syndesmosis between the tibia and the fibula. Synergistic is a type of muscle, not joint. Cartilaginous joints have little movement but are elastic and use cartilage to unite separate bony surfaces such as the synchondrosis that attaches the ribs to the costal cartilage.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the role of the musculoskeletal and nervous systems in the regulation of activity and exercise.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with inner ear problems. Which goal is the priority?",
            "options": [
              "Maintain balance.",
              "Maintain proprioception.",
              "Maintain muscle strength.",
              "Maintain body alignment."
            ],
            "answer": "Maintain balance.",
            "explanation": "Within the inner ear are the semicircular canals, three fluid-filled structures that help maintain balance. Proprioception is the awareness of the position of the body and its parts, and proprioceptors are located on nerve endings, not the inner ear. Muscle strength is maintained with activity and exercise. Although body alignment is important, it is not maintained by the inner ear.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the role of the musculoskeletal and nervous systems in the regulation of activity and exercise.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is teaching a health promotion class about isotonic exercises. Which types of exercises will the nurse give as examples?",
            "options": [
              "Swimming, jogging, and bicycling",
              "Tightening or tensing of muscles without moving body parts",
              "Quadriceps set exercises and contraction of the gluteal muscles",
              "Push-ups, hip lifting, pushing feet against a footboard on the bed"
            ],
            "answer": "Swimming, jogging, and bicycling",
            "explanation": "Examples of isotonic exercises are walking, swimming, dance aerobics, jogging, bicycling, and moving arms and legs with light resistance. Isometric exercises involve tightening or tensing of muscles without moving body parts. Examples include quadriceps set exercises and contraction of the gluteal muscles. Examples of resistive isometric exercises are push-ups and hip lifting, as well as placing a footboard on the foot of the bed for patients to push against with their feet.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the evidence that supports regular activity and exercise in patient care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "An adolescent tells the nurse that a health professional said the fibrous tissue that connects bone and cartilage was strained in a sporting accident. On which structure will the nurse focus an assessment?",
            "options": [
              "Tendon",
              "Ligament",
              "Synergistic muscle",
              "Antagonistic muscle"
            ],
            "answer": "Ligament",
            "explanation": "Ligaments are white, shiny, and flexible bands of fibrous tissue that bind joints and connect bones and cartilage. Tendons are strong, flexible, and inelastic as they serve to connect muscle to bone. Muscles attach bone to bone. Synergistic muscles contract to accomplish the same movement. Antagonistic muscles cause movement at the joint.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the role of the musculoskeletal and nervous systems in the regulation of activity and exercise.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is developing an exercise plan for a middle-aged patient. In which order will the nurse instruct the patient to execute the plan, beginning with the first step?\n\n1. Design the fitness program.\n2. Assemble equipment.\n3. Assess fitness level.\n4. Monitor progress.\n5. Get started.",
            "options": [
              "5, 1, 3, 2, 4",
              "1, 2, 3, 5, 4",
              "2, 5, 3, 1, 4",
              "3, 1, 2, 5, 4"
            ],
            "answer": "3, 1, 2, 5, 4",
            "explanation": "Five steps to beginning an exercise program are:\n\nStep 1: Assess fitness level;\nStep 2: Design the fitness program;\nStep 3: Assemble equipment;\nStep 4: Get started \nStep 5: Monitor progress.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe important factors to consider when planning an exercise program for patients across the life span and for those with specific",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse gives instructions to a nursing assistive personnel (NAP) regarding exercise for a patient. Which action by the NAP indicates a correct understanding of the directions?",
            "options": [
              "Determines the patient's ability to exercise.",
              "Teaches the patient how to do the exercises.",
              "Reports the patient got dizzy after exercising.",
              "Advises the patient to work through the pain."
            ],
            "answer": "Reports the patient got dizzy after exercising.",
            "explanation": "The NAP notifies the nurse if a patient reports increased fatigue, dizziness, or light-headedness when obtaining pre-exercise and/or post-exercise vital signs. The nurse first must assess the patient's ability and tolerance to exercise. The nurse also teaches patients and their families how to implement exercise programs. The NAP can prepare patients for exercise (e.g., putting on shoes and clothing, providing hygiene needs, and obtaining pre-exercise and post-exercise vital signs). The NAP can help the patient exercise.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop an individualized nursing care plan for a patient with activity tolerance.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is starting an exercise program in a local community as a health promotion project. Which information will the nurse include in the teaching session?",
            "options": [
              "A cool-down period lasts about 5 to 10 minutes.",
              "The purpose of weight training is to bulk up muscles.",
              "Resistance training is appropriate for warm-up and cool-down periods.",
              "Aerobic exercise should be done 3 to 5 times per week for about 20 minutes."
            ],
            "answer": "A cool-down period lasts about 5 to 10 minutes.",
            "explanation": "The cool-down period follows the exercise routine and usually lasts about 5 to 10 minutes. The purposes of weight training from a health perspective are to develop tone and strength and to simulate and maintain healthy bone. Stretching and flexibility exercises are ideal for warm-up and cool-down periods. The recommended frequency of aerobic exercise is 3 to 5 times per week or every other day for approximately 30 minutes.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the evidence that supports regular activity and exercise in patient care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is eager to begin an exercise program with a 2-mile jog. The nurse instructs the patient to warm up. The patient does not want to waste time with a “warm-up.” Which information will the nurse share with the patient?",
            "options": [
              "The warm-up in this case can be done after the 2-mile jog.",
              "The warm-up prepares the body and decreases the potential for injury.",
              "The warm-up allows the body to readjust gradually to baseline functioning.",
              "The warm-up should be performed with high intensity to prepare for the coming challenge."
            ],
            "answer": "The warm-up prepares the body and decreases the potential for injury.",
            "explanation": "The warm-up activity prepares the body for activity and decreases the potential for injury and should not be omitted. It usually lasts about 5 to 10 minutes and may include stretching, calisthenics, and/or aerobic activity performed at a lower intensity. The warm-up is before the exercise, while the cool-down period is after the exercise. The cool-down, not the warm-up, allows the body to readjust gradually to baseline functioning and provides an opportunity to combine movement such as stretching with relaxation-enhancing mind-body awareness. The warm-up should not be a high-intensity workout.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the evidence that supports regular activity and exercise in patient care.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who cannot bear weight but needs to be transferred from the bed to a chair. The nurse decides to use a transportable hydraulic lift. What action indicates the nurse is aware of appropriate hydraulic life use?",
            "options": [
              "Places a horseshoe-shaped base on the opposite side from the chair.",
              "Removes straps before lowering the patient to the chair.",
              "Hooks longer straps to the bottom of the sling.",
              "Attaches short straps to the bottom of the sling."
            ],
            "answer": "Hooks longer straps to the bottom of the sling.",
            "explanation": "The nurse should attach the hooks on the strap to the holes in the sling. Short straps hook to top holes of the sling; longer straps hook to the bottom of the sling. The horseshoe-shaped base goes under the side of the bed on the side with the chair. Position the patient and lower slowly into the chair in accordance with manufacturer guidelines to safely guide the patient into the back of the chair as the seat descends; then remove the straps and the mechanical/hydraulic lift.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe equipment needed for safe patient handling and movement.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is preparing to move a patient to a wheelchair. Which action indicates the nurse is following recommendations for safe patient handling?",
            "options": [
              "Mentally reviews the transfer steps before beginning.",
              "Uses own strength to transfer the patient.",
              "Focuses solely on body mechanics.",
              "Bases decisions on intuition."
            ],
            "answer": "Mentally reviews the transfer steps before beginning.",
            "explanation": "Safe patient handling includes mentally reviewing the transfer steps before beginning the procedure to ensure both the patient's and your safety. Use the patient's strength when lifting, transferring, or moving when possible. Body mechanics alone do not protect the nurse from injury to the musculoskeletal system when moving, lifting, or transferring patients. After completing the assessment,nurses use an algorithm to guide decisions about safe patient handling.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the impact of national patient safety resources, initiatives, and regulations in relation to patient handling and movement.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is working in a facility that follows a comprehensive safe patient-handling program. Which finding will alert the nurse to intervene?",
            "options": [
              "Mechanical lifts are in a locked closet.",
              "Algorithms for patient handling are available.",
              "Ergonomic assessment protocols are being followed.",
              "A no-lift policy is in place with adherence by all staff."
            ],
            "answer": "Mechanical lifts are in a locked closet.",
            "explanation": "The nurse will follow up when lifts are not kept in convenient locations. Comprehensive safe patient-handling programs include the following elements: an ergonomics assessment protocol for health care environments, patient assessment criteria, algorithms for patient handling and movement, special equipment kept in convenient locations to help transfer patients, back injury resource nurses, an “after-action review” that allows the health care team to apply knowledge about moving patients safely in different settings, and a no-lift policy.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the impact of national patient safety resources, initiatives, and regulations in relation to patient handling and movement.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is brought to the emergency department with possible injury to the left shoulder. Which area will the nurse assess to best determine joint mobility?",
            "options": [
              "The patient's gait",
              "The patient's range of motion",
              "The patient's ethnic influences",
              "The patient's fine-motor coordination"
            ],
            "answer": "The patient's range of motion",
            "explanation": "Assessing range of motion is one assessment technique used to determine the degree of joint mobility and injury to a joint. Gait is the manner or style of walking. It has little bearing on the shoulder damage. Assessing fine-motor coordination would be beneficial in helping to assess the patient's ability to perform tasks such as feeding and dressing but would not help in evaluating the shoulder. Ethnic influences would not have a direct bearing on the amount of mobility in the joint.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe how to assess patients for activity intolerance. ",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is evaluating care of a patient for crutches. Which finding indicates a successful outcome?",
            "options": [
              "The top of the crutch is three to four finger widths from the armpit.",
              "The elbows are slightly flexed at 30 to 35 degrees when the patient is standing.",
              "The tip of the crutch is 4 to 6 inches anterior to the front of the patient's shoes.",
              "The position of the handgrips allows the axilla to support the patient's body weight."
            ],
            "answer": "The tip of the crutch is 4 to 6 inches anterior to the front of the patient's shoes.",
            "explanation": "When crutches are fitted, the tip of the crutch is 4 to 6 inches anterior to the front of the patient's shoes, and the length of the crutch is two to three finger widths from the axilla. Position the handgrips so the axillae are not supporting the patient's body weight.Pressure on the axillae increases risk to underlying nerves, which sometimes results in partial paralysis of the arm. Determine correct position of the handgrips with the patient upright, supporting weight by the handgrips with the elbows slightly flexed at 20 to 25 degrees.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Evaluate the nursing care plan for maintaining activity and exercise for patients across the life span and with specific chronic illnesses.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient reports being tired and weak and lacks energy. Upon assessment, the nurse finds that patient has gained weight, and blood pressure and pulse are elevated after climbing stairs. Which nursing diagnosis will the nurse add to the care plan?",
            "options": [
              "Fatigue",
              "Ineffective coping",
              "Activity intolerance",
              "Decreased cardiac output"
            ],
            "answer": "Activity intolerance",
            "explanation": "You consider nursing diagnoses of Activity intolerance or Fatigue in a patient who reports being tired and weak. Further review of assessed defining characteristics (e.g., abnormal heart rate and verbal report of weakness and the assessment findings occurring during the activity of climbing the stairs) leads to the definitive diagnosis (Activity intolerance). There is no data to support ineffective coping or decreased cardiac output.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Formulate nursing diagnoses for patients experiencing problems with activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Diagnosis",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient weighs 450 lbs (204.5 kg) and reports shortness of breath with any exertion. The health care provider has recommended beginning an exercise program. The patient states that she can hardly get out of bed and just cannot do anything around the house. Which nursing diagnosis will the nurse add to the care plan?",
            "options": [
              "Activity intolerance related to excessive weight",
              "Impaired physical mobility related to bed rest",
              "Imbalanced nutrition: less than body requirements",
              "Impaired gas exchange related to shortness of breath"
            ],
            "answer": "Activity intolerance related to excessive weight",
            "explanation": "In this case, activity intolerance is related to the patient's excessive weight. The patient is not on bed rest although claims that it is difficult to get out of bed, making this diagnosis inappropriate. Shortness of breath is a symptom, not a cause, of Impaired gas exchange, making this nursing diagnosis ineffective. The patient certainly has an imbalance of nutrition, but it is more than body requirements (obesity).",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Formulate nursing diagnoses for patients experiencing problems with activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Diagnosis",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient diagnosed with diabetes mellitus is starting an exercise program. Which types of exercises will the nurse suggest?",
            "options": [
              "Low intensity",
              "Low to moderate intensity",
              "Moderate to high intensity",
              "High intensity"
            ],
            "answer": "Low to moderate intensity",
            "explanation": "Instruct patients diagnosed with diabetes mellitus to perform low- to moderate-intensity exercises, carry a concentrated form of carbohydrates (sugar packets or hard candy), and wear a medical alert bracelet. Low intensity is not beneficial. Moderate to high end intensity are not recommended for a beginner exercise program.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop an individualized nursing care plan for a patient with activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient is admitted after having experienced a stroke. The outcome of this disorder is uncertain, but the patient is unable to move the right arm and leg. The nurse starts passive range-of-motion (ROM) exercises. Which finding indicates successful goal achievement?",
            "options": [
              "Heart rate decreased.",
              "Contractures developed.",
              "Muscle strength improved.",
              "Joint mobility maintained."
            ],
            "answer": "Joint mobility maintained.",
            "explanation": "When patients cannot participate in active ROM, maintain joint mobility and prevent contractures by implementing passive ROM into the plan of care. Exercise and active ROM can improve muscle strength. ROM is not performed for the heart but for the joints.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Evaluate the nursing care plan for maintaining activity and exercise for patients across the life span and with specific chronic illnesses.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing a patient with activity intolerance for possible orthostatic hypotension. Which finding will help confirm orthostatic hypotension?",
            "options": [
              "Blood pressure sitting 120/64; blood pressure 140/70 standing",
              "Blood pressure sitting 126/64; blood pressure 120/58 standing",
              "Blood pressure sitting 130/60; blood pressure 110/60 standing",
              "Blood pressure sitting 140/60; blood pressure 130/54 standing"
            ],
            "answer": "Blood pressure sitting 130/60; blood pressure 110/60 standing",
            "explanation": "Orthostatic hypotension results in a drop of 20 mm Hg systolic or more in blood pressure when rising from sitting position(110/60). 120 to 140 means the blood pressure increased rather than dropped. 126 to 120 is only a six points' difference. 140 to 130 is only a 10 points' difference.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe how to assess patients for activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is teaching a patient how to use a cane. Which information will the nurse include in the teaching session?",
            "options": [
              "Place the cane at the top of the hip bone.",
              "Place the cane on the stronger side of the body.",
              "Place the cane in front of the body and then move the good leg.",
              "Place the cane 10 to 15 inches in front of the body when walking."
            ],
            "answer": "Place the cane on the stronger side of the body.",
            "explanation": "Have the patient keep the cane on the stronger side of the body. A person's cane length is equal to the distance between the greater trochanter and the floor. The cane should be moved first and then the weaker leg. For maximum support when walking, the patient places the cane forward 15 to 25 cm (6 to 10 inches), keeping body weight on both legs. The weaker leg is then moved forward to the cane, so body weight is divided between the cane and the stronger leg.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe equipment needed for safe patient handling and movement.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assisting the patient to perform isometric exercises. Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Encourage wearing tight shoes.",
              "Set the pace for the exercise session.",
              "Stop the exercise if pain is experienced.",
              "Force muscles or joints to go just beyond resistance."
            ],
            "answer": "Stop the exercise if pain is experienced.",
            "explanation": "Instruct the patient to stop the activity if pain, fatigue, or discomfort is experienced. Assess for pain, shortness of breath, or a change in vital signs; if present, stop the exercise. Let each patient move at his or her own pace. Assess for joint limitations, and do not force a muscle or a joint during exercise. Teach patient to wear comfortable shoes and clothing for exercise.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the evidence that supports regular activity and exercise in patient care.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is developing a plan of care for a patient diagnosed with activity intolerance. Which strategy will the nurse use to provide the best chance of maintaining patient compliance?",
            "options": [
              "Performing 20 minutes of aerobic exercise 7 days a week with 10-minute warm-up and cool-down periods",
              "Instructing the patient to use an exercise log to record day, time, duration, and responses to exercise activity",
              "Stressing the harm of not exercising by getting the patient to take responsibility for current health status",
              "Arranging for the patient to join a gym that takes self-pay rather than insurance"
            ],
            "answer": "Instructing the patient to use an exercise log to record day, time, duration, and responses to exercise activity",
            "explanation": "Keeping a log may increase adherence to an exercise prescription. Recommended frequency of aerobic exercise is 3 to 5 times per week or every other day for approximately 30 minutes. Focusing on the harm of not exercising is usually counterproductive.Instead, the nurse should instruct the patient about the physiological benefits of a regular exercise program. Developing a plan of exercise that the patient may perform at home may improve compliance.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Develop an individualized nursing care plan for a patient with activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is preparing to transfer an uncooperative patient who does not have upper body strength. Which piece of equipment will be best for the nurses to obtain?",
            "options": [
              "Drawsheet",
              "Full body sling",
              "Overhead trapeze",
              "Friction-reducing slide sheet"
            ],
            "answer": "Full body sling",
            "explanation": "Using a mechanical lift and full body sling to transfer an uncooperative patient who can bear partial weight or a patient who cannot bear weight and is either uncooperative or does not have upper body strength to move from bed to chair prevents musculoskeletal injuries to health care workers. The nurse should not attempt to move the patient with a drawsheet. The patient does not have upper body strength, so an overhead trapeze is not appropriate. A friction-reducing slide sheet that minimizes shearing forces is not as effective as a full body sling.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe equipment needed for safe patient handling and movement.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is teaching a patient how to sit with crutches. In which order will the nurse present the instructions starting with the first step?\n\n1. Place both crutches in one hand.\n2. Grasp arm of chair with free hand.\n3. Completely lower self into chair.\n4. Transfer weight to crutches and unaffected leg.",
            "options": [
              "4, 1, 2, 3",
              "1, 4, 2, 3",
              "1, 2, 4, 3",
              "4, 2, 1, 3"
            ],
            "answer": "1, 4, 2, 3",
            "explanation": "A patient is sitting in a chair with crutches. Both crutches are held in one hand. The patient then transfers weight to the crutches and the unaffected leg. Next, the patient grasps the arm of the chair with the free hand and begins to lower self into chair. Finally, the patient completely lowers self into chair.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Develop an individualized nursing care plan for a patient with activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning ",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a group of patients. Which patient will the nurse see first?",
            "options": [
              "A patient with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease doing stretching exercises",
              "A patient with diabetes mellitus carrying hard candy while doing exercises",
              "A patient with a heart attack doing isometric exercises",
              "A patient with hypertension doing Tai Chi exercises"
            ],
            "answer": "A patient with a heart attack doing isometric exercises",
            "explanation": "The nurse must see the myocardial infarction patient first to stop this type of exercise. It is important to understand the energy expenditure (increased respiratory rate and increased work on the heart) associated with isometric exercises because the exercises are sometimes contraindicated in certain patients' illnesses (e.g., myocardial infarction or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease).All the rest are appropriate. Stretching exercises are beneficial for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Also instruct patients to perform low- to moderate-intensity exercises, carry a concentrated form of carbohydrates (sugar packets or hard candy), and wear a medical alert bracelet. The effect of a Tai Chi exercise program has demonstrated a significant reduction in systolic and diastolic blood pressures.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Describe important factors to consider when planning an exercise program for patients across the life span and for those with specific",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to move a patient who is able to assist. Which principles will the nurse consider when planning for safe patient handling? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Keep the body's center of gravity high.",
              "Face the direction of the movement.",
              "Keep the base of support narrow.",
              "Use the under-axilla technique.",
              "Use proper body mechanics.",
              "Use arms and legs."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Face the direction of the movement.",
                "Use proper body mechanics.",
                "Use arms and legs."
            ],
            "explanation": "When a patient is able to assist, remember the following principles: The wider the base of support, the greater the stability of the nurse; the lower the center of gravity, the greater the stability of the nurse; facing the direction of movement prevents abnormal twisting of the spine. The use of assistive equipment and continued use of proper body mechanics significantly reduces the risk of musculoskeletal injuries. Use arms and legs (not back) because the leg muscles are stronger, larger muscles capable of greater work without injury. The under-axilla technique is physically stressful for nurses and uncomfortable for patients.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the impact of national patient safety resources, initiatives, and regulations in relation to patient handling and movement.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing activity tolerance of a patient. Which areas will the nurse assess? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Skeletal abnormalities",
              "Emotional factors",
              "Pregnancy status",
              "Race",
              "Age"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Skeletal abnormalities",
                "Emotional factors",
                "Pregnancy status",
                "Age"
            ],
            "explanation": "Physiological, emotional, and developmental factors (age) influence the patient's activity tolerance. Factors influencing activity tolerance include physiological factors such as skeletal abnormalities, emotional factors such as anxiety/depression, developmental factors such as age and gender, and pregnancy status. Race is not a factor because people of all races are faced with similar factors that affect their activity tolerance.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe how to assess patients for activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is working in a facility that uses no-lift policies. Which benefits will the nurse observe in the facility? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Reduced number of work-related injuries",
              "Increased musculoskeletal accidents",
              "Reduced safety of patients",
              "Improved health of nurses",
              "Increased indirect costs"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Reduced number of work-related injuries",
                "Improved health of nurses"
            ],
            "explanation": "Implementing evidence-based interventions and programs (e.g., lift teams) reduces the number of work-related injuries, which improves the health of the nurse and reduces indirect costs to the health care facility (e.g., workers' compensation and replacing injured workers). Knowing the movements and functions of muscles in maintaining posture and movement and implementing evidence-based knowledge about safe patient handling are essential to protecting the safety of both the patient and the nurse.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the importance of no-lift policies for patients and health care providers.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse writes the following outcomes for a patient who has chronic obstructive pulmonary disease to improve activity level: Diastolic blood pressure will remain below 70 mm Hg with systolic below 130 mm Hg. Resting heart rate will range between 65 and 75. The last goal is that the patient will exercise 3 times a week. Which evaluative findings indicate successful goal achievement? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Resting heart rate 70",
              "Blood pressure 126/64",
              "Blood pressure 140/90",
              "Reports doing stretching and flexibility exercises 2 times this week",
              "Reports doing resistive training 1 time and aerobics 2 times this week"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Resting heart rate 70",
                "Blood pressure 126/64",
                "Reports doing resistive training 1 time and aerobics 2 times this week"
            ],
            "explanation": "Compare actual outcomes with expected outcomes to determine the patient's health status and progression. Heart rate of 70 is between 65 and 75. Blood pressure 126/64 meets the goal. Did resistive training 1 time and aerobics 2 times equals exercising 3 times a week. Did stretching and flexibility exercises 2 times is below the 3 times a week. Blood pressure 140/90 is too high and does not meet the goal.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Evaluate the nursing care plan for maintaining activity and exercise for patients across the life span and with specific chronic illnesses.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A 55 year-old patient is preparing to start an exercise program. The health care provider wants 60% of maximum target heart rate. Calculate the heart rate that the nurse will add to the care plan as the target heart rate. Record answer as a whole number. _________ maximum heart rate",
            "options": [
                "95",
                "101",
                "99",
                "97"
            ],
            "answer": "99",
            "explanation": "Teach patients to calculate their maximum heart rate by subtracting their current age in years from 220 and then obtaining their target heart rate by taking 60% to 90% of the maximum, depending on their health care provider's recommendation. 220 x 55 = 165 x 0.6 = 99.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop an individualized nursing care plan for a patient with activity intolerance.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          }
    ],
    "chapter39": [
        {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing body alignment. What is the nurse monitoring?",
            "options": [
              "The relationship of one body part to another while in different positions",
              "The coordinated efforts of the musculoskeletal and nervous systems",
              "The force that occurs in a direction to oppose movement",
              "The inability to move about freely"
            ],
            "answer": "The relationship of one body part to another while in different positions",
            "explanation": "The terms body alignment and posture are similar and refer to the positioning of the joints, tendons, ligaments, and muscles while standing, sitting, and lying. Body alignment means that the individual's center of gravity is stable. Body mechanics is a term used to describe the coordinated efforts of the musculoskeletal and nervous systems. Friction is a force that occurs in a direction to oppose movement. Immobility is the inability to move about freely.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss physiological and pathological influences on mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is providing range of motion to the shoulder and must perform external rotation. Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Moves patient's arm in a full circle.",
              "Moves patient's arm cross the body as far as possible.",
              "Moves patient's arm behind body, keeping elbow straight.",
              "Moves patient's arm until thumb is upward and lateral to head with elbow flexed."
            ],
            "answer": "Moves patient's arm until thumb is upward and lateral to head with elbow flexed.",
            "explanation": "External rotation: With elbow flexed, move arm until thumb is upward and lateral to head. Circumduction: Move arm in full circle (Circumduction is combination of all movements of ball-and-socket joint.) Adduction: Lower arm sideways and across body as far as possible. Hyperextension: Move arm behind body, keeping elbow straight.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast active and passive range-of-motion exercises.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is providing passive range of motion (ROM) for a patient with impaired mobility. Which technique will the nurse use for each movement?",
            "options": [
              "Each movement is repeated 5 times by the patient.",
              "Each movement is performed until the patient reports pain.",
              "Each movement is completed quickly and smoothly by the nurse.",
              "Each movement is moved just to the point of resistance by the nurse."
            ],
            "answer": "Each movement is moved just to the point of resistance by the nurse.",
            "explanation": "Passive ROM exercises are performed by the nurse. Carry out movements slowly and smoothly, just to the point of resistance; ROM should not cause pain. Never force a joint beyond its capacity. Each movement needs to be repeated 5 times during the session. The patient moves all joints through ROM unassisted in active ROM.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast active and passive range-of-motion exercises.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is performing passive range of motion (ROM) and splinting on an at-risk patient. The absence of which finding will indicate goal achievement for the nurse's action?",
            "options": [
              "Atelectasis",
              "Renal calculi",
              "Pressure ulcers",
              "Joint contractures"
            ],
            "answer": "Joint contractures",
            "explanation": "Goal achievement for passive ROM is prevention of joint contractures. Contractures develop in joints not moved periodically through their full ROM. ROM exercises reduce the risk of contractures. Researchers noted that prompt use of splinting with prescribed ROM exercises reduced contractures and improved active range of joint motion in affected lower extremities. Deep breathing and coughing and using an incentive spirometer will help prevent atelectasis. Adequate hydration helps prevent renal calculi and urinary tract infections. Interventions aimed at prevention of pressure ulcers include positioning, skin care, and the use of therapeutic devices to relieve pressure.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Evaluate patient outcomes as a result of a nursing plan for improving or maintaining mobility.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient requires repositioning every 2 hours. Which task can the nurse delegate to the nursing assistive personnel?",
            "options": [
              "Determining the level of comfort",
              "Changing the patient's position",
              "Identifying immobility hazards",
              "Assessing circulation"
            ],
            "answer": "Changing the patient's position",
            "explanation": "The skill of moving and positioning patients in bed can be delegated to nursing assistive personnel (NAP). The nurse is responsible for assessing the patient's level of comfort and for any hazards of immobility and assessing circulation.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing to assess a patient for orthostatic hypotension. Which piece of equipment will the nurse obtain to assess for this condition?",
            "options": [
              "Thermometer",
              "Elastic stockings",
              "Blood pressure cuff",
              "Sequential compression devices"
            ],
            "answer": "Blood pressure cuff",
            "explanation": "A blood pressure cuff is needed. Orthostatic hypotension is a drop of blood pressure greater than 20 mm Hg in systolic pressure or 10 mm Hg in diastolic pressure and symptoms of dizziness, light-headedness, nausea, tachycardia, pallor, or fainting when the patient changes from the supine to standing position. A thermometer is used to assess for fever. Elastic stockings and sequential compression devices are used to prevent thrombus.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify changes in physiological and psychosocial function associated with immobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient has been in bed for several days and needs to be ambulated. Which action will the nurse take first?",
            "options": [
              "Maintain a narrow base of support.",
              "Dangle the patient at the bedside.",
              "Encourage isometric exercises.",
              "Suggest a high-calcium diet."
            ],
            "answer": "Dangle the patient at the bedside.",
            "explanation": "To prevent injury, nurses implement interventions that reduce or eliminate the effects of orthostatic hypotension. Mobilize the patient as soon as the physical condition allows, even if this only involves dangling at the bedside or moving to a chair. A wide base of support increases balance. Isometric exercises (i.e., activities that involve muscle tension without muscle shortening) have no beneficial effect on preventing orthostatic hypotension, but they improve activity tolerance. A high-calcium diet can help with osteoporosis but can be detrimental in an immobile patient.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse reviews an immobilized patient's laboratory results and discovers hypercalcemia. Which condition will the nurse monitor for most closely in this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Hypostatic pneumonia",
              "Renal stones",
              "Pressure ulcers",
              "Thrombus formation"
            ],
            "answer": "Renal stones",
            "explanation": "Renal calculi are calcium stones that lodge in the renal pelvis or pass through the ureters. Immobilized patients are at risk for calculi because they frequently have hypercalcemia. Hypercalcemia does not lead to hypostatic pneumonia, pressure ulcers, or thrombus formation. Immobility is one cause of hypostatic pneumonia, which is inflammation of the lung from stasis or pooling of secretions. A pressure ulcer is an impairment of the skin that results from prolonged ischemia (decreased blood supply) within tissues. A thrombus is an accumulation of platelets, fibrin, clotting factors, and cellular elements of the blood attached to the interior wall of a vein or artery, which sometimes occludes the lumen of the vessel.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify changes in physiological and psychosocial function associated with immobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is caring for an older, immobile patient whose condition requires a supine position. Which metabolic alteration will the nurse monitor for in this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Increased appetite",
              "Increased diarrhea",
              "Increased metabolic rate",
              "Increased pulse rate"
            ],
            "answer": "Increased pulse rate",
            "explanation": "Lying down increases cardiac workload and results in an increased pulse rate. In older adults, the heart rate often does not tolerate the added workload, and a form of cardiac failure may develop. Immobility disrupts normal metabolic functioning: decreasing the metabolic rate, altering the metabolism of carbohydrates, fats, and proteins; causing fluid, electrolyte, and calcium imbalances; and causing gastrointestinal disturbances such as decreased appetite and slowing of peristalsis, leading to constipation.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify changes in physiological and psychosocial function associated with immobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is preparing a care plan for a patient who is immobile. Which psychosocial aspect will the nurse assess for?",
            "options": [
              "Loss of bone mass",
              "Loss of strength",
              "Loss of weight",
              "Loss of hope"
            ],
            "answer": "Loss of hope",
            "explanation": "Loss of hope is a psychosocial aspect. Patients with restricted mobility may have some depression. Depression is an affective disorder characterized by exaggerated feelings of sadness, melancholy, dejection, worthlessness, emptiness, and hopelessness out of proportion to reality. All the rest are physiological aspects: bone mass, strength, and weight.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify changes in physiological and psychosocial function associated with immobility.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is preparing to lift and reposition a patient. Which action will the nurse take first?",
            "options": [
              "Position a drawsheet under the patient.",
              "Assess weight to determine assistance needs.",
              "Delegate the task to a nursing assistive personnel.",
              "Attempt to manually lift the patient alone before asking for assistance."
            ],
            "answer": "Assess weight to determine assistance needs.",
            "explanation": "When lifting, assess the weight you will lift, and determine the assistance you will need. The nurse has to assess before positioning a drawsheet or delegating the task. Manual lifting is the last resort, and it is used when the task at hand does not involve lifting most or all of the patient's weight; most facilities have a no-lift policy.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for an older-adult patient who has been diagnosed with a stroke. Which intervention will the nurse add to the care plan?",
            "options": [
              "Encourage the patient to perform as many self-care activities as possible.",
              "Provide a complete bed bath to promote patient comfort.",
              "Coordinate with occupational therapy for gait training.",
              "Place the patient on bed rest to prevent fatigue."
            ],
            "answer": "Encourage the patient to perform as many self-care activities as possible.",
            "explanation": "Nurses should encourage the older-adult patient to perform as many self-care activities as possible, thereby maintaining the highest level of mobility. Sometimes nurses inadvertently contribute to a patient's immobility by providing unnecessary help with activities such as bathing and transferring. Placing the patient on bed rest without sufficient ambulation leads to loss of mobility and functional decline, resulting in weakness, fatigue, and increased risk for falls. After a stroke or brain attack, a patient likely receives gait training from a physical therapist; speech rehabilitation from a speech therapist; and help from an occupational therapist for ADLs such as dressing, bathing and toileting, or household chores.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is observing the way a patient walks. Which aspect is the nurse assessing?",
            "options": [
              "Activity tolerance",
              "Body alignment",
              "Range of motion",
              "Gait"
            ],
            "answer": "Gait",
            "explanation": "Gait describes a particular manner or style of walking. Activity tolerance is the type and amount of exercise or work that a person is able to perform. Body alignment refers to the position of the joints, tendons, ligaments, and muscles while standing, sitting, and lying. Range of motion is the maximum amount of movement available at a joint in one of the three planes of the body: sagittal, frontal, or transverse.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing the body alignment of a standing patient. Which finding will the nurse report as normal?",
            "options": [
              "When observed laterally, the spinal curves align in a reversed “S” pattern.",
              "When observed posteriorly, the hips and shoulders form an “S” pattern.",
              "The arms should be crossed over the chest or in the lap.",
              "The feet should be close together with toes pointed out."
            ],
            "answer": "When observed laterally, the spinal curves align in a reversed “S” pattern.",
            "explanation": "When the patient is observed laterally, the head is erect, and the spinal curves are aligned in a reversed “S” pattern. When observed posteriorly, the shoulders and hips are straight and parallel. The arms hang comfortably at the sides. The feet are slightly apart to achieve a base of support, and the toes are pointed forward.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is evaluating the body alignment of a patient in the sitting position. Which observation by the nurse will indicate a normal finding?",
            "options": [
              "The edge of the seat is in contact with the popliteal space.",
              "Both feet are supported on the floor with ankles flexed.",
              "The body weight is directly on the buttocks only.",
              "The arms hang comfortably at the sides."
            ],
            "answer": "Both feet are supported on the floor with ankles flexed.",
            "explanation": "Both feet are supported on the floor, and the ankles are comfortably flexed. Body weight is evenly distributed on the buttocks and thighs. A 1- to 2-inch space is maintained between the edge of the seat and the popliteal space on the posterior surface of the knee to ensure that no pressure is placed on the popliteal artery or nerve. The patient's forearms are supported on the armrest, in the lap, or on a table in front of the chair.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is assessing body alignment for a patient who is immobilized. Which patient position will the nurse use?",
            "options": [
              "Supine position",
              "Lateral position",
              "Lateral position with positioning supports",
              "Supine position with no pillow under the patient's head"
            ],
            "answer": "Lateral position",
            "explanation": "Assess body alignment for a patient who is immobilized or bedridden with the patient in the lateral position, not supine. Remove all positioning supports from the bed except for the pillow under the head and support the body with an adequate mattress.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is assessing the patient for respiratory complications of immobility. Which action will the nurse take when assessing the respiratory system?",
            "options": [
              "Inspect chest wall movements primarily during the expiratory cycle.",
              "Auscultate the entire lung region to assess lung sounds.",
              "Focus auscultation on the upper lung fields.",
              "Assess the patient at least every 4 hours."
            ],
            "answer": "Auscultate the entire lung region to assess lung sounds.",
            "explanation": "Auscultate the entire lung region to identify diminished breath sounds, crackles, or wheezes. Perform a respiratory assessment at least every 2 hours for patients with restricted activity. Inspect chest wall movements during the full inspiratory-expiratory cycle. Focus auscultation on the dependent lung fields because pulmonary secretions tend to collect in these lower regions.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is assessing an immobile patient for deep vein thromboses (DVTs). Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Remove elastic stockings every 4 hours.",
              "Measure the calf circumference of both legs.",
              "Lightly rub the lower leg for redness and tenderness.",
              "Dorsiflex the foot while assessing for patient discomfort."
            ],
            "answer": "Measure the calf circumference of both legs.",
            "explanation": "Measure bilateral calf circumference and record it daily as an assessment for DVT. Unilateral increases in calf circumference are an early indication of thrombosis. Homan's sign, or calf pain on dorsiflexion of the foot, is no longer a reliable indicator in assessing for DVT, and it is present in other conditions. Remove the patient's elastic stockings and/or sequential compression devices (SCDs) every 8 hours, and observe the calves for redness, warmth, and tenderness. Instruct the family, patient, and all health care personnel not to massage the area because of the danger of dislodging the thrombus.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing the skin of an immobilized patient. What will the nurse do?",
            "options": [
              "Assess the skin every 4 hours.",
              "Limit the amount of fluid intake.",
              "Use a standardized tool such as the Braden Scale.",
              "Have special times for inspection so as to not interrupt routine care."
            ],
            "answer": "Use a standardized tool such as the Braden Scale.",
            "explanation": "Consistently use a standardized tool, such as the Braden Scale. This identifies patients with a high risk for impaired skin integrity. Skin assessment can be as often as every hour. Limiting fluids can lead to dehydration, increasing skin breakdown. Observe the skin often during routine care.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for an older-adult patient with a diagnosis of urinary tract infection (UTI). Upon assessment the nurse finds the patient confused and agitated. How will the nurse interpret these assessment findings?",
            "options": [
              "These are normal signs of aging.",
              "These are early signs of dementia.",
              "These are purely psychological in origin.",
              "These are common manifestation with UTIs."
            ],
            "answer": "These are common manifestation with UTIs.",
            "explanation": "The primary symptom of compromised older patients with an acute urinary tract infection or fever is confusion. Acute confusion in older adults is not normal; a thorough nursing assessment is the priority. With the diagnosis of urinary tract infection, these are not early signs of dementia and they are not purely psychological.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify changes in physiological and psychosocial function associated with immobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient has damage to the cerebellum. Which disorder is most important for the nurse to assess?",
            "options": [
              "Impaired balance",
              "Hemiplegia",
              "Muscle sprain",
              "Lower extremity paralysis"
            ],
            "answer": "Impaired balance",
            "explanation": "Damage to the cerebellum causes problems with balance, and motor impairment is directly related to the amount of destruction of the motor strip. A stroke can lead to hemiplegia. Direct trauma to the musculoskeletal system results in bruises, contusions, sprains, and fractures. A complete transection of the spinal cord can lead to lower extremity paralysis.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss physiological and pathological influences on mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which patient will cause the nurse to select a nursing diagnosis of Impaired physical mobility for a care plan?",
            "options": [
              "A patient who is completely immobile",
              "A patient who is not completely immobile",
              "A patient at risk for single-system involvement",
              "A patient who is at risk for multisystem problems"
            ],
            "answer": "A patient who is not completely immobile",
            "explanation": "The diagnosis of Impaired physical mobility applies to the patient who has some limitation but is not completely immobile. The diagnosis of Risk for disuse syndrome applies to the patient who is immobile and at risk for multisystem problems because of inactivity. Beyond these diagnoses, the list of potential diagnoses is extensive because immobility affects multiple body systems.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Formulate appropriate nursing diagnoses for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Diagnosis",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient has the nursing diagnosis of Impaired physical mobility related to pain in the left shoulder. Which priority action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Encourage the patient to do self-care.",
              "Keep the patient as mobile as possible.",
              "Encourage the patient to perform ROM.",
              "Assist the patient with comfort measures."
            ],
            "answer": "Assist the patient with comfort measures.",
            "explanation": "The diagnosis related to pain requires the nurse to assist the patient with comfort measures so that the patient is then willing and more able to move. Pain must be controlled so the patient will not be reluctant to initiate movement. The diagnosis related to reluctance to initiate movement requires interventions aimed at keeping the patient as mobile as possible and encouraging the patient to perform self-care and ROM.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is developing an individualized plan of care for a patient. Which action is important for the nurse to take?",
            "options": [
              "Establish goals that are measurable and realistic.",
              "Set goals that are a little beyond the capabilities of the patient.",
              "Use the nurse's own judgment and not be swayed by family desires.",
              "Explain that without taking alignment risks, there can be no progress."
            ],
            "answer": "Establish goals that are measurable and realistic.",
            "explanation": "The nurse must develop an individualized plan of care for each nursing diagnosis and must set goals that are individualized, realistic, and measurable. The nurse should set realistic expectations for care and should include the patient and family when possible. The goals focus on preventing problems or risks to body alignment and mobility.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which behavior indicates the nurse is using a team approach when caring for a patient who is experiencing alterations in mobility?",
            "options": [
              "Delegates assessment of lung sounds to nursing assistive personnel",
              "Becomes solely responsible for modifying activities of daily living",
              "Consults physical therapy for strengthening exercises in the extremities",
              "Involves respiratory therapy for altered breathing from severe anxiety levels"
            ],
            "answer": "Consults physical therapy for strengthening exercises in the extremities",
            "explanation": "The nurse should collaborate with other health care team members such as physical or occupational therapists when considering mobility needs. For example, physical therapists are a resource for planning ROM or strengthening exercises. Nurses often delegate some interventions to nursing assistive personnel, but assessment of lung sounds is the nurse's responsibility. Nursing assistive personnel may turn and position patients, apply elastic stockings, help patients use the incentive spirometer, etc. Occupational therapists are a resource for planning activities of daily living that patients need to modify or relearn. A mental health advanced practice nurse or psychologist should be used for severe anxiety.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is being admitted to the neurological unit with a diagnosis of stroke. When will the nurse begin discharge planning?",
            "options": [
              "At the time of admission",
              "The day before the patient is to be discharged",
              "When outpatient therapy will no longer be needed",
              "As soon as the patient's discharge destination is known"
            ],
            "answer": "At the time of admission",
            "explanation": "Discharge planning begins when a patient enters the health care system. In anticipation of the patient's discharge from an institution, the nurse makes appropriate referrals or consults a case manager or a discharge planner to ensure that the patient's needs are met at home. Referrals to home care or outpatient therapy are often needed. Planning the day before discharge, when outpatient therapy is no longer needed, and as soon as the discharge destination is known is too late.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which goal is most appropriate for a patient who has had a total hip replacement?",
            "options": [
              "The patient will ambulate briskly on the treadmill by the time of discharge.",
              "The patient will walk 100 feet using a walker by the time of discharge.",
              "The nurse will assist the patient to ambulate in the hall 2 times a day.",
              "The patient will ambulate by the time of discharge."
            ],
            "answer": "The patient will walk 100 feet using a walker by the time of discharge.",
            "explanation": "“The patient will walk 100 feet using a walker by the time of discharge” is individualized, realistic, and measurable. “Ambulating briskly on a treadmill” is not realistic for this patient. The option that focuses on the nurse, not the patient, is not a measurable goal; this is an intervention. “The patient will ambulate by the time of discharge” is not measurable because it does not specify the distance. Even though we can see that the patient will ambulate, this does not quantify how far.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is working on an orthopedic rehabilitation unit that requires lifting and positioning of patients. Which personal injury will the nurse most likely try to prevent?",
            "options": [
              "Arm",
              "Hip",
              "Back",
              "Ankle"
            ],
            "answer": "Back",
            "explanation": "Back injuries are often the direct result of improper lifting and bending. The most common back injury is strain on the lumbar muscle group. While arm, hip, and ankle can occur, they are not as common as back.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient diagnosed with osteoporosis and lactose intolerance. What intervention will the nurse implement?",
            "options": [
              "Encourage dairy products.",
              "Monitor intake of vitamin D.",
              "Increase intake of caffeinated drinks.",
              "Try to do as much as possible for the patient."
            ],
            "answer": "Monitor intake of vitamin D.",
            "explanation": "Encourage patients at risk to be screened for osteoporosis and assess their diets for calcium and vitamin D intake. Patients who have lactose intolerance need dietary teaching about alternative sources of calcium. Caffeine should be decreased. The goal of the patient with osteoporosis is to maintain independence with ADLs. Assistive ambulatory devices, adaptive clothing, and safety bars help the patient maintain independence.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is providing care to a group of patients. Which patient will the nurse see first?",
            "options": [
              "A patient with a hip replacement on prolonged bed rest reporting chest pain and dyspnea",
              "A bedridden patient who has a reddened area on the buttocks who needs to be turned",
              "A patient on bed rest who has renal calculi and needs to go to the bathroom",
              "A patient after knee surgery who needs range of motion exercises"
            ],
            "answer": "A patient with a hip replacement on prolonged bed rest reporting chest pain and dyspnea",
            "explanation": "A patient on prolonged bed rest will be prone to deep vein thrombosis, which can lead to an embolus. An embolus can travel through the circulatory system to the lungs and impair circulation and oxygenation, resulting in tachycardia and shortness of breath. Venous emboli that travel to the lungs are sometimes life threatening. While the patient with a reddened area needs to be turned, a patient with renal calculi needing the restroom, and a patient needing range of motion, these are not as life threatening as the chest pain and dyspnea.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is immobilized after undergoing hip replacement surgery. Which finding will alert the nurse to monitor for hemorrhage in this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Thick, tenacious pulmonary secretions",
              "Low-molecular-weight heparin doses",
              "SCDs wrapped around the legs",
              "Elastic stockings (TED hose)"
            ],
            "answer": "Low-molecular-weight heparin doses",
            "explanation": "Heparin and low-molecular-weight heparin are the most widely used drugs in the prophylaxis of deep vein thrombosis. Because bleeding is a potential side effect of these medications, continually assess the patient for signs of bleeding. Pulmonary secretions that become thick and tenacious are difficult to remove and are a sign of inadequate hydration or developing pneumonia but not of bleeding. SCDs consist of sleeves or stockings made of fabric or plastic that are wrapped around the leg and are secured with Velcro. They decrease venous stasis by increasing venous return through the deep veins of the legs. They do not usually cause bleeding. Elastic stockings also aid in maintaining external pressure on the muscles of the lower extremities and in promoting venous return. They do not usually cause bleeding.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse needs to move a patient up in bed using a drawsheet. The nurse has another nurse helping. In which order will the nurses perform the steps, beginning with the first one?\n\n1. Grasp the drawsheet firmly near the patient.\n2. Move the patient and drawsheet to the desired position.\n3. Position one nurse at each side of the bed.\n4. Place the drawsheet under the patient from shoulder to thigh.\n5. Place your feet apart with a forward-backward stance.\n6. Flex knees and hips and on the count of three shift weight from the front to back leg.",
            "options": [
              "1, 4, 5, 6, 3, 2",
              "4, 1, 3, 5, 6, 2",
              "3, 4, 1, 5, 6, 2",
              "5, 6, 3, 1, 4, 2"
            ],
            "answer": "3, 4, 1, 5, 6, 2",
            "explanation": "Assisting a patient up in bed with a drawsheet (two or three nurses): (1) Place the patient supine with the head of the bed flat. A nurse stands on each side of the bed. (2) Remove the pillow from under the patient's head and shoulders and place it at the head of the bed. (3) Turn the patient side to side to place the drawsheet under the patient, extending it from shoulders to thighs. (4) Return the patient to the supine position. (5) Fanfold the drawsheet on both sides, with each nurse grasping firmly near the patient. (6) Nurses place their feet apart with a forward-backward stance. Nurses should flex knees and hips. On the count of three, nurses should shift their weight from front to back leg and move the patient and drawsheet to the desired position in the bed.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who needs to be placed in the prone position. Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Place pillow under the patient's lower legs.",
              "Turn head toward one side with large, soft pillow.",
              "Position legs flat against bed.",
              "Raise head of bed to 45 degrees."
            ],
            "answer": "Place pillow under the patient's lower legs.",
            "explanation": "Placing a pillow under the lower leg permits dorsiflexion of the ankles and some knee flexion, which promote relaxation. Head is turned toward one side with a small pillow to reduce flexion or hyperextension of cervical vertebrae. Legs should be supported with pillows to elevate toes and prevent footdrop. Forty-five degrees is the position for Fowler's position; prone is on the stomach.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with a spinal cord injury and notices that the patient's hips have a tendency to rotate externally when the patient is supine. Which device will the nurse use to help prevent injury secondary to this rotation?",
            "options": [
              "Hand rolls",
              "A trapeze bar",
              "A trochanter roll",
              "Hand-wrist splints"
            ],
            "answer": "A trochanter roll",
            "explanation": "A trochanter roll prevents external rotation of the hips when the patient is in a supine position. Hand rolls maintain the thumb in slight adduction and in opposition to the fingers. Hand-wrist splints are individually molded for the patient to maintain proper alignment of the thumb and the wrist. The trapeze bar is a triangular device that hangs down from a securely fastened overhead bar that is attached to the bedframe. It allows the patient to pull with the upper extremities to raise the trunk off the bed, to assist in transfer from bed to wheelchair, or to perform upper arm exercises.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is unable to move self and needs to be pulled up in bed. What will the nurse do to make this procedure safe?",
            "options": [
              "Place the pillow under the patient's head and shoulders.",
              "Do by self if the bed is in the flat position.",
              "Place the side rails in the up position.",
              "Use a friction-reducing device."
            ],
            "answer": "Use a friction-reducing device.",
            "explanation": "This is not a one-person task. Helping a patient move up in bed without help from other co-workers or without the aid of an assistive device (e.g., friction-reducing pad) is not recommended and is not considered safe for the patient or the nurse. Remove the pillow from under head and shoulders and place it at the head of the bed to prevent striking the patient's head against the head of the bed. When pulling a patient up in bed, the bed should be flat to gain gravity assistance, and the side rails should be down.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who is immobile and needs to be turned every 2 hours. The patient has poor lower extremity circulation, and the nurse is concerned about irritation of the patient's toes. Which device will the nurse use?",
            "options": [
              "Hand rolls",
              "A foot cradle",
              "A trapeze bar",
              "A trochanter roll"
            ],
            "answer": "A foot cradle",
            "explanation": "A foot cradle may be used in patients with poor peripheral circulation as a means of reducing pressure on the tips of a patient's toes. A trochanter roll prevents external rotation of the hips when the patient is in a supine position. Hand rolls maintain the thumb in slight adduction and in opposition to the fingers. The trapeze bar is a triangular device that hangs down from a securely fastened overhead bar that is attached to the bedframe. It allows the patient to pull with the upper extremities to raise the trunk off the bed, to assist in transfer from bed to wheelchair, or to perform upper arm exercises.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse delegates a position change to a nursing assistive personnel. The nurse instructs the assistive personnel (AP) to place the patient in the lateral position. Which finding by the nurse indicates a correct outcome?",
            "options": [
              "Patient is lying on side.",
              "Patient is lying on back.",
              "Patient is lying semiprone.",
              "Patient is lying on abdomen."
            ],
            "answer": "Patient is lying on side.",
            "explanation": "In the side-lying (or lateral) position, the patient rests on the side with the major portion of body weight on the dependent hip and shoulder. Patients in the supine position rest on their backs. Sims' position is semiprone. The patient in the prone position lies face or chest down on the abdomen.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Evaluate patient outcomes as a result of a nursing plan for improving or maintaining mobility.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is evaluating care of an immobilized patient. Which action will the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Focus on whether the interdisciplinary team is satisfied with the care.",
              "Compare the patient's actual outcomes with the outcomes in the care plan.",
              "Involve primarily the patient's family and health care team to determine goal achievement.",
              "Use objective data solely in determining whether interventions have been successful."
            ],
            "answer": "Compare the patient's actual outcomes with the outcomes in the care plan.",
            "explanation": "From your perspective as the nurse, you are to evaluate outcomes and response to nursing care and compare the patient's actual outcomes with the outcomes selected during planning. Ask if the patient's expectations (subjective data) of care are being met and use objective data to determine the success of interventions. Just as it was important to include the patient during the assessment and planning phase of the care plan, it is essential to have the patient's evaluation of the plan of care, not just the patient's family and health care team.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Evaluate patient outcomes as a result of a nursing plan for improving or maintaining mobility.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is supervising the logrolling of a patient. To which patient is the nurse most likely providing care?",
            "options": [
              "A patient with neck surgery",
              "A patient with hypostatic pneumonia",
              "A patient with a total knee replacement",
              "A patient with a stage IV pressure ulcer"
            ],
            "answer": "A patient with neck surgery",
            "explanation": "A nurse supervises and aids personnel when there is a health care provider's order to logroll a patient. Patients who have suffered from spinal cord injury or are recovering from neck, back, or spinal surgery often need to keep the spinal column in straight alignment to prevent further injury. Hypostatic pneumonia, total knee replacement, and stage IV ulcers do not have to be logrolled.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is providing teaching to an immobilized patient with impaired skin integrity about diet. Which diet will the nurse recommend?",
            "options": [
              "High protein, high calorie",
              "High carbohydrate, low fat",
              "High vitamin A, high vitamin E",
              "Fluid restricted, bland"
            ],
            "answer": "High protein, high calorie",
            "explanation": "Because the body needs protein to repair injured tissue and rebuild depleted protein stores, give the immobilized patient a high-protein, high-calorie diet. A high-carbohydrate, low-fat diet is not beneficial for an immobilized patient. Vitamins B and C are needed rather than A and E. Fluid restriction can be detrimental to the immobilized patient; this can lead to dehydration. A bland diet is not necessary for immobilized patients.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has experienced a stroke causing total paralysis of the right side. To help maintain joint function and minimize the disability from contractures, passive range of motion (ROM) will be initiated. When should the nurse begin this therapy?",
            "options": [
              "After the acute phase of the disease has passed.",
              "As soon as the ability to move is lost.",
              "Once the patient enters the rehab unit.",
              "When the patient requests it."
            ],
            "answer": "As soon as the ability to move is lost.",
            "explanation": "Passive ROM exercises should begin as soon as the patient's ability to move the extremity or joint is lost. The nurse should not wait for the acute phase to end. It may be some time before the patient enters the rehab unit or the patient requests it, and contractures could form by then.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast active and passive range-of-motion exercises.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is admitting a patient who has been diagnosed as having had a stroke. The health care provider writes orders for “ROM as needed.” What should the nurse do next?",
            "options": [
              "Restrict patient's mobility as much as possible.",
              "Realize the patient is unable to move extremities.",
              "Move all the patient's extremities.",
              "Further assess the patient."
            ],
            "answer": "Further assess the patient.",
            "explanation": "Further assessment of the patient is needed to determine what the patient is able to perform. Some patients are able to move some joints actively, whereas the nurse passively moves others. With a weak patient, the nurse may have to support an extremity while the patient performs the movement. In general, exercises need to be as active as health and mobility allow.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Compare and contrast active and passive range-of-motion exercises.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is assessing pressure points in a patient placed in the Sims' position. Which areas will the nurse observe?",
            "options": [
              "Chin, elbow, hips",
              "Ileum, clavicle, humerus",
              "Shoulder, anterior iliac spine, ankles",
              "Occipital region of the head, coccyx, heels"
            ],
            "answer": "Ileum, clavicle, humerus",
            "explanation": "In the Sims' position, pressure points include the ileum, humerus, clavicle, knees, and ankles. The lateral position pressure points include the ear, shoulder, anterior iliac spine, and ankles. The prone position pressure points include the chin, elbows, female breasts, hips, knees, and toes. Supine position pressure points include the occipital region of the head, vertebrae, coccyx, elbows, and heels.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Assess for correct and impaired body alignment and mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient is admitted to a skilled care unit for rehabilitation after the surgical procedure of fixation of a fractured left hip. The patient's nursing diagnosis is Impaired physical mobility related to musculoskeletal impairment from surgery and pain with movement. The patient is able to use a walker but needs assistance ambulating and transferring from the bed to the chair. Which nursing intervention is most appropriate for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Obtain assistance and physically transfer the patient to the chair.",
              "Assist with ambulation and measure how far the patient walks.",
              "Give pain medication after ambulation so the patient will have a clear mind.",
              "Bring the patient to the cafeteria for group instruction on ambulation."
            ],
            "answer": "Assist with ambulation and measure how far the patient walks.",
            "explanation": "Assist with walking and measure how far the patient walks to quantify progress. The nurse should allow the patient to do as much for self as possible. Therefore, the nurse should observe the patient transferring from the bed to the chair using the walker and should provide assistance as needed. The patient should be encouraged to use adequate pain medication to decrease the effects of pain and to increase mobility. The patient should be instructed on safe transfer and ambulation techniques in an environment with few distractions, not in the cafeteria.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient has been diagnosed with a spinal cord injury and needs to be repositioned using the logrolling technique. Which technique will the nurse use for logrolling?",
            "options": [
              "Use at least three people.",
              "Have the patient reach for the opposite side rail when turning.",
              "Move the top part of the patient's torso and then the bottom part.",
              "Do not use pillows after turning."
            ],
            "answer": "Use at least three people.",
            "explanation": "At least three to four people are needed to perform this skill safely. Have the patient cross the arms on the chest to prevent injury to the arms. Move the patient as one unit in a smooth, continuous motion on the count of three. Gently lean the patient as a unit back toward pillows for support.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "Upon assessment a nurse discovers that a patient has erythema. Which actions will the nurse take? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Consult a dietitian.",
              "Increase fiber in the diet.",
              "Place on chest physiotherapy.",
              "Increase frequency of turning.",
              "Place on pressure-relieving mattress."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Consult a dietitian.",
                "Increase frequency of turning.",
                "Place on pressure-relieving mattress."
            ],
            "explanation": "If skin shows areas of erythema and breakdown, increase the frequency of turning and repositioning; place the turning schedule above the patient's bed; implement other activities per agency skin care policy or protocol (e.g., assess more frequently, consult dietitian, place patient on pressure-relieving mattress). Increased fiber will help constipation. Chest physiotherapy is for respiratory complications.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe interventions for improving or maintaining patients' mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with impaired physical mobility. Which potential complications will the nurse monitor for in this patient? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Footdrop",
              "Somnolence",
              "Hypostatic pneumonia",
              "Impaired skin integrity",
              "Increased socialization"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Footdrop",
                "Hypostatic pneumonia",
                "Impaired skin integrity"
            ],
            "explanation": "Immobility leads to complications such as hypostatic pneumonia. Other possible complications include footdrop and impaired skin integrity. Interruptions in the sleep-wake cycle and social isolation are more common complications than somnolence or increased socialization.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Identify changes in physiological and psychosocial function associated with immobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has experienced a recent stroke and is paralyzed on the left side. The patient has no respiratory or cardiac issues but cannot walk. The patient cannot button a shirt and cannot feed self-due to being left-handed and becomes frustrated very easily. The patient has been eating very little and has lost 2 lb. The patient asks the nurse, “How can I go home like this? I'm not getting better.” Which health care team members will the nurse need to consult? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Dietitian",
              "Physical therapist",
              "Respiratory therapist",
              "Cardiac rehabilitation therapist",
              "Occupational therapist",
              "Psychologist"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Dietitian",
                "Physical therapist",
                "Occupational therapist",
                "Psychologist"
            ],
            "explanation": "Physical therapists are a resource for planning ROM or strengthening exercises, and occupational therapists are a resource for planning ADLs that patients need to modify or relearn. Because of the loss of 2 lb and eating very little, a dietitian will also be helpful. Referral to a mental health advanced practice nurse, a licensed social worker, or a physiologist to assist with coping or other psychosocial issues is also wise. Because the patient exhibits good cardiac and respiratory function, respiratory therapy and cardiac rehabilitation probably are not needed at this time.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Develop individualized nursing care plans for patients with impaired mobility.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "Upon assessment a nurse discovers postural abnormalities on several patients. Match the abnormalities to the findings the nurse observed.",
            "matching": [
              "Lordosis",
              "Kyphosis",
              "Scoliosis",
              "Genu valgum",
              "Genu varum",
              "Torticollis"
            ],
            "options": [
              "Lateral-S- or C-shaped spinal column with vertebral rotation",
              "Legs curved inward so knees come together as person walks",
              "One or both legs bent outward at knee",
              "Inclining of head to affected side",
              "Exaggeration of anterior convex curve of lumbar spine",
              "Increased convexity in curvature of thoracic spine"
            ],
            "answer": {
              "Lordosis": "Exaggeration of anterior convex curve of lumbar spine",
              "Kyphosis": "Increased convexity in curvature of thoracic spine",
              "Scoliosis": "Lateral-S- or C-shaped spinal column with vertebral rotation",
              "Genu valgum": "Legs curved inward so knees come together as person walks",
              "Genu varum": "One or both legs bent outward at knee",
              "Torticollis": "Inclining of head to affected side"
            },
            "explanation": "Lordosis: This is an exaggeration of the natural inward curve of the lumbar spine, causing a swayback appearance.\nKyphosis: This refers to an increased outward curvature of the thoracic spine, leading to a rounded or hunched back.\nScoliosis: It's a condition where the spine curves sideways in an \"S\" or \"C\" shape, often with rotation of the vertebrae.\nGenu valgum: This describes a condition where the legs curve inward at the knees, causing them to come together as the person walks.\nGenu varum: In this condition, one or both legs are bent outward at the knee, causing a bow-legged appearance.\nTorticollis: It's the inclining of the head to one side due to tight muscles in the neck, limiting movement and causing discomfort.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss physiological and pathological influences on mobility.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          }
    ],
    "chapter41": [
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching staff about the conduction of the heart. In which order will the nurse present the conduction cycle, starting with the first structure? 1. Bundle of His 2. Purkinje network 3. Intraatrial pathways 4. Sinoatrial (SA) node 5. Atrioventricular (AV) node",
        "options": [
          "5, 4, 3, 2, 1",
          "4, 3, 5, 1, 2",
          "4, 5, 3, 1, 2",
          "5, 3, 4, 2, 1"
        ],
        "answer": "4, 3, 5, 1, 2",
        "explanation": "The conduction system originates with the SA node, the “pacemaker” of the heart. The electrical impulses are transmitted through the atria along intraatrial pathways to the AV node. It assists atrial emptying by delaying the impulse before transmitting it through the Bundle of His and the ventricular Purkinje network.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the structure and function of the cardiopulmonary system.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching the patient with mitral valve problems about the valves in the heart. Starting on the right side of the heart, describe the sequence of the blood flow through these valves. 1. Mitral 2. Aortic 3. Tricuspid 4. Pulmonic",
        "options": [
          "1, 3, 2, 4",
          "4, 3, 2, 1",
          "3, 4, 1, 2",
          "2, 4, 1, 3"
        ],
        "answer": "3, 4, 1, 2",
        "explanation": "The blood flows through the valves in the following direction: tricuspid, pulmonic, mitral, and aortic.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the structure and function of the cardiopulmonary system.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse explains the function of the alveoli to a patient with respiratory problems. Which information about the alveoli’s function will the nurse share with the patient?",
        "options": [
          "Carries out gas exchange.",
          "Regulates tidal volume.",
          "Produces hemoglobin.",
          "Stores oxygen."
        ],
        "answer": "Carries out gas exchange.",
        "explanation": "The alveolus is a capillary membrane that allows gas exchange of oxygen and carbon dioxide during respiration. The alveoli do not store oxygen, regulate tidal volume, or produce hemoglobin.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the physiological processes of ventilation, perfusion, and exchange of respiratory gases.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse auscultates heart sounds. When the nurse hears S2, which valves is the nurse hearing close?",
        "options": [
          "Aortic and mitral",
          "Mitral and tricuspid",
          "Aortic and pulmonic",
          "Mitral and pulmonic"
        ],
        "answer": "Aortic and pulmonic",
        "explanation": "As the ventricles empty, the ventricular pressures decrease, allowing closure of the aortic and pulmonic valves, producing the second heart sound, S2. The mitral and tricuspid produce the first heart sound, S1. The aortic and mitral do not close at the same time. The mitral and pulmonic do not close at the same time.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the structure and function of the cardiopulmonary system.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is teaching about the process of exchanging gases through the alveolar capillary membrane. Which term will the nurse use to describe this process?",
        "options": [
          "Ventilation",
          "Surfactant",
          "Perfusion",
          "Diffusion"
        ],
        "answer": "Diffusion",
        "explanation": "Diffusion is the process of gases exchanging across the alveoli and capillaries of body tissues. Ventilation is the process of moving gases into and out of the lungs. Surfactant is a chemical produced in the lungs to maintain the surface tension of the alveoli and keep them from collapsing. Perfusion is the ability of the cardiovascular system to carry oxygenated blood to tissues and return deoxygenated blood to the heart.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the physiological processes of ventilation, perfusion, and exchange of respiratory gases.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who was in a motor vehicle accident that resulted in cervical trauma to C4. Which assessment is the priority?",
        "options": [
          "Pulse",
          "Respirations",
          "Temperature",
          "Blood pressure"
        ],
        "answer": "Respirations",
        "explanation": "Respirations and oxygen saturation are the priorities. Cervical trauma at C3 to C5 usually results in paralysis of the phrenic nerve. When the phrenic nerve is damaged, the diaphragm does not descend properly, thus reducing inspiratory lung volumes and causing hypoxemia. While pulse and blood pressure are important, respirations are the priority. Temperature is not a high priority in this situation.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Assess for the risk factors affecting a patient’s oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is breathing normally. Which process does the nurse consider is working properly when the patient inspires?",
        "options": [
          "Stimulation of chemical receptors in the aorta",
          "Reduction of arterial oxygen saturation levels",
          "Requirement of elastic recoil lung properties",
          "Enhancement of accessory muscle usage"
        ],
        "answer": "Stimulation of chemical receptors in the aorta",
        "explanation": "Inspiration is an active process, stimulated by chemical receptors in the aorta. Reduced arterial oxygen saturation levels indicate hypoxemia, an abnormal finding. Expiration is a passive process that depends on the elastic recoil properties of the lungs, requiring little or no muscle work. Prolonged use of the accessory muscles does not promote effective ventilation and causes fatigue.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "State the process of the neural and chemical regulation of respiration.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The home health nurse recommends that a patient with respiratory problems install a carbon monoxide detector in the home. What is the rationale for the nurse’s action?",
        "options": [
          "Carbon monoxide detectors are required by law in the home.",
          "Carbon monoxide tightly binds to hemoglobin, causing hypoxia.",
          "Carbon monoxide signals the cerebral cortex to cease ventilations.",
          "Carbon monoxide combines with oxygen in the body and produces a deadly toxin."
        ],
        "answer": "Carbon monoxide tightly binds to hemoglobin, causing hypoxia.",
        "explanation": "Carbon monoxide binds tightly to hemoglobin; therefore, oxygen is not able to bind to hemoglobin and be transported to tissues, causing hypoxia. A carbon monoxide detector is not required by law, does not signal the cerebral cortex to cease ventilations, and does not combine with oxygen but with hemoglobin to produce a toxin.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "While performing an assessment, the nurse hears crackles in the patient’s lung fields. The nurse also learns that the patient is sleeping on three pillows to help with the difficulty breathing during the night. Which condition will the nurse most likely observe written in the patient’s medical record?",
        "options": [
          "Atrial fibrillation",
          "Myocardial ischemia",
          "Left-sided heart failure",
          "Right-sided heart failure"
        ],
        "answer": "Left-sided heart failure",
        "explanation": "Left-sided heart failure results in pulmonary congestion, the signs and symptoms of which include shortness of breath, cough, crackles, and paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea (difficulty breathing when lying flat). Right-sided heart failure is systemic and results in peripheral edema, weight gain, and distended neck veins. Atrial fibrillation is often described as an irregularly irregular rhythm; rhythm is irregular because of the multiple pacemaker sites. Myocardial ischemia results when the supply of blood to the myocardium from the coronary arteries is insufficient to meet myocardial oxygen demands, producing angina or myocardial infarction.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess for the physical manifestations that occur with alterations in oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has experienced a myocardial infarction. On which primary blood vessel will the nurse focus care to reduce ischemia?",
        "options": [
          "Superior vena cava",
          "Pulmonary artery",
          "Coronary artery",
          "Carotid artery"
        ],
        "answer": "Coronary artery",
        "explanation": "A myocardial infarction is the lack of blood flow due to obstruction to the coronary artery, which supplies the heart with blood. The superior vena cava returns blood back to the heart. The pulmonary artery supplies deoxygenated blood to the lungs. The carotid artery supplies blood to the brain.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Differentiate among the physiological processes of cardiac output, myocardial blood flow, and coronary artery circulatio n.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching a health class about the heart. Which information from the class members indicates teaching by the nurse is successful for the flow of blood through the heart, starting in the right atrium?",
        "options": [
          "Right ventricle, left ventricle, left atrium",
          "Left atrium, right ventricle, left ventricle",
          "Right ventricle, left atrium, left ventricle",
          "Left atrium, left ventricle, right ventricle"
        ],
        "answer": "Right ventricle, left atrium, left ventricle",
        "explanation": "Unoxygenated blood flows through the venae cavae into the right atrium, where it is pumped down to the right ventricle; the blood is then pumped out the pulmonary artery and is returned oxygenated via the pulmonary vein to the left atrium, where it flows to the left ventricle and is pumped out to the rest of the body via the aorta.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the structure and function of the cardiopulmonary system.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse suspects the patient has increased cardiac afterload. Which piece of equipment should the nurse obtain to determine the presence of this condition?",
        "options": [
          "Pulse oximeter",
          "Oxygen cannula",
          "Blood pressure cuff",
          "Yankauer suction tip catheter"
        ],
        "answer": "Blood pressure cuff",
        "explanation": "A blood pressure cuff is needed. The diastolic aortic pressure is a good clinical measure of afterload. Afterload is the resistance to left ventricular ejection. In hypertension the afterload increases, making cardiac workload also increase. A pulse oximeter is used to monitor the level of arterial oxygen saturation; it will not help determine increased afterload. While an oxygen cannula may be needed to help decrease the effects of increased afterload, it will not help determine the presence of afterload. A Yankauer suction tip catheter is used to suction the oral cavity.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe the relationship of cardiac output, preload, afterload, contractility, and heart rate to the process of oxygena tion.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has been diagnosed with heart failure and cardiac output is decreased. Which formula can the nurse use to calculate cardiac output?",
        "options": [
          "Myocardial contractility × myocardial blood flow",
          "Ventricular filling time/diastolic filling time",
          "Stroke volume × heart rate",
          "Preload/afterload"
        ],
        "answer": "Stroke volume × heart rate",
        "explanation": "Cardiac output can be calculated by multiplying the stroke volume and the heart rate. The other options are not measures of cardiac output.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Differentiate among the physiological processes of cardiac output, myocardial blood flow, and coronary artery circulatio n.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient’s heart rate increased from 94 to 164 beats/min. What will the nurse expect as a result?",
        "options": [
          "Increase in diastolic filling time",
          "Decrease in hemoglobin level",
          "Decrease in cardiac output",
          "Increase in stroke volume"
        ],
        "answer": "Decrease in cardiac output",
        "explanation": "With a sustained heart rate greater than 160 beats/min, diastolic filling time decreases, decreasing stroke volume, and cardiac output. The hemoglobin level would not be affected.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the relationship of cardiac output, preload, afterload, contractility, and heart rate to the process of oxygena tion.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which determination is the nurse trying to achieve by monitoring a patient’s cardiac output?",
        "options": [
          "Peripheral extremity circulation",
          "Oxygenation requirements",
          "Presence of cardiac dysrhythmias",
          "Ventilation status"
        ],
        "answer": "Peripheral extremity circulation",
        "explanation": "Cardiac output indicates how much blood is being circulated systemically throughout the body to the periphery. The amount of blood ejected from the left ventricle each minute is the cardiac output. Oxygen status would be determined by pulse oximetry and the presence of cyanosis. Cardiac dysrhythmias are an electrical impulse monitored through ECG results. Ventilation status is measured by respiratory rate, pulse oximetry, and capnography. Capnography provides instant information about the patient’s ventilation. Ventilation status does not depend solely on cardiac output.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the relationship of cardiac output, preload, afterload, contractility, and heart rate to the process of oxygena tion.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a group of patients. Which patient should the nurse see first?",
        "options": [
          "A patient with hypercapnia wearing an oxygen mask",
          "A patient with a chest tube ambulating with the chest tube unclamped",
          "A patient with thick secretions being tracheal suctioned first and then orally",
          "A patient with a new tracheostomy and tracheostomy obturator at bedside"
        ],
        "answer": "A patient with hypercapnia wearing an oxygen mask",
        "explanation": "The mask is contraindicated for patients with carbon dioxide retention (hypercapnia) because retention can be worsened; the nurse must see this patient first to correct the problem. All the rest are using correct procedures and do not need to be seen first. A chest tube should not be clamped when ambulating. Clamping a chest tube is contraindicated when ambulating or transporting a patient. Clamping can result in a tension pneumothorax. Use nasotracheal suctioning before pharyngeal suctioning whenever possible. The mouth and pharynx contain more bacteria than the trachea. Keep tracheostomy obturator at bedside with a fresh (new) tracheostomy to facilitate reinsertion of the outer cannula if dislodged.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Assess for the risk factors affecting a patient’s oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has inadequate stroke volume related to decreased preload. Which treatment does the nurse prepare to administer?",
        "options": [
          "Diuretics",
          "Vasodilators",
          "Chest physiotherapy",
          "Intravenous (IV) fluids"
        ],
        "answer": "Intravenous (IV) fluids",
        "explanation": "Preload is affected by the circulating volume; if the patient has decreased fluid volume, it will need to be replaced with fluid or blood therapy. Preload is the amount of blood in the left ventricle at the end of diastole, often referred to as end-diastolic volume. Giving diuretics and vasodilators will make the situation worse. Diuretics cause fluid loss; the patient is already low on fluids or the preload would not be decreased. Vasodilators reduced blood return to the heart, making the situation worse; the patient does not have enough blood and fluid to the heart or the preload would not be decreased. Chest physiotherapy is a group of therapies for mobilizing pulmonary secretions. Chest physiotherapy will not help this cardiovascular problem.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the relationship of cardiac output, preload, afterload, contractility, and heart rate to the process of oxygena tion.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is preparing to suction a patient. The pulse is 65 and pulse oximetry is 94%. Which finding will cause the nurse to stop suctioning?",
        "options": [
          "Pulse 75",
          "Pulse 80",
          "Oxygen saturation 91%",
          "Oxygen saturation 88%"
        ],
        "answer": "Oxygen saturation 88%",
        "explanation": "Stop when oxygen saturation is 88%. Monitor patient’s vital signs and oxygen saturation during procedure; note whether there is a change of 20 beats/min (either increase or decrease) or if pulse oximetry falls below 90% or 5% from baseline. If this occurs, stop suctioning. A pulse rate of 75 is only 10 beats different from the start of the procedure. A pulse rate of 80 is 15 beats different from the start of suctioning. Oxygen saturation of 91% is not 5% from baseline or below 90%.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify the clinical outcomes occurring as a result of hyperventilation, hypoventilation, and hypoxemia.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is experiencing right-sided heart failure. Which finding will the nurse expect when performing an assessment?",
        "options": [
          "Peripheral edema",
          "Basilar crackles",
          "Chest pain",
          "Cyanosis"
        ],
        "answer": "Peripheral edema",
        "explanation": "Right-sided heart failure results from inability of the right side of the heart to pump effectively, leading to a systemic backup. Peripheral edema, distended neck veins, and weight gain are signs of right-sided failure. Basilar crackles can indicate pulmonary congestion from left-sided heart failure. Cyanosis and chest pain result from inadequate tissue perfusion.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess for the physical manifestations that occur with alterations in oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is reviewing the electrocardiogram (ECG) results. Which portion of the conduction system does the nurse consider when evaluating the P wave?",
        "options": [
          "SA node",
          "AV node",
          "Bundle of His",
          "Purkinje fibers"
        ],
        "answer": "SA node",
        "explanation": "The P wave represents the electrical conduction through both atria; the SA node initiates electrical conduction through the atria. The AV node conducts down through the bundle of His and the Purkinje fibers to cause ventricular contraction.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the relationship of cardiac output, preload, afterload, contractility, and heart rate to the process of oxygena tion.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse teaches a patient about atelectasis. Which statement by the patient indicates an understanding of atelectasis?",
        "options": [
          "“Atelectasis affects only those with chronic conditions such as emphysema.”",
          "“It is important to do breathing exercises every hour to prevent atelectasis.”",
          "“If I develop atelectasis, I will need a chest tube to drain excess fluid.”",
          "“Hyperventilation will open up my alveoli, preventing atelectasis.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“It is important to do breathing exercises every hour to prevent atelectasis.”",
        "explanation": "Atelectasis develops when alveoli do not expand. Breathing exercises, especially deep breathing and incentive spirometry, increase lung volume and open the airways, preventing atelectasis. Deep breathing also opens the pores of Kohn between alveoli to allow sharing of oxygen between alveoli. Atelectasis can affect anyone who does not deep breathe. A chest tube is for pneumothorax or hemothorax. It is deep breathing, not hyperventilation, that prevents atelectasis.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify the clinical outcomes occurring as a result of hyperventilation, hypoventilation, and hypoxemia.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with respiratory problems. Which assessment finding indicates a late sign of hypoxia?",
        "options": [
          "Elevated blood pressure",
          "Increased pulse rate",
          "Restlessness",
          "Cyanosis"
        ],
        "answer": "Cyanosis",
        "explanation": "Cyanosis, blue discoloration of the skin and mucous membranes caused by the presence of desaturated hemoglobin in capillaries, is a late sign of hypoxia. Elevated blood pressure, increased pulse rate, and restlessness are early signs of hypoxia.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Assess for the physical manifestations that occur with alterations in oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a 5-year-old patient whose temperature is 101.2° F. The nurse expects this patient to hyperventilate. Which factor does the nurse remember when planning care for this type of hyperventilation?",
        "options": [
          "Anxiety over illness",
          "Decreased drive to breathe",
          "Increased metabolic demands",
          "Infection destroying lung tissues"
        ],
        "answer": "Increased metabolic demands",
        "explanation": "Increased body temperature (fever) increases the metabolic rate, thereby increasing carbon dioxide production. The increased carbon dioxide level stimulates an increase in the patient’s rate and depth of respiration, causing hyperventilation. Anxiety can cause hyperventilation, but this is not the direct cause from a fever. Sleep causes a decreased respiratory drive; hyperventilation speeds up breathing. The cause of the fever in this question is unknown.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the effects of a patient’s level of health, age, lifestyle, and environment on oxygenation.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is preparing a patient for nasotracheal suctioning. In which order will the nurse perform the steps, beginning with the first step?\n1. Insert catheter.\n2. Apply suction and remove.\n3. Have patient deep breathe.\n4. Encourage patient to cough.\n5. Attach catheter to suction system.\n6. Rinse catheter and connecting tubing.",
        "options": [
          "1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6",
          "4, 5, 1, 2, 3, 6",
          "5, 3, 1, 2, 4, 6",
          "3, 1, 2, 5, 4, 6"
        ],
        "answer": "5, 3, 1, 2, 4, 6",
        "explanation": "The steps for nasotracheal suctioning are as follows: verify that catheter is attached to suction; have patient deep breathe; insert catheter; apply intermittent suction for no more than 10 seconds and remove; encourage patient to cough; and rinse catheter and connecting tubing with normal saline.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is experiencing carbon dioxide retention from lung problems. Which type of diet will the nurse most likely suggest for this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Moderate-carbohydrate",
          "Low-caffeine",
          "High-caffeine",
          "High-carbohydrate"
        ],
        "answer": "Moderate-carbohydrate",
        "explanation": "A moderate-carbohydrate diet is best. Diets high in carbohydrates play a role in increasing the carbon dioxide load for patients with carbon dioxide retention. As carbohydrates are metabolized, an increased load of carbon dioxide is created and excreted via the lungs. A low- or high-caffeine diet is not as important as the carbohydrate load.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the effects of a patient’s level of health, age, lifestyle, and environment on oxygenation.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse caring for a patient prescribed warfarin discovers that the patient is taking garlic to help with hypertension. Which condition will the nurse assess for in this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Increased cholesterol level",
          "Distended jugular vein",
          "Bleeding",
          "Angina"
        ],
        "answer": "Bleeding",
        "explanation": "Patients taking warfarin for anticoagulation prolong the prothrombin time (PT)/international normalized ratio (INR) results if they are taking Gingko biloba, garlic, or ginseng with the anticoagulant. The drug interaction can precipitate a life-threatening bleed. Increased cholesterol levels are associated with saturated fat dietary intake. A distended jugular vein and peripheral edema are associated with damage to the right side of the heart. Angina is temporary ischemia of the heart muscle.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the effects of a patient’s level of health, age, lifestyle, and environment on oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient whose tissue perfusion is poor as the result of hypertension. When the patient asks what to eat for breakfast, which meal should the nurse suggest?",
        "options": [
          "A cup of nonfat yogurt with granola and a handful of dried apricots",
          "Whole wheat toast with butter and a side of bacon",
          "A bowl of cereal with whole milk and a banana",
          "Omelet with sausage, cheese, and onions"
        ],
        "answer": "A cup of nonfat yogurt with granola and a handful of dried apricots",
        "explanation": "A 2000-calorie diet of fruits, vegetables, and low-fat dairy foods that are high in fiber, potassium, calcium, and magnesium and low in saturated and total fat helps prevent and reduce the effects of hypertension. Nonfat yogurt with granola is a good source of calcium, fiber, and potassium; dried apricots add a second source of potassium. Although cereal and a banana provide fiber and potassium, skim milk should be substituted for whole milk to decrease fat. An omelet with sausage and cheese is high in fat. Butter and bacon are high in fat.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Develop a plan of care for a patient with altered need for oxygenation.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "Upon auscultation of the patient’s chest, the nurse hears a whooshing sound at the fifth intercostal space. What does this finding indicate to the nurse?",
        "options": [
          "The beginning of the systolic phase",
          "Regurgitation of the mitral valve",
          "The opening of the aortic valve",
          "Presence of orthopnea"
        ],
        "answer": "Regurgitation of the mitral valve",
        "explanation": "When regurgitation occurs, there is a backflow of blood into an adjacent chamber. For example, in mitral regurgitation, the mitral leaflets do not close completely. When the ventricles contract, blood escapes back into the atria, causing a murmur, or “whooshing” sound. The systolic phase begins with ventricular filling and closing of the aortic valve, which is heard as the first heart sound, S1. Orthopnea is an abnormal condition in which a patient uses multiple pillows when reclining to breathe easier or sits leaning forward with arms elevated.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify the clinical outcomes occurring as a result of disturbances in conduction, altered cardiac output, impaired valvular function,",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient diagnosed with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) who is receiving 2 L/min of oxygen. Which oxygen delivery device is most appropriate for the nurse to administer the oxygen?",
        "options": [
          "Nasal cannula",
          "Simple face mask",
          "Non-rebreather mask",
          "Partial non-rebreather mask"
        ],
        "answer": "Nasal cannula",
        "explanation": "Nasal cannulas deliver oxygen from 1 to 6 L/min. All other devices (simple face mask, non-rebreather mask, and partial non-rebreather mask) are intended for flow rates greater than 6 L/min.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Develop a plan of care for a patient with altered need for oxygenation.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse plans to closely monitor the oxygen status of an older-adult patient undergoing anesthesia because of which age-related change?",
        "options": [
          "Thinner heart valves cause lipid accumulation and fibrosis.",
          "Diminished respiratory muscle strength may cause poor chest expansion.",
          "Alterations in mental status prevent patients’ awareness of ineffective breathing.",
          "An increased number of pacemaker cells make proper anesthesia induction more difficult."
        ],
        "answer": "Diminished respiratory muscle strength may cause poor chest expansion.",
        "explanation": "Age-related changes in the thorax that occur from ossification of costal cartilage, decreased space between vertebrae, and diminished respiratory muscle strength lead to problems with chest expansion and oxygenation, whereby the patient will have difficulty excreting anesthesia gas. The nurse needs to monitor the patient’s oxygen status carefully to make sure the patient does not retain too much of the drug. Older adults experience alterations in cardiac function as a result of calcification of the conduction pathways, thicker and stiffer heart valves caused by lipid accumulation and fibrosis, and a decrease in the number of pacemaker cells in the SA node. Altered mental status is not a normal age-related change; it indicates possible cardiac and/or respiratory problems.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the effects of a patient’s level of health, age, lifestyle, and environment on oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse determines that an older-adult patient is at risk for infection due to decreased immunity. Which plan of care best addresses the prevention of infection for the patient?",
        "options": [
          "Inform the patient of the importance of finishing the entire dose of antibiotics.",
          "Encourage the patient to stay up-to-date on all vaccinations.",
          "Schedule patient to get annual tuberculosis skin testing.",
          "Create an exercise routine to run 45 minutes every day."
        ],
        "answer": "Encourage the patient to stay up-to-date on all vaccinations.",
        "explanation": "A nursing care plan for preventative health measures should be reasonable and feasible. Keeping up-to-date on vaccinations is important because vaccine reduces the severity of illnesses and serious complications. Determine if and when the patient has had a pneumococcal or influenza (flu) vaccine. This is especially important when assessing older adults because of their increased risk for respiratory disease. Although it is important to finish the full course of antibiotics, it is not a preventative health measure. Scheduling annual tuberculosis skin tests does not address prevention and is an unreliable indictor of tuberculosis in older patients. The exercise routine should be reasonable to increase compliance; exercise is recommended only 3 to 4 times a week for 30 to 60 minutes, and walking, rather than running, is an efficient method.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient experiencing fluid volume overload. Which physiological effect does the nurse most likely expect?",
        "options": [
          "Increased preload",
          "Increased heart rate",
          "Decreased afterload",
          "Decreased tissue perfusion"
        ],
        "answer": "Increased preload",
        "explanation": "Preload refers to the amount of blood in the left ventricle at the end of diastole; an increase in circulating volume would increase the preload of the heart. Afterload refers to resistance; increased pressure would lead to increased resistance, and afterload would increase. A decrease in tissue perfusion would be seen with hypovolemia. A decrease in fluid volume would cause an increase in heart rate as the body is attempting to increase cardiac output.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the relationship of cardiac output, preload, afterload, contractility, and heart rate to the process of oxygena tion.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient prescribed continuous cardiac monitoring for heart dysrhythmias. Which rhythm will cause the nurse to intervene immediately?",
        "options": [
          "Ventricular tachycardia",
          "Atrial fibrillation",
          "Sinus rhythm",
          "Paroxysmal supraventricular tachycardia"
        ],
        "answer": "Ventricular tachycardia",
        "explanation": "Ventricular tachycardia and ventricular fibrillation are life-threatening rhythms that require immediate intervention. Ventricular tachycardia is a life-threatening dysrhythmia because of the decreased cardiac output and the potential to deteriorate into ventricular fibrillation or sudden cardiac death. Atrial fibrillation is a common dysrhythmia in older adults and is not as serious as ventricular tachycardia. Sinus rhythm is normal. Paroxysmal supraventricular tachycardia is a sudden, rapid onset of tachycardia originating above the AV node. It often begins and ends spontaneously.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify the clinical outcomes occurring as a result of disturbances in conduction, altered cardiac output, impaired valvular function,",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is experiencing angina pectoris. Which assessment finding does the nurse expect when conducting a history and physical examination?",
        "options": [
          "Experiences chest pain after eating a heavy meal.",
          "Experiences adequate oxygen saturation during exercise.",
          "Experiences crushing chest pain for more than 20 minutes.",
          "Experiences tingling in the left arm that lasts throughout the morning."
        ],
        "answer": "Experiences chest pain after eating a heavy meal.",
        "explanation": "Angina pectoris is chest pain that results from limited oxygen supply. Often pain is precipitated by activities such as exercise, stress, and eating a heavy meal and lasts 3 to 5 minutes. Symptoms of angina pectoris are relieved by rest and/or nitroglycerin. Adequate oxygen saturation occurs with rest; inadequate oxygen saturation occurs during exercise. Pain lasting longer than 20 minutes or arm tingling that persists could be a sign of myocardial infarction.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess for the physical manifestations that occur with alterations in oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which risk factor for cardiopulmonary disease should the nurse describe as modifiable?",
        "options": [
          "Stress",
          "Allergies",
          "Family history",
          "Gender"
        ],
        "answer": "Stress",
        "explanation": "Young and middle-age adults are exposed to multiple cardiopulmonary risk factors: an unhealthy diet, lack of exercise, stress, over-the-counter and prescription drugs not used as intended, illegal substances, and smoking. Reducing these modifiable factors decreases a patient’s risk for cardiac or pulmonary diseases. A nonmodifiable risk factor is family history; determine familial risk factors such as a family history of lung cancer or cardiovascular disease. Other nonmodifiable risk factors include allergies and gender.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Assess for the risk factors affecting a patient’s oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is creating a plan of care for an obese patient who is experiencing fatigue related to ineffective breathing. Which intervention best addresses a short-term goal the patient could achieve?",
        "options": [
          "Sleeping on two to three pillows at night",
          "Sensibly reducing daily calorie intake",
          "Running 30 minutes every morning",
          "Stopping smoking immediately"
        ],
        "answer": "Sleeping on two to three pillows at night",
        "explanation": "To achieve a short-term goal, the nurse should plan a lifestyle change that the patient can make immediately that will have a quick effect. Sleeping on several pillows at night will immediately relieve orthopnea and open the patient’s airway, thereby reducing fatigue. Running 30 minutes a day will improve cardiopulmonary health, but a patient needs to build up exercise tolerance. Smoking cessation is another process that many people have difficulty doing immediately. A more realistic short-term goal would be to gradually reduce the number of cigarettes smoked. Limiting caloric intake can help a patient lose weight, but this is a gradual process and is not reasonable for a short-term goal.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Develop a plan of care for a patient with altered need for oxygenation.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient experiencing left-sided hemiparesis has developed bronchitis and has a heart rate of 105 beats/min, blood pressure of 156/90 mm Hg, and respiration rate of 30 breaths/min. Which nursing diagnosis is a priority?",
        "options": [
          "Risk for skin breakdown",
          "Impaired gas exchange",
          "Activity intolerance",
          "Risk for infection"
        ],
        "answer": "Impaired gas exchange",
        "explanation": "The most important nursing intervention is to maintain airway and circulation for this patient; therefore, Impaired gas exchange is the first nursing priority. Activity intolerance is a concern but is not the priority in this case. Risk for skin breakdown and Risk for infection are also important but do not address an immediate impairment with physiological integrity.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Develop a plan of care for a patient with altered need for oxygenation.",
        "top": "Diagnosis",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which nursing intervention is most effective in preventing hospital-acquired pneumonia in an older-adult patient?",
        "options": [
          "Discontinue the humidification delivery device to keep excess fluid from lungs.",
          "Monitor oxygen saturation, and frequently auscultate lung bases.",
          "Assist the patient to cough, turn, and deep breathe every 2 hours.",
          "Decrease fluid intake to 300 mL a shift."
        ],
        "answer": "Assist the patient to cough, turn, and deep breathe every 2 hours.",
        "explanation": "The goal of the nursing action should be the prevention of pneumonia; the action that best addresses this is to cough, turn, and deep breathe to keep secretions from pooling at the base of the lungs. Humidification thins respiratory secretions, making them easier to expel and should be used. Monitoring oxygen status is important but is not a method of prevention. Hydration assists in preventing hospital-acquired pneumonia. The best way to maintain thin secretions is to provide a fluid intake of 1500 to 2500 mL/day unless contraindicated by cardiac or renal status. Restricting fluids is contraindicated in this situation since there is no data indicating cardiac or renal disease.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is assessing a patient diagnosed with emphysema. Which assessment finding requires further follow-up with the health care provider?",
        "options": [
          "Increased anterior-posterior diameter of the chest",
          "Accessory muscle used for breathing",
          "Clubbing of the fingers",
          "Hemoptysis"
        ],
        "answer": "Hemoptysis",
        "explanation": "Hemoptysis is an abnormal occurrence of emphysema, and further diagnostic studies are needed to determine the cause of blood in the sputum. Clubbing of the fingers, barrel chest (increased anterior-posterior chest diameter), and accessory muscle used are all normal findings in a patient with emphysema.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Assess for the physical manifestations that occur with alterations in oxygenation.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient diagnosed with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) asks the nurse why clubbing occurs. Which response by the nurse is most therapeutic?",
        "options": [
          "“Your disease doesn’t send enough oxygen to your fingers.”",
          "“Your disease affects both your lungs and your heart, and not enough blood is being pumped.”",
          "“Your disease will be helped if you pursed-lip breathe.”",
          "“Your disease often makes patients lose mental status.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Your disease doesn’t send enough oxygen to your fingers.”",
        "explanation": "Clubbing of the nail bed can occur with COPD and other diseases that cause prolonged oxygen deficiency or chronic hypoxemia. Pursed-lipped breathing helps the alveoli stay open but is not the cause of clubbing. Loss of mental status is not a normal finding with COPD and will not result in clubbing. Low oxygen and not low circulating blood volume is the problem in COPD that results in clubbing.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify the clinical outcomes occurring as a result of hyperventilation, hypoventilation, and hypoxemia.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient experiencing a pneumothorax has a chest tube inserted and is placed on low constant suction. Which finding requires immediate action by the nurse?",
        "options": [
          "The patient reports pain at the chest tube insertion site that increases with movement.",
          "Fifty milliliters of blood gushes into the drainage device after the patient coughs.",
          "No bubbling is present in the suction control chamber of the drainage device.",
          "Yellow purulent discharge is seen leaking out from around the dressing site."
        ],
        "answer": "No bubbling is present in the suction control chamber of the drainage device.",
        "explanation": "No bubbling in the suction control chamber indicates an obstruction of the drainage system. An obstruction causes increased pressure, which can cause a tension pneumothorax, which can be life threatening. The nurse needs to determine whether the leak is inside the thorax or in the tubing and act from there. Occasional blood gushes from the lung owing to lung expansion, as during a cough; this is reserve drainage. Drainage over 100 mL/hr after 3 hours of chest tube placement is cause for concern. Yellow purulent drainage indicates an infection that should be reported to the health care provider but is not as immediately life threatening as the lack of bubbling in the suction control chamber.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has had a tracheostomy tube inserted. Which nursing intervention is most effective in promoting effective airway clearance?",
        "options": [
          "Suctioning respiratory secretions several times every hour",
          "Administering humidified oxygen through a tracheostomy collar",
          "Instilling normal saline into the tracheostomy to thin secretions before suctioning",
          "Deflating the tracheostomy cuff before allowing the patient to cough up secretions"
        ],
        "answer": "Administering humidified oxygen through a tracheostomy collar",
        "explanation": "Humidification from air humidifiers or humidified oxygen tracheostomy collars can help prevent drying of secretions that cause occlusion. Suctioning should be done only as needed; too frequent suctioning can damage the mucosal lining, resulting in thicker secretions. Normal saline should not be instilled into a tracheostomy; research showed no benefit with this technique. The purpose of the tracheostomy cuff is to keep secretions from entering the lungs; the nurse should not deflate the tracheostomy cuff unless instructed to do so by the health care provider.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Develop a plan of care for a patient with altered need for oxygenation.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is educating a student nurse on caring for a patient with a chest tube. Which statement from the student nurse indicates successful learning?",
        "options": [
          "“I should clamp the chest tube when giving the patient a bed bath.”",
          "“I should report if I see continuous bubbling in the water-seal chamber.”",
          "“I should strip the drains on the chest tube every hour to promote drainage.”",
          "“I should notify the health care provider first, if the chest tube becomes dislodged.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“I should report if I see continuous bubbling in the water-seal chamber.”",
        "explanation": "Correct care of a chest tube involves knowing normal and abnormal functioning of the tube. A constant or intermittent bubbling in the water-seal chamber indicates a leak in the drainage system, and the health care provider must be notified immediately. Stripping the tube is not routinely performed as it increases pressure. If the tubing disconnects from the drainage unit, instruct the patient to exhale as much as possible and to cough. This maneuver rids the pleural space of as much air as possible. Temporarily reestablish a water seal by immersing the open end of the chest tube into a container of sterile water. The chest tube should not be clamped unless necessary; if so, the length of time clamped would be minimal to reduce the risk of pneumothorax.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which coughing technique will the nurse use to help a patient clear central airways?",
        "options": [
          "Huff",
          "Quad",
          "Cascade",
          "Incentive spirometry"
        ],
        "answer": "Huff",
        "explanation": "The huff cough stimulates a natural cough reflex and is generally effective only for clearing central airways. While exhaling, the patient opens the glottis by saying the word huff. The quad cough technique is for patients without abdominal muscle control such as those with spinal cord injuries. While the patient breathes out with a maximal expiratory effort, the patient or nurse pushes inward and upward on the abdominal muscles toward the diaphragm, causing the cough. With the cascade cough the patient takes a slow, deep breath and holds it for 2 seconds while contracting expiratory muscles. Then he or she opens the mouth and performs a series of coughs throughout exhalation, thereby coughing at progressively lowered lung volumes. This technique promotes airway clearance and a patent airway in patients with large volumes of sputum. Incentive spirometry encourages voluntary deep breathing by providing visual feedback to patients about inspiratory volume. It promotes deep breathing and prevents or treats atelectasis in the postoperative patient.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is suctioning a patient with a tracheostomy tube. Which action will the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Set suction regulator at 150 to 200 mm Hg.",
          "Limit the length of suctioning to 10 seconds.",
          "Apply suction while gently rotating and inserting the catheter.",
          "Liberally lubricate the end of the suction catheter with a water-soluble solution."
        ],
        "answer": "Limit the length of suctioning to 10 seconds.",
        "explanation": "Suctioning passes should be limited to 10 seconds to avoid hypoxemia. Suction for a tracheostomy should be set at 100 to 150 mm Hg. Excessive lubrication can clog the catheter or occlude the airway; lubricant is not necessary for oropharyngeal or artificial airway (tracheostomy) suctioning. Suction should never be applied on insertion.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who is prescribed oxygen via a nasal cannula. Which task can the nurse delegate to the nursing assistive personnel?",
        "options": [
          "Applying the nasal cannula",
          "Adjusting the oxygen flow",
          "Assessing lung sounds",
          "Setting up the oxygen"
        ],
        "answer": "Applying the nasal cannula",
        "explanation": "The skill of applying (not adjusting oxygen flow) a nasal cannula or oxygen mask can be delegated to assistive personnel (AP). The nurse is responsible for assessing the patient’s respiratory system, response to oxygen therapy, and setup of oxygen therapy, including adjustment of oxygen flow rate.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is using a closed suction device. Which patient will be most appropriate for this suctioning method?",
        "options": [
          "A 5 year old with excessive drooling from epiglottitis",
          "A 5 year old with an asthma attack following severe allergies",
          "A 24 year old with a right pneumothorax following a motor vehicle accident",
          "A 24 year old with acute respiratory distress syndrome requiring mechanical ventilation"
        ],
        "answer": "A 24 year old with acute respiratory distress syndrome requiring mechanical ventilation",
        "explanation": "Closed suctioning is most often used on patients who require invasive mechanical ventilation to support their respiratory efforts because it permits continuous delivery of oxygen while suction is performed and reduces the risk of oxygen desaturation. In this case, the acute respiratory distress syndrome requires mechanical ventilation. In the presence of epiglottitis, croup, laryngospasm, or irritable airway, the entrance of a suction catheter via the nasal route causes intractable coughing, hypoxemia, and severe bronchospasm, necessitating emergency intubation or tracheostomy. The 5-year-old child with asthma would benefit from an inhaler. A chest tube is needed for the pneumothorax.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss the effects of a patient’s level of health, age, lifestyle, and environment on oxygenation.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "While the nurse is changing the ties on a tracheostomy collar, the patient coughs, dislodging the tracheostomy tube. Which action will the nurse take first?",
        "options": [
          "Press the emergency response button.",
          "Insert a spare tracheostomy with the obturator.",
          "Manually occlude the tracheostomy with sterile gauze.",
          "Place a face mask delivering 100% oxygen over the nose and mouth."
        ],
        "answer": "Insert a spare tracheostomy with the obturator.",
        "explanation": "The nurse’s first priority is to establish a stable airway by inserting a spare trach into the patient’s airway; ideally an obturator should be used. The nurse could activate the emergency response team if the patient is still unstable after the tracheostomy is placed. A patient with a tracheostomy breathes through the tube, not the nose or mouth; a face mask would not be an effective method of getting air into the lungs. Manually occluding pressure over the tracheostomy site is not appropriate and would block the patient’s only airway.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Develop a plan of care for a patient with altered need for oxygenation.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is following the How-to Guide to prevent ventilator-associated pneumonia. Which strategies is the nurse using? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Head of bed elevation to 90 degrees at all times",
          "Daily oral care with chlorhexidine",
          "Delirium monitoring",
          "Clean technique when suctioning",
          "Daily “sedation vacations”",
          "Heart failure prophylaxis"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Daily oral care with chlorhexidine",
          "Delirium monitoring",
          "Daily “sedation vacations”"
        ],
        "explanation": "The key components of the Institute for Healthcare Improvement (IHI) How-to Guide are: Elevation of the head of the bed (HOB)—elevation is greater than 30 degrees Daily “sedation vacations” and assessment of readiness to extubate Peptic ulcer disease prophylaxis Venous thromboembolism prophylaxis Daily oral care with chlorhexidine Delirium monitoring Early ambulation Sterile technique is used for suctioning when on ventilators. Heart failure prophylaxis is not a component.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching a community health promotion class and discusses the flu vaccine. Which information will the nurse include in the teaching session? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "It is given yearly.",
          "It is given in a series of four doses.",
          "It is safe for children allergic to eggs.",
          "It is safe for adults with acute febrile illnesses.",
          "The live, attenuated nasal spray is given to people over 50.",
          "The vaccines are recommended for all people 6 months and older."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "It is given yearly.",
          "The vaccines are recommended for all people 6 months and older."
        ],
        "explanation": "Annual (yearly) flu vaccines are recommended for all people 6 months and older. People with a known hypersensitivity to eggs or other components of the vaccine should consult their health care provider before being vaccinated. There is a flu vaccine made without egg proteins that is approved for adults 18 years of age and older. Adults with an acute febrile illness should schedule the vaccination after they have recovered. The live, attenuated nasal spray vaccine is given to people from 2 through 49 years of age if they are not pregnant or do not have certain long-term health problems such as asthma; heart, lung, or kidney disease; diabetes; or anemia.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient being treated for sleep apnea. Which types of ventilator support should the nurse be prepared to administer for this patient? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Assist-control (AC)",
          "Pressure support ventilation (PSV)",
          "Bilevel positive airway pressure (BiPAP)",
          "Continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP)",
          "Synchronized intermittent mandatory ventilation (SIMV)"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Bilevel positive airway pressure (BiPAP)",
          "Continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP)"
        ],
        "explanation": ", D Ventilatory support is achieved using a variety of modes, including continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) and bilevel positive airway pressure (BiPAP). The purpose of CPAP and BiPAP is to maintain a positive airway pressure and improve alveolar ventilation. This prevents or treats atelectasis by inflating the alveoli, reducing pulmonary edema by forcing fluid out of the lungs back into circulation, and improving oxygenation in those with sleep apnea. AC, PSV, and SIMV are invasive mechanical ventilation and are not routinely used on patients with sleep apnea. AC delivers a set tidal volume (VT) with each breath, regardless of whether the breath was triggered by the patient or the ventilator. Synchronized intermittent mandatory ventilation like AC delivers a minimum number of fully assisted breaths per minute that are synchronized with the patient’s respiratory effort. Any breaths taken between volume-cycled breaths are not assisted; the volume of these breaths is determined by the patient’s strength, effort, and lung mechanics. PSV mode is often combined with SIMV mode: inspiratory pressure is added to spontaneous breaths to overcome the resistance of the endotracheal tube or to help increase the volume of the patient’s spontaneous breaths.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing care interventions used to promote oxygenation in the primary care, acute care, and restorative and continuing care",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      }
    ],
    "chapter42": [
      {
        "question": "A patient is experiencing dehydration. While planning care, the nurse considers that the majority of the patient’s total water volume exists in with compartment?",
        "options": [
          "Intracellular",
          "Extracellular",
          "Intravascular",
          "Transcellular"
        ],
        "answer": "Intracellular",
        "explanation": "Intracellular (inside the cells) fluid accounts for approximately two thirds of total body water. Extracellular (outside the cells) is approximately one third of the total body water. Intravascular fluid (liquid portion of the blood) and transcellular fluid are two major divisions of the extracellular compartment.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating extracellular fluid volume, body fluid osmolality, and fluid distribution.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is teaching about the process of passively moving water from an area of lower particle concentration to an area of higher particle concentration. Which process is the nurse describing?",
        "options": [
          "Osmosis",
          "Filtration",
          "Diffusion",
          "Active transport"
        ],
        "answer": "Osmosis",
        "explanation": "The process of moving water from an area of low particle concentration to an area of higher particle concentration is known as osmosis. Filtration is mediated by fluid pressure from an area of higher pressure to an area of lower pressure. Diffusion is passive movement of electrolytes or other particles down the concentration gradient (from areas of higher concentration to areas of lower concentration). Active transport requires energy in the form of adenosine triphosphate (ATP) to move electrolytes across cell membranes against the concentration gradient (from areas of lower concentration to areas of higher concentration).",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating extracellular fluid volume, body fluid osmolality, and fluid distribution.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse observes edema in a patient who is experiencing venous congestion as a result of right heart failure. Which type of pressure facilitated the formation of the patient’s edema?",
        "options": [
          "Osmotic",
          "Oncotic",
          "Hydrostatic",
          "Concentration"
        ],
        "answer": "Hydrostatic",
        "explanation": "Venous congestion increases capillary hydrostatic pressure. Increased hydrostatic pressure causes edema by causing increased movement of fluid into the interstitial area. Osmotic and oncotic pressures involve the concentrations of solutes and can contribute to edema in other situations, such as inflammation or malnutrition. Concentration pressure is not a nursing term.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe common fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse administers an intravenous (IV) hypertonic solution to a patient expects the fluid shift to occur in what direction?",
        "options": [
          "From intracellular to extracellular",
          "From extracellular to intracellular",
          "From intravascular to intracellular",
          "From intravascular to interstitial"
        ],
        "answer": "From intracellular to extracellular",
        "explanation": "Hypertonic solutions will move fluid from the intracellular to the extracellular (intravascular). A hypertonic solution has a concentration greater than normal body fluids, so water will shift out of cells because of the osmotic pull of the extra particles. Movement of water from the extracellular (intravascular) into cells (intracellular) occurs when hypotonic fluids are administered. Distribution of fluid between intravascular and interstitial spaces occurs by filtration, the net sum of hydrostatic and osmotic pressures.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating extracellular fluid volume, body fluid osmolality, and fluid distribution.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is preparing to start peripheral intravenous (IV) therapy. In which order will the nurse perform the steps starting with the first one?\n1. Clean site.\n2. Select vein.\n3. Apply tourniquet.\n4. Release tourniquet.\n5. Reapply tourniquet.\n6. Advance and secure.\n7. Insert vascular access device.",
        "options": [
          "1, 3, 2, 7, 5, 4, 6",
          "1, 3, 2, 5, 7, 6, 4",
          "3, 2, 1, 5, 7, 6, 4",
          "3, 2, 4, 1, 5, 7, 6"
        ],
        "answer": "3, 2, 4, 1, 5, 7, 6",
        "explanation": "The steps for inserting an intravenous catheter are as follows: Apply tourniquet, select vein, release tourniquet, clean site, reapply tourniquet, insert vascular access device, and advance and secure.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss purpose and procedure for initiation and maintenance of intravenous therapy.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is laboratory blood results will expect to observe which cation in the most abundance?",
        "options": [
          "Sodium",
          "Chloride",
          "Potassium",
          "Magnesium"
        ],
        "answer": "Sodium",
        "explanation": "Sodium is the most abundant cation in the blood. Potassium is the predominant intracellular cation. Chloride is an anion (negatively charged) rather than a cation (positively charged). Magnesium is found predominantly inside cells and in bone.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating plasma concentrations of potassium, calcium, magnesium, and phosphate ions.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse receives the patient’s most recent blood work results. Which laboratory value is of greatest concern?",
        "options": [
          "Sodium of 145 mEq/L",
          "Calcium of 15.5 mg/dL",
          "Potassium of 3.5 mEq/L",
          "Chloride of 100 mEq/L"
        ],
        "answer": "Calcium of 15.5 mg/dL",
        "explanation": "Normal calcium range is 9 to 10.5 mg/dL; therefore, a value of 15.5 mg/dL is abnormally high and of concern. The rest of the laboratory values are within their normal ranges: sodium 136 to 145 mEq/L, potassium 3.5 to 5.0 mEq/L, and chloride 98 to 106 mEq/L.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Interpret basic fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base laboratory values.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse observes that the patient’s calcium is elevated. When checking the phosphate level, what does the nurse expect to see?",
        "options": [
          "An increase",
          "A decrease",
          "Equal to calcium",
          "No change in phosphate"
        ],
        "answer": "A decrease",
        "explanation": "Phosphate will decrease. Serum calcium and phosphate have an inverse relationship. When one is elevated, the other decreases, except in some patients with end-stage renal disease.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating plasma concentrations of potassium, calcium, magnesium, and phosphate ions.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "Four patients arrive at the emergency department at the same time. Which patient will the nurse see first?",
        "options": [
          "An infant with temperature of 102.2° F and diarrhea for 3 days",
          "A teenager with a sprained ankle and excessive edema",
          "A middle-aged adult with abdominal pain who is moaning and holding her stomach",
          "An older adult with nausea and vomiting for 3 days with blood pressure 112/60"
        ],
        "answer": "An infant with temperature of 102.2° F and diarrhea for 3 days",
        "explanation": "The infant should be seen first. An infant’s proportion of total body water (70% to 80% total body weight) is greater than that of children or adults. Infants and young children have greater water needs and immature kidneys. They are at greater risk for extracellular volume deficit and hypernatremia because body water loss is proportionately greater per kilogram of weight. A teenager with excessive edema from a sprained ankle can wait. A middle-aged adult moaning in pain can wait as can an older adult with a blood pressure of 112/60.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient has an intravenous (IV) line and the nurse needs to remove the gown. In which order will the nurse perform the steps, starting with the first one? 1. Remove the sleeve of the gown from the arm without the IV. 2. Remove the sleeve of the gown from the arm with the IV. 3. Remove the IV solution container from its stand. 4. Pass the IV bag and tubing through the sleeve.",
        "options": [
          "1, 2, 3, 4",
          "2, 3, 4, 1",
          "3, 4, 1, 2",
          "4, 1, 2, 3"
        ],
        "answer": "1, 2, 3, 4",
        "explanation": "Change regular gowns by following these steps for maximum speed and arm mobility: (1) To remove a gown, remove the sleeve of the gown from the arm without the IV line, maintaining the patient’s privacy. (2) Remove the sleeve of the gown from the arm with the IV line. (3) Remove the IV solution container from its stand and pass it and the tubing through the sleeve. (If this involves removing the tubing from an EID, use the roller clamp to slow the infusion to prevent the accidental infusion of a large volume of solution or medication.)",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss purpose and procedure for initiation and maintenance of intravenous therapy.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
      },
      {
        "question": "A 2-year-old child has ingested a quantity of a medication that causes respiratory depression. For which acid-base imbalance will the nurse most closely monitor this child?",
        "options": [
          "Respiratory alkalosis",
          "Respiratory acidosis",
          "Metabolic acidosis",
          "Metabolic alkalosis"
        ],
        "answer": "Respiratory acidosis",
        "explanation": "Respiratory depression leads to hypoventilation. Hypoventilation results in retention of CO2 and respiratory acidosis. Respiratory alkalosis would result from hyperventilation, causing a decrease in CO2 levels. Metabolic acid-base imbalance would be a result of kidney dysfunction, vomiting, diarrhea, or other conditions that affect metabolic acids.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify risk factors for fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is admitted for a bowel obstruction and has had a nasogastric tube set to low intermittent suction for the past 3 days. Which arterial blood gas values will the nurse expect to observe?",
        "options": [
          "Respiratory alkalosis",
          "Metabolic alkalosis",
          "Metabolic acidosis",
          "Respiratory acidosis"
        ],
        "answer": "Metabolic alkalosis",
        "explanation": "The patient is losing acid from the nasogastric tube so the patient will have metabolic alkalosis. Lung problems will produce respiratory alkalosis or acidosis. Metabolic acidosis will occur when too much acid is in the body like kidney failure.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe common fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which blood gas result will the nurse expect to observe in a patient with respiratory alkalosis?",
        "options": [
          "pH 7.60, PaCO2 40 mm Hg, HCO3– 30 mEq/L",
          "pH 7.53, PaCO2 30 mm Hg, HCO3– 24 mEq/L",
          "pH 7.35, PaCO2 35 mm Hg, HCO3– 26 mEq/L",
          "pH 7.25, PaCO2 48 mm Hg, HCO3– 23 mEq/L"
        ],
        "answer": "pH 7.53, PaCO2 30 mm Hg, HCO3– 24 mEq/L",
        "explanation": "Respiratory alkalosis should show an alkalotic pH and decreased CO2 (respiratory) values, with a normal HCO3–. In this case, pH 7.53 is alkaline (normal = 7.35 to 7.45), PaCO2 is 30 (normal 35 to 45 mm Hg), and HCO3– is 24 (normal = 22 to 26 mEq/L). A result of pH 7.60, PaCO2 40 mm Hg, HCO3– 30 mEq/L is metabolic alkalosis. pH 7.35, PaCO2 35 mm Hg, HCO3– 26 mEq/L is within normal limits. pH 7.25, PaCO2 48 mm Hg, HCO3– 23 mEq/L is respiratory acidosis.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Interpret basic fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base laboratory values.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient whose electrocardiogram (ECG) presents with changes characteristic of hypokalemia. Which assessment finding will the nurse expect?",
        "options": [
          "Dry mucous membranes",
          "Abdominal distention",
          "Distended neck veins",
          "Flushed skin"
        ],
        "answer": "Abdominal distention",
        "explanation": "Signs and symptoms of hypokalemia are muscle weakness, abdominal distention, decreased bowel sounds, and cardiac dysrhythmias. Distended neck veins occur in fluid overload. Thready peripheral pulses indicate hypovolemia. Dry mucous membranes and flushed skin are indicative of dehydration and hypernatremia.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Choose appropriate clinical assessments for specific fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which patient will the nurse expect to see a positive Chvostek’s sign?",
        "options": [
          "A 7-year-old child admitted for severe burns",
          "A 24-year-old adult admitted for chronic alcohol abuse",
          "A 50-year-old patient admitted for an acute exacerbation of hyperparathyroidism",
          "A 75-year-old patient admitted for a broken hip related to osteoporosis"
        ],
        "answer": "A 24-year-old adult admitted for chronic alcohol abuse",
        "explanation": "A positive Chvostek’s sign is representative of hypocalcemia or hypomagnesemia. Hypomagnesemia is common with alcohol abuse. Hypocalcemia can be brought on by alcohol abuse and pancreatitis (which also can be affected by alcohol consumption). Burn patients frequently experience extracellular fluid volume deficit. Hyperparathyroidism causes hypercalcemia. Immobility is associated with hypercalcemia.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Choose appropriate clinical assessments for specific fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is experiencing respiratory acidosis. Which organ system is responsible for compensation in this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Renal",
          "Endocrine",
          "Respiratory",
          "Gastrointestinal"
        ],
        "answer": "Renal",
        "explanation": "The kidneys (renal) are responsible for respiratory acidosis compensation. A problem with the respiratory system causes respiratory acidosis, so another organ system (renal) needs to compensate. Problems with the gastrointestinal and endocrine systems can cause acid-base imbalances, but these systems cannot compensate for an existing imbalance.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating acid-base balance.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient prescribed peripheral intravenous (IV) therapy. Which task will the nurse assign to the nursing assistive personnel?",
        "options": [
          "Recording intake and output",
          "Regulating intravenous flow rate",
          "Starting peripheral intravenous therapy",
          "Changing a peripheral intravenous dressing"
        ],
        "answer": "Recording intake and output",
        "explanation": "A nursing assistive personnel (AP) can record intake and output. An RN cannot delegate regulating flow rate, starting an IV, or changing an IV dressing to an NAP.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a diabetic patient in renal failure who is in metabolic acidosis. Which laboratory findings are consistent with metabolic acidosis?",
        "options": [
          "pH 7.3, PaCO2 36 mm Hg, HCO3– 19 mEq/L",
          "pH 7.5, PaCO2 35 mm Hg, HCO3– 35 mEq/L",
          "pH 7.32, PaCO2 47 mm Hg, HCO3– 23 mEq/L",
          "pH 7.35, PaCO2 40 mm Hg, HCO3– 25 mEq/L"
        ],
        "answer": "pH 7.3, PaCO2 36 mm Hg, HCO3– 19 mEq/L",
        "explanation": "The laboratory values that reflect metabolic acidosis are pH 7.3, PaCO2 36 mm Hg, HCO3– 19 mEq/L. A laboratory finding of pH 7.5, PaCO2 35 mm Hg, HCO3– 35 mEq/L is metabolic alkalosis. pH 7.32, PaCO2 47 mm Hg, HCO3– 23 mEq/L is respiratory acidosis. pH 7.35, PaCO2 40 mm Hg, HCO3– 25 mEq/L values are within normal range.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Interpret basic fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base laboratory values.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is assessing a patient and notes crackles in the lung bases and neck vein distention. Which action will the nurse take first?",
        "options": [
          "Offer calcium-rich foods.",
          "Administer diuretic.",
          "Raise head of bed.",
          "Increase fluids."
        ],
        "answer": "Raise head of bed.",
        "explanation": "The patient is in fluid overload. Raising the head of the bed to a high-Flower’s position will help ease breathing and so is the first action. Offering calcium-rich foods is for hypocalcemia, not fluid overload. Administering a diuretic is the second action. Increasing fluids is contraindicated and would make the situation worse.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient receiving chemotherapy has gained 5 pounds in 2 days. Which assessment question by the nurse is most appropriate?",
        "options": [
          "“Are you following any weight loss program?”",
          "“How many calories a day do you consume?”",
          "“Do you have dry mouth or feel thirsty?”",
          "“How many times a day do you urinate?”"
        ],
        "answer": "“How many times a day do you urinate?”",
        "explanation": "A rapid gain in weight usually indicates extracellular volume (ECV) excess if the person began with normal ECV. Asking the patient about urination habits will help determine whether the body is trying to excrete the excess fluid or if renal dysfunction is contributing to ECV excess. This is too rapid a weight gain to be dietary; it is fluid retention. Asking about following a weight loss program will not help determine the cause of the problem. Caloric intake does not account for rapid weight changes. Dry mouth and thirst accompany ECV deficit, which would be associated with rapid weight loss.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Choose appropriate clinical assessments for specific fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The health care provider has ordered a hypotonic intravenous (IV) solution to be administered. Which IV bag will the nurse prepare?",
        "options": [
          "0.45% sodium chloride (1/2 NS)",
          "0.9% sodium chloride (NS)",
          "Lactated Ringer’s (LR)",
          "Dextrose 5% in Lactated Ringer’s (D5LR)"
        ],
        "answer": "0.45% sodium chloride (1/2 NS)",
        "explanation": "0.45% sodium chloride is a hypotonic solution. NS and LR are isotonic. D5LR is hypertonic.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating extracellular fluid volume, body fluid osmolality, and fluid distribution.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "The health care provider asks the nurse to monitor the fluid volume status of a heart failure patient and a patient at risk for clinical dehydration. Which is the most effective nursing intervention for monitoring both of these patients?",
        "options": [
          "Assess the patients for edema in extremities.",
          "Ask the patients to record their intake and output.",
          "Weigh the patients every morning before breakfast.",
          "Measure the patients’ blood pressures every 4 hours."
        ],
        "answer": "Weigh the patients every morning before breakfast.",
        "explanation": "An effective measure of fluid retention or loss is daily weights; each kg (2.2 pounds) change is equivalent to 1 L of fluid gained or lost. This measurement should be performed at the same time every day using the same scale and the same amount of clothing. Although intake and output records are important assessment measures, some patients are not able to keep their own records themselves. Blood pressure can decrease with extracellular volume (ECV) deficit but will not necessarily increase with recent ECV excess (heart failure patient). Edema occurs with ECV excess but not with clinical dehydration.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient diagnosed with cancer who presents with anorexia, blood pressure 100/60, and elevated white blood cell count. Which primary purpose for starting total parenteral nutrition (TPN) will the nurse add to the care plan?",
        "options": [
          "Stimulate the patient’s appetite to eat.",
          "Deliver antibiotics to fight off infection.",
          "Replace fluid, electrolytes, and nutrients.",
          "Provide medication to raise blood pressure."
        ],
        "answer": "Replace fluid, electrolytes, and nutrients.",
        "explanation": "Total parenteral nutrition is an intravenous solution composed of nutrients and electrolytes to replace the ones the patient is not eating or losing. TPN does not stimulate the appetite. TPN does not contain blood pressure medication or antibiotics.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the purpose and procedure for initiation and maintenance of intravenous therapy.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient presents to the emergency department with reports of vomiting and diarrhea for the past 48 hours. The health care provider orders isotonic intravenous (IV) therapy. Which IV will the nurse prepare?",
        "options": [
          "0.225% sodium chloride (1/4 NS)",
          "0.45% sodium chloride (1/2 NS)",
          "0.9% sodium chloride (NS)",
          "3% sodium chloride (3% NaCl)"
        ],
        "answer": "0.9% sodium chloride (NS)",
        "explanation": "Patients with prolonged vomiting and diarrhea become hypovolemic. A solution to replace extracellular volume is 0.9% sodium chloride, which is an isotonic solution. 0.225% and 0.45% sodium chloride are hypotonic. 3% sodium chloride is hypertonic.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the purpose and procedure for initiation and maintenance of intravenous therapy.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse administering a diuretic to a patient is teaching about foods to increase in the diet. Which food choices by the patient will best indicate successful teaching?",
        "options": [
          "Milk and cheese",
          "Potatoes and fresh fruit",
          "Canned soups and vegetables",
          "Whole grains and dark green leafy vegetables"
        ],
        "answer": "Potatoes and fresh fruit",
        "explanation": "Potatoes and fruits are high in potassium. Milk and cheese are high in calcium. Canned soups and vegetables are high in sodium. Whole grains and dark green leafy vegetables are high in magnesium.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify risk factors for fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is evaluating the effectiveness of the intravenous fluid therapy in a patient with hypernatremia. Which finding indicates goal achievement?",
        "options": [
          "Urine output increases to 150 mL/hr.",
          "Systolic and diastolic blood pressure decreases.",
          "Serum sodium concentration returns to normal.",
          "Large amounts of emesis and diarrhea decrease."
        ],
        "answer": "Serum sodium concentration returns to normal.",
        "explanation": "Hypernatremia is diagnosed by elevated serum sodium concentration. Blood pressure is not an accurate indicator of hypernatremia. Emesis and diarrhea will not stop because of intravenous therapy. Urine output is influenced by many factors, including extracellular fluid volume. A large dilute urine output can cause further hypernatremia.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is calculating intake and output on a patient. The patient drinks 150 mL of orange juice at breakfast, voids 125 mL after breakfast, vomits 250 mL of greenish fluid, sucks on 60 mL of ice chips, and for lunch consumes 75 mL of chicken broth. Which totals for intake and output will the nurse document in the patient’s medical record?",
        "options": [
          "Intake 255; output 375",
          "Intake 285; output 375",
          "Intake 505; output 125",
          "Intake 535; output 125"
        ],
        "answer": "Intake 255; output 375",
        "explanation": "Intake = 150 mL of orange juice, 60 mL of ice chips (but only counts as 30 since ice chips are half of the amount), and 75 mL of chicken broth; 150 + 30 + 75 = 255. Output = 125 mL of urine (void) and 250 mL of vomitus; 125 + 250 = 375.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe how to measure and record fluid intake and output.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which assessment finding should cause a nurse to further assess for extracellular fluid volume deficit?",
        "options": [
          "Moist mucous membranes",
          "Postural hypotension",
          "Supple skin turgor",
          "Pitting edema"
        ],
        "answer": "Postural hypotension",
        "explanation": "Physical examination findings of deficit include postural hypotension, tachycardia, thready pulse, dry mucous membranes, and poor skin turgor. Pitting edema indicates that the patient may be retaining excess extracellular fluid.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Choose appropriate clinical assessments for specific fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is to receive 1000 mL of 0.9% sodium chloride intravenously at a rate of 125 mL/hr. The nurse is using microdrip gravity drip tubing. Which rate will the nurse calculate for the minute flow rate (drops/min)?",
        "options": [
          "12 drops/min",
          "24 drops/min",
          "125 drops/min",
          "150 drops/min"
        ],
        "answer": "125 drops/min",
        "explanation": "Microdrip tubing delivers 60 drops/mL. Calculation for a rate of 125 mL/hr using microdrip tubing: (125 mL/1 hr)(60 drops/1 mL)(1 hr/60 min) = 125 drop/min.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Calculate an intravenous flow rate.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse begins infusing a 250-mL bag of IV fluid at 1845 on Monday and programs the pump to infuse at 50 mL/hr. At what time should the infusion be completed?",
        "options": [
          "2300 Monday",
          "2345 Monday",
          "0015 Tuesday",
          "0045 Tuesday"
        ],
        "answer": "2345 Monday",
        "explanation": "250 mL ÷ 50 mL/hr = 5 hr 1845 + 5 hr = 2345, which would be 2345 on Monday.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Calculate an intravenous flow rate.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse caring for a diabetic patient with a bowel obstruction has orders to ensure that the volume of intake matches the output. In the past 4 hours, the patient received dextrose 5% with 0.9% sodium chloride through a 22-gauge catheter infusing at 150 mL/hr and has eaten 200 mL of ice chips. The patient also has an NG suction tube set to low continuous suction that had 300-mL output. The patient has voided 400 mL of urine. After reporting these values to the health care provider, which order does the nurse anticipate?",
        "options": [
          "Add a potassium supplement to replace loss from output.",
          "Decrease the rate of intravenous fluids to 100 mL/hr.",
          "Administer a diuretic to prevent fluid volume excess.",
          "Discontinue the nasogastric suctioning."
        ],
        "answer": "Add a potassium supplement to replace loss from output.",
        "explanation": "The total fluid intake and output equals 700 mL, which meets the provider goals. Patients with nasogastric suctioning are at risk for potassium deficit, so the nurse would anticipate a potassium supplement to correct this condition. Remember to record half the volume of ice chips when calculating intake. The other measures would be unnecessary because the net fluid volume is equal.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe how to measure and record fluid intake and output.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who is receiving peripheral intravenous (IV) therapy. When the nurse is flushing the patient’s peripheral IV, the patient reports pain. Upon assessment, the nurse notices a red streak that is warm to the touch. What is the nurse’s initial action?",
        "options": [
          "Record a phlebitis grade of 4.",
          "Assign an infiltration grade.",
          "Apply moist compress.",
          "Discontinue the IV."
        ],
        "answer": "Discontinue the IV.",
        "explanation": "The IV site has phlebitis. The nurse should discontinue the IV. The phlebitis score is 3. The site has phlebitis, not infiltration. A moist compress may be needed after the IV is discontinued.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe potential complications of intravenous therapy and what to do if they occur.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is assisting the health care provider in inserting a central line. Which action indicates the nurse is following the recommended bundle protocol to reduce central line-associated bloodstream infections (CLABSI)?",
        "options": [
          "Preps skin with povidone-iodine solution.",
          "Suggests the femoral vein for insertion site.",
          "Applies double gloving without hand hygiene.",
          "Uses chlorhexidine skin antisepsis prior to insertion."
        ],
        "answer": "Uses chlorhexidine skin antisepsis prior to insertion.",
        "explanation": "A recommended bundle at insertion of a central line is hand hygiene prior to catheter insertion, use of maximum sterile barrier precautions upon insertion, chlorhexidine skin antisepsis prior to insertion and during dressing changes, avoidance of the femoral vein for central venous access for adults, and daily evaluation of line necessity, with prompt removal of nonessential lines. Povidone-iodine is not recommended.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss purpose and procedure for initiation and maintenance of intravenous therapy.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a group of patients. Which patient will the nurse see first?",
        "options": [
          "A patient with D5W hanging with the blood",
          "A patient with type A blood receiving type O blood",
          "A patient with intravenous potassium chloride that is diluted",
          "A patient with a right mastectomy and an intravenous site in the left arm"
        ],
        "answer": "A patient with D5W hanging with the blood",
        "explanation": "The nurse will see the patient with D5W and blood to prevent a medication error. When preparing to administer blood, prime the tubing with 0.9% sodium chloride (normal saline) to prevent hemolysis or breakdown of RBCs. All the rest are normal. A patient with type A blood can receive type O. Type O is considered the universal donor. A patient with a mastectomy should have the IV in the other arm. Potassium chloride should be diluted, and it is never given IV push.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is administering a blood transfusion. Which assessment finding will the nurse report immediately?",
        "options": [
          "Blood pressure 110/60",
          "Temperature 101.3° F",
          "Poor skin turgor and pallor",
          "Heart rate of 100 beats/min"
        ],
        "answer": "Temperature 101.3° F",
        "explanation": "A fever should be reported immediately, and the blood transfusion stopped. All other assessment findings are expected. Blood is given to elevate blood pressure, improve pallor, and decrease tachycardia.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the procedure for initiating a blood transfusion and interventions to manage a transfusion reaction.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse has just received a bag of packed red blood cells (RBCs) for a patient. What is the longest time the nurse can let the blood infuse?",
        "options": [
          "30 minutes",
          "2 hours",
          "4 hours",
          "6 hours"
        ],
        "answer": "4 hours",
        "explanation": "Ideally a unit of whole blood or packed RBCs is transfused in 2 hours. This time can be lengthened to 4 hours if the patient is at risk for extracellular volume excess. Beyond 4 hours there is a risk for bacterial contamination of the blood.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss the procedure for initiating a blood transfusion and interventions to manage a transfusion reaction.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has an acute intravascular hemolytic reaction to a blood transfusion. After discontinuing the blood transfusion, which is the nurse’s next action?",
        "options": [
          "Discontinue the IV catheter.",
          "Return the blood to the blood bank.",
          "Run normal saline through the existing tubing.",
          "Start normal saline at TKO rate using new tubing."
        ],
        "answer": "Start normal saline at TKO rate using new tubing.",
        "explanation": "The nurse should first attach new tubing and begin running in normal saline at a rate to keep the vein open, in case any medications need to be delivered through an IV site. The existing tubing should not be used because that would infuse the blood in the tubing into the patient. It is necessary to preserve the IV catheter in place for IV access to treat the patient. After the patient has been assessed and stabilized, the blood can be returned to the blood bank.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the procedure for initiating a blood transfusion and interventions to manage a transfusion reaction.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse assessing a patient who is receiving a blood transfusion finds that the patient is anxiously fidgeting in bed. The patient is afebrile but dyspneic. The nurse auscultates crackles in both lung bases and sees jugular vein distention. On which transfusion complication will the nurse focus interventions?",
        "options": [
          "Fluid volume excess",
          "Hemolytic reaction",
          "Anaphylactic shock",
          "Septicemia"
        ],
        "answer": "Fluid volume excess",
        "explanation": "The signs and symptoms are concurrent with fluid volume excess. Anaphylactic shock would have presented with urticaria, dyspnea, and hypotension. Septicemia would include a fever. A hemolytic reaction would consist of flank pain, chills, and fever.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the procedure for initiating a blood transfusion and interventions to manage a transfusion reaction.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse preparing to start a blood transfusion will use which type of tubing?",
        "options": [
          "Two-way valves to allow the patient’s blood to mix and warm the blood transfusing",
          "An injection port to mix additional electrolytes into the blood",
          "One with a filter to ensure that clots do not enter the patient",
          "An air vent to let bubbles into the blood"
        ],
        "answer": "One with a filter to ensure that clots do not enter the patient",
        "explanation": "When administering a transfusion, you need an appropriate-size IV catheter and blood administration tubing that has a special in-line filter. The patient’s blood should not be mixed with the infusion blood. Air bubbles should not be allowed to enter the blood. The only substance compatible with blood is normal saline; no additives should be mixed with the infusing blood.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the procedure for initiating a blood transfusion and interventions to manage a transfusion reaction.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with hyperkalemia. Which body system assessment is the priority?",
        "options": [
          "Gastrointestinal",
          "Neurological",
          "Respiratory",
          "Cardiac"
        ],
        "answer": "Cardiac",
        "explanation": "Cardiac is the priority. Hyperkalemia places the patient at risk for potentially serious dysrhythmias and cardiac arrest. Potassium balance is necessary for cardiac function. Respiratory is the priority with hypokalemia. Monitoring of gastrointestinal and neurological systems would be indicated for other electrolyte imbalances.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which assessment finding will the nurse expect for a patient with the following laboratory values: sodium 145 mEq/L, potassium 4.5 mEq/L, calcium 4.5 mg/dL?",
        "options": [
          "Weak quadriceps muscles",
          "Decreased deep tendon reflexes",
          "Light-headedness when standing up",
          "Tingling of extremities with possible tetany"
        ],
        "answer": "Tingling of extremities with possible tetany",
        "explanation": "This patient has hypocalcemia because the normal calcium range is 8.4 to 10.5 mg/dL. Hypocalcemia causes muscle tetany, positive Chvostek’s sign, and tingling of the extremities. Sodium and potassium values are within their normal ranges: sodium 135 to 145 mEq/L; potassium 3.5 to 5.0 mEq/L. Light-headedness when standing up is a manifestation of ECV deficit or sometimes hypokalemia. Weak quadriceps muscles are associated with potassium imbalances. Decreased deep tendon reflexes are related to hypercalcemia or hypermagnesemia.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Choose appropriate clinical assessments for specific fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "While the nurse is taking a patient history, the nurse discovers the patient has a type of diabetes that results from a head injury and does not require insulin. Which dietary change should the nurse share with the patient?",
        "options": [
          "Reduce the quantity of carbohydrates ingested to lower blood sugar.",
          "Include a serving of dairy in each meal to elevate calcium levels.",
          "Drink plenty of fluids throughout the day to stay hydrated.",
          "Avoid foods high in acid to avoid metabolic acidosis."
        ],
        "answer": "Drink plenty of fluids throughout the day to stay hydrated.",
        "explanation": "The patient has diabetes insipidus, which places the patient at risk for dehydration and hypernatremia. Dehydration should be prevented by drinking plenty of fluids to replace the extra water excreted in the urine. Foods high in acid are not what causes metabolic acidosis. A reduction in carbohydrates to lower blood sugar will not help a patient with diabetes insipidus but it may help a patient with diabetes mellitus. Calcium-rich dairy products would be recommended for a hypocalcemic patient.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply the nursing process when caring for patients with fluid, electrolyte, and acid-base imbalances.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is selecting a site to insert an intravenous (IV) catheter on an adult. Which actions will the nurse take? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Check for contraindications to the extremity.",
          "Start proximally and move distally on the arm.",
          "Choose a vein with minimal curvature.",
          "Choose the patient’s dominant arm.",
          "Select a vein that is rigid.",
          "Avoid areas of flexion."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Check for contraindications to the extremity.",
          "Choose a vein with minimal curvature.",
          "Avoid areas of flexion."
        ],
        "explanation": "The vein should be relatively straight to avoid catheter occlusion. Contraindications to starting an IV catheter are conditions such as mastectomy, AV fistula, and central line in the extremity and should be checked before initiation of IV. Avoid areas of flexion if possible. The nurse should start distally and move proximally, choosing the nondominant arm if possible. The nurse should feel for the best location; a good vein should feel spongy; a rigid vein should be avoided because it might have had previous trauma or damage.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the purpose and procedure for initiation and maintenance of intravenous therapy.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which assessments will alert the nurse that a patient’s IV has infiltrated? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Edema of the extremity near the insertion site",
          "Reddish streak proximal to the insertion site",
          "Skin discolored or pale in appearance",
          "Pain and warmth at the insertion site",
          "Palpable venous cord",
          "Skin cool to the touch"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Edema of the extremity near the insertion site",
          "Skin discolored or pale in appearance",
          "Skin cool to the touch"
        ],
        "explanation": "Infiltration results in skin that is edematous near the IV insertion site. Skin is cool to the touch and may be pale or discolored. Pain, warmth, erythema, a reddish streak, and a palpable venous cord are all symptoms of phlebitis.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe potential complications of intravenous therapy and what to do if they occur.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is discontinuing a patient’s peripheral IV access. Which actions should the nurse take? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Wear sterile gloves and a mask.",
          "Stop the infusion before removing the IV catheter.",
          "Use scissors to remove the IV site dressing and tape.",
          "Apply firm pressure with sterile gauze during removal.",
          "Keep the catheter parallel to the skin while removing it.",
          "Apply pressure to the site for 2 to 3 minutes after removal."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Stop the infusion before removing the IV catheter.",
          "Keep the catheter parallel to the skin while removing it.",
          "Apply pressure to the site for 2 to 3 minutes after removal."
        ],
        "explanation": "The nurse should stop the infusion before removing the IV catheter, so the fluid does not drip on the patient’s skin; keep the catheter parallel to the skin while removing it to reduce trauma to the vein; and apply pressure to the site for 2 to 3 minutes after removal to decrease bleeding from the site. Scissors should not be used because they may accidentally cut the catheter or tubing or may injure the patient. During removal of the IV catheter, light pressure, not firm pressure, is indicated to prevent trauma. Clean gloves are used for discontinuing a peripheral IV access because gloved hands will handle the external dressing, tubing, and tape, which are not sterile.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain how to change intravenous solutions and tubing and discontinue an infusion.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has 250 mL of a jejunostomy feeding with 30 mL of water before and after feeding and 200 mL of urine. Thirty minutes later the patient has 100 mL of diarrhea. At 1300 the patient receives 150 mL of blood and voids another 200 mL. Calculate the patient’s intake. Record your answer as a whole number. _____ mL ",
        "options": [
          "420",
          "440",
          "460",
          "480"
        ],
        "explanation": "The patient’s fluid intake is 250 mL of feeding, 60 mL of water (30 mL before and after), and 150 blood: 250 + 60 + 150 = 460 mL. Fluid intake includes all liquids that a person eats (e.g., gelatin, ice cream, soup), drinks (e.g., water, coffee, juice), or receives through nasogastric or jejunostomy feeding tubes. IV fluids (continuous infusions and intermittent IV piggybacks) and blood components also are sources of intake. Fluid output includes urine, diarrhea, vomitus, gastric suction, and drainage from postsurgical wounds or other tubes.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe how to measure and record fluid intake and output.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is monitoring patients for fluid and electrolyte and acid-base imbalances. Match the body’s regulators to the function it provides.",
        "matching": [
          "Antidiuretic hormone",
          "Angiotensin II",
          "Aldosterone",
          "Atrial natriuretic peptide",
          "Bicarbonate"
        ],
        "options": [
          "Increases excretion of sodium and water.",
          "Reduces excretion of sodium and water.",
          "Reduces excretion of water.",
          "Major buffer in the extracellular fluid.",
          "Vasoconstricts and stimulates aldosterone release."
        ],
        "answer": {
          "Antidiuretic hormone": "Reduces excretion of water.",
          "Angiotensin II": "Vasoconstricts and stimulates aldosterone release.",
          "Aldosterone": "Reduces excretion of sodium and water.",
          "Atrial natriuretic peptide": "Increases excretion of sodium and water.",
          "Bicarbonate": "Major buffer in the extracellular fluid."
        },
        "explanation": "Antidiuretic hormone (ADH) acts to reduce the excretion of water, thereby conserving fluid within the body. Angiotensin II, on the other hand, functions by vasoconstriction and stimulation of aldosterone release, aiming to retain both water and sodium in the body. Aldosterone, another hormone, works to reduce the excretion of both sodium and water, aiding in fluid balance regulation. Conversely, atrial natriuretic peptide (ANP) acts to increase the excretion of sodium and water, promoting fluid loss from the body. Additionally, bicarbonate serves as a major buffer in the extracellular fluid, helping to maintain the body's acid-base balance. Understanding the roles of these regulators is essential in planning interventions to address fluid and electrolyte imbalances, contributing to physiological adaptation and overall patient care.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the processes involved in regulating extracellular fluid volume, body fluid osmolality, and fluid distribution.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      }
    ],
    "chapter43": [
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a young-adult patient on the medical-surgical unit. When doing midnight checks, the nurse observes the patient awake, putting a puzzle together. Which information will the nurse consider to best explain this finding?",
        "options": [
          "The patient misses family and is lonely.",
          "The patient was waiting to talk with the nurse.",
          "The patient has been kept up with the noise on the unit.",
          "The patient’s sleep-wake cycle preference is late evening."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient’s sleep-wake cycle preference is late evening.",
        "explanation": "This patient is awake and alert enough to do a puzzle. The individual’s sleep-wake preference is probably late evening. All persons have biological clocks that synchronize their sleep-wake cycle. This explains why some individuals fall asleep in the early evening, whereas others go to bed at midnight or early morning. Waiting to talk with the nurse, being lonely, and noise on the unit may contribute to lack of sleep, but the best explanation for the patient being awake is the biological clock.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Explain the effect the 24-hour sleep-wake cycle has on biological function.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is providing an educational session on sleep regulation for new nurses in the Sleep Disorder Treatment Center. Which statement by the nurses will best indicate that the teaching is effective?",
        "options": [
          "“If the patient has a disease process in the central nervous system, it can influence the functions of sleep.”",
          "“If the patient has a disease process in the cranial nerves, it can influence the functions of sleep.”",
          "“If the patient has an interruption in the urinary pathways, it can influence the functions of sleep.”",
          "“If the patient has an interruption in the spinal reflexes, it can influence the functions of sleep.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“If the patient has a disease process in the central nervous system, it can influence the functions of sleep.”",
        "explanation": "Sleep involves a sequence of physiological states maintained by the central nervous system. It is associated with changes in the peripheral nervous, endocrine, cardiovascular, respiratory, and muscular systems. A disease process associated with the cranial nerves, urinary pathway, or spinal reflexes may influence a person’s ability to sleep, but the best answer is the central nervous system.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss mechanisms that regulate sleep.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who reports having trouble sleeping. Which action will the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Suggest snug-fitting nightwear.",
          "Provide a favorite beverage.",
          "Encourage deep breathing.",
          "Walk with the patient."
        ],
        "answer": "Encourage deep breathing.",
        "explanation": "Relaxation exercises such as slow, deep breathing for 1 or 2 minutes relieve tension and prepare the body for rest. Instruct patients to wear loose-fitting nightwear. Walking and drinking a favorite beverage would not necessarily encourage sleep.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss mechanisms that regulate sleep.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient in the sleep lab. Which assessment finding indicates to the nurse that the patient is in stage 4 NREM?",
        "options": [
          "The patient awakens easily.",
          "The patient’s eyes rapidly move.",
          "The patient is difficult to awaken.",
          "The patient’s vital signs are elevated."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient is difficult to awaken.",
        "explanation": "The patient is difficult to arouse, vital signs are significantly lower, and this stage lasts about 15 to 30 minutes. Stage 4 NREM is the deepest stage of sleep. Lighter sleep is seen in stages 1 and 2, where the patient awakens easily. REM sleep is characterized by rapid eye movement.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe the stages of a normal sleep cycle.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching the staff about the sleep cycle. Which sequence will the nurse include in the teaching session?",
        "options": [
          "NREM Stage 1, 2, 3, 4, REM",
          "NREM Stage 1, 2, 3, 4, 3, 2, 1, REM",
          "NREM Stage 1, 2, 3, 4, REM, 4, 3, 2 REM",
          "NREM Stage 1, 2, 3, 4, 3, 2, REM"
        ],
        "answer": "NREM Stage 1, 2, 3, 4, 3, 2, REM",
        "explanation": "The cyclical pattern usually progresses from stage 1 through stage 4 of NREM, followed by a reversal from stages 4 to 3 to 2, ending with a period of REM sleep. The others are incorrect sequences.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe the stages of a normal sleep cycle.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which nursing observation of the patient in intensive care indicates the patient is sleeping comfortably during NREM sleep?",
        "options": [
          "Eyes closed, lying quietly, respirations 12, heart rate 60",
          "Eyes closed, tossing in bed, respirations 18, heart rate 80",
          "Eyes closed, mumbling to self, respirations 16, heart rate 68",
          "Eyes closed, lying supine in bed, respirations 22, heart rate 66"
        ],
        "answer": "Eyes closed, lying quietly, respirations 12, heart rate 60",
        "explanation": "During NREM sleep, biological functions slow. During sleep, the heart rate decreases to 60 beats/min or less. The patient experiences decreased respirations, blood pressure, and muscle tone. Heart rates above 60 are too high and respirations of 22 are too high to indicate comfortable NREM sleep.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Explain the functions of sleep.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is teaching a new mother about the sleep requirements of a neonate. Which comment by the patient indicates a correct understanding of the teaching?",
        "options": [
          "“I can’t wait to get the baby home to play with the brothers and sisters.”",
          "“I will ask my mom to come after the first week, when the baby is more alert.”",
          "“I can get the baby on a sleeping schedule the first week while my mom is here.”",
          "“I won’t be able to nap during the day because the baby will be awake.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“I will ask my mom to come after the first week, when the baby is more alert.”",
        "explanation": "The patient indicates an understanding when asking the mother to come after the first week. The neonate up to the age of 3 months averages about 16 hours of sleep a day, sleeping almost constantly during the first week. The baby will sleep rather than play. The baby will not be on a sleeping schedule the first week home. The mother will be able to nap since the baby sleeps 16 hours a day.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast the sleep requirements of different age-groups.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is discussing lack of sleep with a middle-aged adult. Which area should the nurse most likely assess to determine a possible cause of the lack of sleep?",
        "options": [
          "Anxiety",
          "Loud teenagers",
          "Caring for pets",
          "Late night television"
        ],
        "answer": "Anxiety",
        "explanation": "During middle adulthood, the total time spent sleeping at night begins to decline. Anxiety, depression, and certain physical illnesses can affect sleep, and women can experience menopausal symptoms. Insomnia is common because of the changes and stresses associated with middle age. Teenagers, caring for pets, and late-night television can influence the amount of sleep; however, these are not the most common causes of insomnia in this age-group.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast the sleep requirements of different age-groups.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A parent is discussing the sleep needs of a preschooler with the nurse. Which information will the nurse share with the parent?",
        "options": [
          "“Most preschoolers sleep soundly all night long.”",
          "“It is important that the 5 year old get a nap every day.”",
          "“On average, the preschooler needs to sleep 10 hours a night.”",
          "“Preschoolers may have trouble settling down after a busy day.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Preschoolers may have trouble settling down after a busy day.”",
        "explanation": "The preschooler usually has difficulty relaxing or settling down after long, active days. By the age of 5, naps are rare for children, except those for whom a siesta is a custom. Preschoolers frequently awaken during the night. On average, a preschooler needs about 12 hours of sleep.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast the sleep requirements of different age-groups.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is having a conversation with an adolescent regarding the need for sleep. The adolescent states that it is common to stay up with friends several nights a week. Which action should the nurse take next?",
        "options": [
          "Talk with the adolescent’s parent about staying up with friends and the need for sleep.",
          "Discuss with the adolescent sleep needs and the effects of excessive daytime sleepiness.",
          "Refer the adolescent for counseling about alcohol abuse problems.",
          "Take no action for this normal occurrence."
        ],
        "answer": "Discuss with the adolescent sleep needs and the effects of excessive daytime sleepiness.",
        "explanation": "Discussion regarding adolescent sleep needs should first occur with the adolescent. Although it may be common for this adolescent to want to visit with friends and experience activities that go late into the night, these activities can and do impact the hours of sleep and the physical needs of the adolescent, no matter the reason for the late nights, and they do need to be addressed. The nurse will address the adolescent, not the parents. Addressing alcohol abuse problems is not the next step but may be required later. While staying up late may be a normal occurrence for this adolescent, action is required.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast the sleep requirements of different age-groups.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is completing an assessment on an older-adult patient who is having difficulty falling asleep. Which condition will the nurse further assess for in this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Depression",
          "Mild fatigue",
          "Hypertension",
          "Hypothyroidism"
        ],
        "answer": "Depression",
        "explanation": "Older adults and other individuals who experience depressive mood problems experience delays in falling asleep, earlier appearance of REM sleep, frequent awakening, feelings of sleeping poorly, and daytime sleepiness. A person who is moderately fatigued usually achieves restful sleep, especially if the fatigue is the result of enjoyable work or exercise. Hypertension often causes early-morning awakening and fatigue. Alcohol speeds the onset of sleep. Hypothyroidism decreases stage 4 sleep.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify factors that normally promote and disrupt sleep.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for an adolescent post-appendectomy who is reporting difficulty falling asleep. Which intervention will be most appropriate?",
        "options": [
          "Close the door to decrease noise from unit activities.",
          "Adjust temperature in the patient’s room to 21° C (70° F).",
          "Ensure that the night-light in the patient’s room is working.",
          "Encourage the discontinuation of a soda and chocolate as a nightly snack."
        ],
        "answer": "Encourage the discontinuation of a soda and chocolate as a nightly snack.",
        "explanation": "Discontinuing the soda and chocolate nightly snack will be most beneficial for this patient since it has two factors that will cause difficulty falling asleep. Coffee, tea, colas, and chocolate act as stimulants, causing a person to stay awake or to awaken throughout the night. Personal preference influences the temperature of the room, as well as the lighting of the room. Noise can be a factor in the unit and can awaken the patient, but caffeine can make it difficult to fall asleep.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify factors that normally promote and disrupt sleep.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is diagnosed with obstructive sleep apnea. Which assessment is the priority?",
        "options": [
          "Gastrointestinal function",
          "Neurological function",
          "Respiratory status",
          "Circulatory status"
        ],
        "answer": "Respiratory status",
        "explanation": "In obstructive sleep apnea, the upper airway becomes partially or completely blocked, diminishing nasal airflow or stopping it. The person still attempts to breathe because the chest and abdominal movement continue, which results in loud snoring and snorting sounds. According to the ABCs of prioritizing care, airway and respiratory status takes priority over gastrointestinal, circulatory, and neurological functioning.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the characteristics of common sleep disorders.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient has just been diagnosed with narcolepsy. The nurse teaches the patient about management of the condition. Which information from the patient will cause the nurse to intervene?",
        "options": [
          "Takes antidepressant medications.",
          "Naps shorter than 20 minutes.",
          "Sleeps in hot, stuffy room.",
          "Chews gum regularly."
        ],
        "answer": "Sleeps in hot, stuffy room.",
        "explanation": "The nurse will intervene about sitting in a hot, stuffy room as this will make the narcolepsy worse so this needs to be corrected. Patients with narcolepsy need to avoid factors that increase drowsiness (e.g., alcohol, heavy meals, exhausting activities, long-distance driving, and long periods of sitting in hot, stuffy rooms). Patients are treated with antidepressants, and management techniques involve scheduling naps no longer than 20 minutes and chewing gum. Additional management techniques include exercise, light high-protein meals, deep breathing, and taking vitamins.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss the characteristics of common sleep disorders.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has been in holding in the emergency department for 24 hours. The nurse is concerned about the patient’s experiencing sleep deprivation. Which action will be best for the nurse to take?",
        "options": [
          "Expedite the process of obtaining a medical-surgical room for the patient.",
          "Pull the curtains shut, dim the lights, and decrease the number of visitors.",
          "Obtain an order for a hypnotic medication to help the patient sleep.",
          "Ask everyone in the unit to try to be quiet so the patient can sleep."
        ],
        "answer": "Expedite the process of obtaining a medical-surgical room for the patient.",
        "explanation": "The most effective treatment for sleep deprivation is elimination or correction of factors that disrupt the sleep pattern. Obtaining a private room in the medical-surgical unit for the patient will help with decreasing stimuli and promoting more rest than an individual can obtain in an emergency department even with the interventions mentioned.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss characteristics of common sleep disorders.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is completing a sleep assessment on a patient. Which tool will the nurse use to complete the assessment?",
        "options": [
          "Visual analog scale",
          "Cataplexy scale",
          "Polysomnogram",
          "RAS scale"
        ],
        "answer": "Visual analog scale",
        "explanation": "The visual analog scale is utilized for assessing sleep quality. Cataplexy, or sudden muscle weakness during intense emotions such as anger, sadness, or laughter, occurs at any time during the day; there is no cataplexy scale for sleep assessment. A polysomnogram involves the use of EEG, EMG, and EOG to monitor stages of sleep and wakefulness during nighttime sleep; this is used in a sleep laboratory study. Researchers believe that the ascending reticular activating system (RAS) located in the upper brainstem contains special cells that maintain alertness and wakefulness; however, there is no assessment tool called the RAS scale.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Conduct a sleep history for a patient.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is beginning a sleep assessment on a patient. Which question will be most appropriate for the nurse to ask initially?",
        "options": [
          "“What is going on?”",
          "“How are you sleeping?”",
          "“Are you taking any medications?”",
          "“What did you have for dinner last night?”"
        ],
        "answer": "“How are you sleeping?”",
        "explanation": "Sleep is a subjective experience. Only the patient is able to report whether or not it is sufficient and restful. Asking patients how they are sleeping is an introductory question. After this beginning question is asked, problems with sleep such as the nature of the problem, signs and symptoms, onset and duration of the issue, severity, predisposing factors, and the effect on the patient can be assessed. What is going on is too broad and open ended for information about sleep to be obtained specifically. Medications and food intake can be part of the detailed assessment of sleep issues.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Conduct a sleep history for a patient.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse adds a nursing diagnosis of Ineffective Breathing Pattern to a patient’s care plan. Which sleep condition likely caused the nurse to assign this nursing diagnosis?",
        "options": [
          "Insomnia",
          "Narcolepsy",
          "Sleep deprivation",
          "Obstructive sleep apnea"
        ],
        "answer": "Obstructive sleep apnea",
        "explanation": "Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) occurs when the muscles or structures of the oral cavity or throat relax during sleep. The upper airway becomes partially or completely blocked, diminishing airflow or stopping it for as long as 30 seconds. The person still attempts to breathe because chest and abdominal movements continue, resulting in snoring or snorting sounds. With narcolepsy, the person feels an overwhelming wave of sleepiness and falls asleep. Insomnia is characterized by chronic difficulty falling asleep. Sleep deprivation is a condition caused by dyssomnia. OSA is the only one of these conditions that results in blockage of the airway and impacts the ability to breathe.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing diagnoses appropriate for patients with sleep alterations.",
        "top": "Diagnosis",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a postpartum patient whose labor lasted over 28 hours. The patient has not slept since delivering and is disoriented to date and time. Which nursing diagnosis will the nurse document in the patient’s care plan?",
        "options": [
          "Insomnia",
          "Impaired parenting",
          "Ineffective coping",
          "Sleep deprivation"
        ],
        "answer": "Sleep deprivation",
        "explanation": "This patient has been deprived of sleep by staying awake during a 28-hour labor. Disorientation is one potential sign of sleep deprivation. In this scenario, there is a clear cause for the patient’s lack of sleep, and it is a one-time episode. Insomnia, on the other hand, is a chronic disorder whereby patients have difficulty falling asleep, awaken frequently, or sleep only for a short time. This scenario does not indicate that this has been a chronic problem for this patient. Although ineffective coping can manifest as a sleep disturbance, clear evidence shows that it was labor that deprived this patient of sleep, not an inability to cope. It could be difficult to care for an infant when sleep deprived; however, this scenario gives no evidence that this mother displays impaired parenting and is not caring adequately for her child or lacks the skills to do so.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing diagnoses appropriate for patients with sleep alterations.",
        "top": "Diagnosis",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient presents to the clinic with reports of irritability and anxiety, being sleepy during the day, chronically not being able to fall asleep, and being fatigued. Which nursing diagnosis will the nurse document in the plan of care?",
        "options": [
          "Anxiety",
          "Fatigue",
          "Insomnia",
          "Sleep deprivation"
        ],
        "answer": "Insomnia",
        "explanation": "Insomnia is experienced when the patient has chronic difficulty falling asleep, frequent awakenings from sleep, and/or short sleep or nonrestorative sleep. It is the most common sleep-related complaint and includes symptoms such as irritability, excessive daytime sleepiness, not being able to fall asleep, and fatigue. Anxiety is a vague, uneasy feeling of discomfort or dread accompanied by an autonomic response. Fatigue is an overwhelming sustained sense of exhaustion with decreased capacity for physical and mental work at a usual level. Sleep deprivation is a condition caused by dyssomnia and includes symptoms caused by illness, emotional distress, or medications.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing diagnoses appropriate for patients with sleep alterations.",
        "top": "Diagnosis",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is preparing an older-adult patient’s evening medications. Which treatment will the nurse recognize as relatively safe for difficulty sleeping in older adults?",
        "options": [
          "Ramelteon",
          "Benzodiazepine",
          "Antihistamine",
          "Kava"
        ],
        "answer": "Ramelteon",
        "explanation": "Ramelteon, a melatonin receptor agonist, is well tolerated and appears to be effective in improving sleep by improving the circadian rhythm and shortening time to sleep onset. It is safe for long- and short-term use particularly in older adults. The use of benzodiazepines in older adults is potentially dangerous because of the tendency of the drugs to remain active in the body for a longer time. As a result, they also cause respiratory depression, next-day sedation, amnesia, rebound insomnia, and impaired motor functioning and coordination, which leads to increased risk of falls. Caution older adults about using over-the-counter antihistamines because their long duration of action can cause confusion, constipation, and urinary retention. Kava promotes sleep in patients with anxiety; it should be used cautiously because of its potential toxic effects on the liver.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing interventions designed to promote normal sleep cycles for patients of all ages.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient on the medical-surgical unit who is experiencing an exacerbation of asthma. Which intervention will be most appropriate to help this patient sleep?",
        "options": [
          "Place bed in semi-Fowler’s position.",
          "Offer iron-rich foods for meals.",
          "Provide a snack before bedtime.",
          "Encourage the patient to read."
        ],
        "answer": "Place bed in semi-Fowler’s position.",
        "explanation": "Placing the patient in a semi-Fowler’s position eases the work of breathing. Respiratory disease often interferes with sleep. Patients with chronic lung disease such as emphysema or asthma are short of breath and frequently cannot sleep without two or three pillows to raise their heads. Iron-rich food may help a patient with restless legs syndrome. Providing a snack and encouraging the patient to read may be good interventions for patients, but the most appropriate would be raising the head of the bed.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing interventions designed to promote normal sleep cycles for patients of all ages.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A young adult has been hospitalized for an irregular heartbeat (dysrhythmia). The night nurse makes rounds and finds the patient awake. Which action by the nurse is most appropriate?",
        "options": [
          "Inform the patient that it is late and time to go to sleep.",
          "Ask the patient if he/she would like medication for sleep.",
          "Recommend a good movie that is on television tonight.",
          "Take time to sit and talk with the patient about his/her inability to sleep."
        ],
        "answer": "Take time to sit and talk with the patient about his/her inability to sleep.",
        "explanation": "A nurse on the night shift needs to take time to sit and talk with patients unable to sleep. This helps to determine the factors keeping patients awake. Assessment is the first step of the nursing process; therefore, assessment needs to be done first and involves ascertaining the cause of the patient’s inability to sleep. Patients who are admitted to the hospital for uncertain diagnoses can be stressed and worried about the testing and outcomes. In addition, a young mother can be worried about the care of her children and those caring for the children. This uncertainty and change in routine can cause difficulty in resting or falling asleep. A distraction such as a television may or may not work for the patient. After assessment is completed, a sedative may or may not be in order. Telling the patient that it is late and time to go to sleep is not a therapeutic response for an adult who is under stress.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing interventions designed to promote normal sleep cycles for patients of all ages.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is evaluating outcomes for the patient diagnosed with insomnia. Which key principle will the nurse consider during this process?",
        "options": [
          "The patient is the best evaluator of sleep.",
          "The nurse is the best evaluator of sleep.",
          "Effective interventions are the best evaluators of sleep.",
          "Observations of the patient are the best evaluators of sleep."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient is the best evaluator of sleep.",
        "explanation": "With regard to problems with sleep, the patient is the source for evaluating outcomes. The patient is the only one who knows whether sleep problems have improved and what has been successful. Interventions are not the best indicator; achievement of goals according to the patient is the best. Observations do provide needed data, but in the case of insomnia, the patient is the source for evaluating the restfulness of sleep.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe ways to evaluate the effects of sleep therapies.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is experiencing sleep deprivation. Which statement by the patient will indicate to the nurse that outcomes are being met?",
        "options": [
          "“I wake up only once a night to go to the bathroom.”",
          "“I feel rested when I wake up in the morning.”",
          "“I go to sleep within 30 minutes of lying down.”",
          "“I only take a 20-minute nap during the day.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“I feel rested when I wake up in the morning.”",
        "explanation": "Being able to sleep and feeling rested would indicate that outcomes are being met for sleep deprivation. Limiting a nap to 20 minutes is an intervention to promote sleep. Going to sleep within 30 minutes indicates a goal for insomnia. Waking up only once may indicate nocturia is improving but does not relate to sleep deprivation.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Describe ways to evaluate the effects of sleep therapies.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "An older-adult patient is visiting the clinic after a fall during the night. The nurse obtains information on what medications the patient takes. Which medication most likely contributed to the patient’s fall?",
        "options": [
          "Melatonin",
          "L-tryptophan",
          "Benzodiazepine",
          "Iron supplement"
        ],
        "answer": "Benzodiazepine",
        "explanation": "The most likely cause is a benzodiazepine. If older patients who were recently continent, ambulatory, and alert become incontinent or confused and/or demonstrate impaired mobility, the use of benzodiazepines needs to be considered as a possible cause. This can contribute to a fall in an older adult. Short-term use of melatonin has been found to be safe, with mild side effects of nausea, headache, and dizziness being infrequent. Iron supplements may be given to patients with restless legs syndrome. Some substances such as L-tryptophan, a natural protein found in foods such as milk, cheese, and meats, promote sleep; while it does promote sleep, it is not the most likely to cause mobility problems.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Conduct a sleep history for a patient.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has not been able to sleep well while in the hospital, leading to a disrupted sleep-wake cycle. Which assessment findings will the nurse monitor for in this patient? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Changes in physiological function such as temperature",
          "Decreased appetite and weight loss",
          "Anxiety, irritability, and restlessness",
          "Shortness of breath and chest pain",
          "Nausea, vomiting, and diarrhea",
          "Impaired judgment"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Changes in physiological function such as temperature",
          "Decreased appetite and weight loss",
          "Anxiety, irritability, and restlessness",
          "Impaired judgment"
        ],
        "explanation": "The biological rhythm of sleep frequently becomes synchronized with other body functions. Changes in body temperature correlate with sleep pattern. When the sleep-wake cycle becomes disrupted, changes in physiological function such as temperature can occur. Patients can experience decreased appetite, loss of weight, anxiety, restlessness, irritability, and impaired judgment. Gastrointestinal and respiratory/cardiovascular symptoms such as shortness of breath and chest pain are not symptoms of a disrupted sleep cycle.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the effect that the 24-hour sleep-wake cycle has on biological function.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient in the intensive care unit who is having trouble sleeping. The nurse explains the purpose of sleep and its benefits. Which information will the nurse include in the teaching session? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "NREM sleep contributes to body tissue restoration.",
          "During NREM sleep, biological functions increase.",
          "Restful sleep preserves cardiac function.",
          "Sleep contributes to cognitive restoration.",
          "REM sleep decreases cortical activity."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "NREM sleep contributes to body tissue restoration.",
          "Restful sleep preserves cardiac function.",
          "Sleep contributes to cognitive restoration."
        ],
        "explanation": "Sleep contributes to physiological and psychological restoration. NREM sleep contributes to body tissue restoration. It allows the body to rest and conserve energy. This benefits the cardiac system by allowing the heart to beat fewer times each minute. During stage 4, the body releases growth hormone for renewal and repair of specialized cells such as the brain. During NREM sleep, biological functions slow. REM sleep is necessary for brain tissue restoration and cognitive restoration and is associated with a change in cerebral blood flow and increased cortical activity.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the functions of sleep.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient and the nurse discuss the need for sleep. After the discussion, the patient is able to state factors that hinder sleep. Which statements indicate the patient has a good understanding of the teaching? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "“Drinking coffee at 7 PM could interrupt my sleep.”",
          "“Staying up late for a party can interrupt sleep patterns.”",
          "“Exercising 2 hours before bedtime can decrease relaxation.”",
          "“Changing the time of day that I eat dinner can disrupt sleep.”",
          "“Worrying about work can disrupt my sleep.”",
          "“Taking an antacid can decrease sleep.”"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "“Drinking coffee at 7 PM could interrupt my sleep.”",
          "“Staying up late for a party can interrupt sleep patterns.”",
          "“Changing the time of day that I eat dinner can disrupt sleep.”",
          "“Worrying about work can disrupt my sleep.”"
        ],
        "explanation": "Caffeine, alcohol, and nicotine consumed late in the evening produce insomnia. Worry over personal problems or situations frequently disrupts sleep. Alterations in routines, including changing mealtimes and staying up late at night for social activities, can disrupt sleep. Exercising 2 hours before bedtime actually increases a sense of fatigue and promotes relaxation. Taking an antacid does not decrease sleep.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify factors that normally promote and disrupt sleep.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A community health nurse is providing an educational session at the senior center on how to promote sleep. Which practices should the nurse recommend? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Take a nap in the afternoon.",
          "Sleep where you sleep best.",
          "Use sedatives as a last resort.",
          "Watch television right before sleep.",
          "Decrease fluids 2 to 4 hours before sleep.",
          "Get up if unable to fall asleep in 20 minutes."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Sleep where you sleep best.",
          "Use sedatives as a last resort.",
          "Decrease fluids 2 to 4 hours before sleep.",
          "Get up if unable to fall asleep in 20 minutes."
        ],
        "explanation": ", C, E, F The nurse should instruct the patient to sleep where he or she sleeps best, to use sedatives as a last resort, to decrease fluid intake to cut down on bathroom trips, and, if unable to sleep in 20 minutes, to get up out of bed. Naps should be eliminated if they are not part of the individual’s routine schedule, and if naps are taken, they should be limited to 20 minutes or less a day. Television can stimulate and disrupt sleep patterns.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing interventions designed to promote normal sleep cycles for patients of all ages.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is caring for a group of patients who have sleeping disruptions. Match the condition to the intervention the nurse will use.",
        "matching": [
          "Cataplexy",
          "Narcolepsy",
          "Insomnia",
          "Hiatal hernia",
          "Sleepwalking",
          "Obstructive sleep apnea"
        ],
        "options": [
          "Use continuous positive airway pressure.",
          "Offer a small meal several hours before bedtime.",
          "Administer antidepressants.",
          "Administer modafinil.",
          "Do not startle.",
          "Administer benzodiazepine-like drugs."
        ],
        "answer": {
          "Cataplexy": "Administer antidepressants.",
          "Narcolepsy": "Administer modafinil.",
          "Insomnia": "Administer benzodiazepine-like drugs.",
          "Hiatal hernia": "Offer a small meal several hours before bedtime.",
          "Sleepwalking": "Do not startle.",
          "Obstructive sleep apnea": "Use continuous positive airway pressure."
        },
        "explanation": "Cataplexy, often linked with narcolepsy, involves sudden muscle weakness triggered by emotions. Administering antidepressants helps manage this symptom by regulating relevant neurotransmitters. Narcolepsy, characterized by daytime sleepiness and sudden sleep attacks, is addressed with modafinil, a wakefulness-promoting medication. Insomnia, difficulty sleeping, can be managed with benzodiazepine-like drugs that induce sleep and reduce anxiety. Hiatal hernia discomfort before bed can be minimized by offering a small meal earlier. Sleepwalking individuals should not be startled to prevent confusion or injury. Obstructive sleep apnea is managed with continuous positive airway pressure therapy, ensuring an open airway during sleep. These interventions aim to promote normal sleep cycles, aiding physiological adaptation and aligning with nursing practice objectives.",
        "dif":"Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing interventions designed to promote normal sleep cycles for patients of all ages.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      } 
    ],
    "chapter46": [
      {
        "question": "A nurse is teaching a patient about the urinary system. In which order will the nurse present the structures, following the flow of urine?",
        "options": [
          "Kidney, urethra, bladder, ureters",
          "Kidney, ureters, bladder, urethra",
          "Bladder, kidney, ureters, urethra",
          "Bladder, kidney, urethra, ureters"
        ],
        "answer": "Kidney, ureters, bladder, urethra",
        "explanation": "The flow of urine follows these structures: kidney, ureters, bladder, and urethra.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Explain the function and role of urinary system structures in urine formation and elimination.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is reviewing urinary laboratory results. Which finding will cause the nurse to follow up?",
        "options": [
          "Protein level of 2 mg/100 mL",
          "Urine output of 80 mL/hr",
          "Specific gravity of 1.036",
          "pH of 6.4"
        ],
        "answer": "Specific gravity of 1.036",
        "explanation": "Dehydration, reduced renal blood flow, and increase in antidiuretic hormone secretion elevate specific gravity. Normal specific gravity is 1.005 to 1.030. An output of 30 mL/hr or less for 2 or more hours would be cause for concern; 80 mL/hr is normal. The normal pH of urine is between 4.6 and 8.0. Protein up to 8 mg/100 mL is acceptable; however, values in excess of this could indicate renal disease.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing implications of common diagnostic tests of the urinary system.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient is experiencing oliguria. Which action should the nurse perform first?",
        "options": [
          "Assess for bladder distention.",
          "Request an order for diuretics.",
          "Increase the patient’s intravenous fluid rate.",
          "Encourage the patient to drink caffeinated beverages."
        ],
        "answer": "Assess for bladder distention.",
        "explanation": "Oliguria is diminished urinary output in relation to fluid intake. The nurse first should gather all assessment data to determine the potential cause of oliguria. It could be that the patient does not have adequate intake, or it could be that the bladder sphincter is not functioning and the patient is retaining water. Increasing fluids is effective if the patient does not have adequate intake or if dehydration occurs. Caffeine can work as a diuretic but is not helpful if an underlying pathology is present. An order for diuretics can be obtained if the patient was retaining water, but this should not be the first action.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Perform a physical assessment focused on urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient requests the nurse’s help to the bedside commode and becomes frustrated when unable to void in front of the nurse. How should the nurse interpret the patient’s inability to void?",
        "options": [
          "The patient can be anxious, making it difficult for abdominal and perineal muscles to relax enough to void.",
          "The patient does not recognize the physiological signals that indicate a need to void.",
          "The patient is lonely and calling the nurse in under false pretenses is a way to get attention.",
          "The patient is not drinking enough fluids to produce adequate urine output."
        ],
        "answer": "The patient can be anxious, making it difficult for abdominal and perineal muscles to relax enough to void.",
        "explanation": "Attempting to void in the presence of another can cause anxiety and tension in the muscles that make voiding difficult. Anxiety can impact bladder emptying due to inadequate relaxation of the pelvic floor muscles and urinary sphincter. The nurse should give the patient privacy and adequate time if appropriate. No evidence suggests that an underlying physiological (does not recognize signals or not drinking enough fluids) or psychological (lonely) condition exists.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify factors that commonly impact urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is having lower abdominal surgery and the nurse inserts an indwelling catheter. What is the rationale for the nurse’s action?",
        "options": [
          "The patient may void uncontrollably during the procedure.",
          "Local trauma sometimes promotes excessive urine incontinence.",
          "Anesthetics can decrease bladder contractility and cause urinary retention.",
          "The patient will not interrupt the procedure by asking to go to the bathroom."
        ],
        "answer": "Anesthetics can decrease bladder contractility and cause urinary retention.",
        "explanation": "Anesthetic agents and other agents given during surgery can decrease bladder contractility and/or sensation of bladder fullness, causing urinary retention. Local trauma during lower abdominal and pelvic surgery sometimes obstructs urine flow, requiring temporary use of an indwelling urinary catheter. The patient is more likely to retain urine rather than experience uncontrollable voiding.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Identify factors that commonly impact urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse, upon reviewing the history, discovers the patient has dysuria. Which assessment finding is consistent with dysuria?",
        "options": [
          "Blood in the urine",
          "Burning upon urination",
          "Immediate, strong desire to void",
          "Awakes from sleep due to urge to void"
        ],
        "answer": "Burning upon urination",
        "explanation": "Dysuria is burning or pain with urination. Hematuria is blood in the urine. Urgency is an immediate and strong desire to void that is not easily deferred. Nocturia is awakening form sleep due to urge to void.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast common alterations associated with urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "An 86-year-old patient is experiencing uncontrollable leakage of urine with a strong desire to void and even leaks on the way to the toilet. Which priority nursing diagnosis will the nurse include in the patient’s plan of care?",
        "options": [
          "Functional urinary incontinence",
          "Urge urinary incontinence",
          "Impaired skin integrity",
          "Urinary retention"
        ],
        "answer": "Urge urinary incontinence",
        "explanation": "Urge urinary incontinence is the leakage of urine associated with a strong urge to void. Patients leak urine on the way to or at the toilet and rush or hurry to the toilet. Urinary retention is the inability to empty the bladder. Functional urinary incontinence is incontinence due to causes outside the urinary tract, such as mobility or cognitive impairments. While Impaired skin integrity can occur, it is not the priority at this time, and there is no data to support this diagnosis.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Identify nursing diagnoses associated with alterations in urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Diagnosis",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient has fallen several times in the past week when attempting to get to the bathroom. The patient gets up 3 or 4 times a night to urinate. Which recommendation by the nurse is most appropriate in correcting this urinary problem?",
        "options": [
          "Limit fluid and caffeine intake before bed.",
          "Leave the bathroom light on to illuminate a pathway.",
          "Practice Kegel exercises to strengthen bladder muscles.",
          "Clear the path to the bathroom of all obstacles before bedtime."
        ],
        "answer": "Limit fluid and caffeine intake before bed.",
        "explanation": "Reducing fluids, especially caffeine and alcohol, before bedtime can reduce nocturia. To prevent nocturia, suggest that the patient avoid drinking fluids 2 hours before bedtime. Clearing a path to the bathroom, illuminating the path, or shortening the distance to the bathroom may reduce falls but will not correct the urination problem. Kegel exercises are useful if a patient is experiencing stress incontinence.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a male patient experiencing urinary retention. Which action should the nurse take first?",
        "options": [
          "Limit fluid intake.",
          "Insert a urinary catheter.",
          "Assist to a standing position.",
          "Ask for a diuretic medication."
        ],
        "answer": "Assist to a standing position.",
        "explanation": "In some patients just helping them to a normal position to void prompts voiding. A urinary catheter would relieve urinary retention, but it is not the first measure; other nursing interventions should be tried before catheterization. Reducing fluids would reduce the amount of urine produced but would not alleviate the urine retention and is usually not recommended unless the retention is severe. Diuretic medication would increase urine production and may worsen the discomfort caused by urine retention.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "Upon palpation, the nurse notices that the bladder is firm and distended; the patient expresses an urge to urinate. Which question is most appropriate?",
        "options": [
          "“Does your urinary problem interfere with any activities?”",
          "“Do you lose urine when you cough or sneeze?”",
          "“When was the last time you voided?”",
          "“Are you experiencing a fever or chills?”"
        ],
        "answer": "“When was the last time you voided?”",
        "explanation": "To obtain an accurate assessment, the nurse should first determine the source of the discomfort. Urinary retention causes the bladder to be firm and distended; time of last void is most appropriate. Further assessment to determine the pathology of the condition can be performed later. Questions concerning fever and chills, interference with any activities, and losing urine during coughing or sneezing focus on specific pathological conditions.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Obtain a nursing history from a patient with an alteration in urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is planning care for a group of patients. Which task will the nurse assign to the nursing assistive personnel (AP)?",
        "options": [
          "Obtaining a midstream urine specimen",
          "Interpreting a bladder scan result",
          "Inserting a straight catheter",
          "Irrigating a catheter"
        ],
        "answer": "Obtaining a midstream urine specimen",
        "explanation": "The skill of collecting midstream (clean-voided) urine specimens can be delegated to nursing assistive personnel. The nurse must first determine the timing and frequency of the bladder scan measurement and interprets the measurements obtained. Inserting a straight or an indwelling catheter cannot be delegated. Catheter irrigation or instillation cannot be delegated to nursing assistive personnel.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "While receiving a shift report on a female patient, the nurse is informed that the patient has been experiencing urinary incontinence. Upon assessment, which finding will the nurse expect?",
        "options": [
          "An indwelling Foley catheter",
          "Reddened irritated skin on buttocks",
          "Tiny blood clots in the patient’s urine",
          "Foul-smelling discharge indicative of infection"
        ],
        "answer": "Reddened irritated skin on buttocks",
        "explanation": "Urinary incontinence is uncontrolled urinary elimination; if the urine has prolonged contact with the skin, skin breakdown can occur. An indwelling Foley catheter is a solution for urine retention. Blood clots and foul-smelling discharge are often signs of infection.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast common alterations associated with urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is inserting a catheter into a female patient. When the nurse inserts the catheter, no urine is obtained. The nurse suspects the catheter is not in the urethra. What should the nurse do?",
        "options": [
          "Throw the catheter way and begin again.",
          "Fill the balloon with the recommended sterile water.",
          "Remove the catheter, wipe with alcohol, and reinsert after lubrication.",
          "Leave the catheter in the vagina as a landmark for insertion of a new, sterile catheter."
        ],
        "answer": "Leave the catheter in the vagina as a landmark for insertion of a new, sterile catheter.",
        "explanation": "If no urine appears, the catheter may be in the vagina. If misplaced, leave the catheter in the vagina as a landmark to indicate where not to insert, and insert another sterile catheter. The catheter should be left in place until the new, sterile catheter is inserted. The balloon should not be filled since the catheter is in the vagina. The catheter must be sterile; using alcohol will not make the catheter sterile.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply an external catheter and insert a urinary catheter.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Safety and Infection Control"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient asks about treatment for stress urinary incontinence. Which is the nurse’s best response?",
        "options": [
          "Perform pelvic floor exercises.",
          "Avoid voiding frequently.",
          "Drink cranberry juice.",
          "Wear an adult diaper."
        ],
        "answer": "Perform pelvic floor exercises.",
        "explanation": "Poor muscle tone leads to an inability to control urine flow. The nurse should recommend pelvic muscle strengthening exercises such as Kegel exercises; this solution best addresses the patient’s problem. Evidence has shown that patients with urgency, stress, and mixed urinary incontinence can eventually achieve continence when treated with pelvic floor muscle training. Drinking cranberry juice is a preventative measure for urinary tract infection. The nurse should not encourage the patient to reduce voiding; residual urine in the bladder increases the risk of infection. Wearing an adult diaper could be considered if attempts to correct the root of the problem fail.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse suspects cystitis related to a lower urinary tract infection. Which clinical manifestation does the nurse expect the patient to report?",
        "options": [
          "Dysuria",
          "Flank pain",
          "Frequency",
          "Fever"
        ],
        "answer": "Frequency",
        "explanation": "Cystitis is inflammation of the bladder; associated symptoms include hematuria, foul-smelling cloudy urine, and urgency/frequency. Dysuria is a common symptom of a lower urinary tract infection (bladder). Flank pain, fever, and chills are all signs of pyelonephritis (upper urinary tract).",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast common alterations associated with urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which assessment question should the nurse ask if stress incontinence is suspected?",
        "options": [
          "“Do you think your bladder feels distended?”",
          "“Do you empty your bladder completely when you void?”",
          "“Do you experience urine leakage when you cough or sneeze?”",
          "“Do your symptoms increase with consumption of alcohol or caffeine?”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Do you experience urine leakage when you cough or sneeze?”",
        "explanation": "Stress incontinence can be related to intraabdominal pressure causing urine leakage, as would happen during coughing or sneezing. Asking the patient about the fullness of the bladder would rule out retention and overflow. An inability to void completely can refer to urge incontinence. Physiological causes and medications can effect elimination, but this is not related to stress incontinence.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast common alterations associated with urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient has a catheter that must be irrigated. The nurse is using a needleless closed irrigation technique. In which order will the nurse perform the steps, starting with the first one?\n1. Clean injection port.\n2. Inject prescribed solution.\n3. Twist needleless syringe into port.\n4. Remove clamp and allow to drain.\n5. Clamp catheter just below specimen port.\n6. Draw up prescribed amount of sterile solution ordered.",
        "options": [
          "3, 2, 6, 1, 5, 4",
          "5, 6, 1, 2, 3, 4",
          "1, 5, 6, 3, 2, 4",
          "6, 5, 1, 3, 2, 4"
        ],
        "answer": "6, 5, 1, 3, 2, 4",
        "explanation": "The steps for irrigating with a needleless closed irrigation technique is as follows: draw up in a syringe the prescribed amount of medication or sterile solution; clamp indwelling retention catheter just below specimen port; using circular motion, clean injection port with antiseptic swab; insert tip of needleless syringe using twisting motion into irrigation port; slowly and evenly inject fluid into catheter and bladder; and withdraw syringe, remove clamp, and allow solution to drain into drainage bag.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Perform closed catheter irrigation correctly.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "To obtain a clean-voided urine specimen from a female patient, what should the nurse teach the patient to do?",
        "options": [
          "Cleanse the urethral meatus from the area of most contamination to least.",
          "Initiate the first part of the urine stream directly into the collection cup.",
          "Drink fluids 5 minutes before collecting the urine specimen.",
          "Hold the labia apart while voiding into the specimen cup."
        ],
        "answer": "Hold the labia apart while voiding into the specimen cup.",
        "explanation": "The patient should hold the labia apart to reduce bacterial levels in the specimen. The urethral meatus should be cleansed from the area of least contamination to greatest contamination (or front to back). The initial stream flushes out microorganisms in the urethra and prevents bacterial transmission in the specimen. Drink fluids 30 minutes before giving a specimen.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing implications of common diagnostic tests of the urinary system.",
        "top": "Teaching/Learning",
        "msc": "Infection and Safety Control"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is reviewing results from a urine specimen. What will the nurse expect to see in a patient with a urinary tract infection?",
        "options": [
          "Casts",
          "Protein",
          "Crystals",
          "Bacteria"
        ],
        "answer": "Bacteria",
        "explanation": "Bacteria in the urine along with other symptoms support a diagnosis of urinary tract infection. Crystals would be seen with renal stone formation. Casts indicate renal disease. Protein indicates kidney function and damage to the glomerular membrane such as in glomerulonephritis.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe characteristics of normal and abnormal urine.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The patient is prescribed phenazopyridine. When assessing the urine, what will the nurse expect?",
        "options": [
          "Red color",
          "Orange color",
          "Dark amber color",
          "Intense yellow color"
        ],
        "answer": "Orange color",
        "explanation": "Some drugs change the color of urine (e.g., phenazopyridine—orange, riboflavin—intense yellow). Eating beets, rhubarb, and blackberries causes red urine. Dark amber urine is the result of high concentrations of bilirubin in patients with liver disease.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe characteristics of normal and abnormal urine.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which clinical manifestation will the nurse expect to observe in a patient with excessive white blood cells present in the urine?",
        "options": [
          "Reduced urine specific gravity",
          "Increased blood pressure",
          "Abnormal blood sugar",
          "Fever with chills"
        ],
        "answer": "Fever with chills",
        "explanation": "Fever and chills may be observed. The presence of white blood cells in urine indicates a urinary tract infection or inflammation. Overhydration, early renal disease, and inadequate antidiuretic hormone secretion reduce specific gravity. Increased blood pressure is associated with renal disease or damage and some medications. Abnormal blood sugars would be seen in someone with ketones in the urine or a patient with diabetes.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe characteristics of normal and abnormal urine.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A patient reports severe flank pain. The urinalysis reveals presence of calcium phosphate crystals. The nurse will anticipate an order for which diagnostic test?",
        "options": [
          "Intravenous pyelogram",
          "Mid-stream urinalysis",
          "Bladder scan",
          "Cystoscopy"
        ],
        "answer": "Intravenous pyelogram",
        "explanation": "Flank pain and calcium phosphate crystals are associated with renal calculi. An intravenous pyelogram allows the provider to observe pathological problems such as obstruction of the ureter. A mid-stream urinalysis is performed for a routine urinalysis or if an infection is suspected, a urinalysis was already performed, a mid-stream would not be obtained again. A cystoscopy is used to detect bladder tumors and obstruction of the bladder outlet and urethra. A bladder scan measures the amount of urine in the bladder.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing implications of common diagnostic tests of the urinary system.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient who just underwent an intravenous pyelography that revealed a renal calculus obstructing the left ureter. What is the nurse’s first priority in caring for this patient?",
        "options": [
          "Turn the patient on the right side to alleviate pressure on the left kidney.",
          "Encourage the patient to increase fluid intake to flush the obstruction.",
          "Monitor the patient for fever, rash, and difficulty breathing.",
          "Administer narcotic medications to the patient for pain."
        ],
        "answer": "Monitor the patient for fever, rash, and difficulty breathing.",
        "explanation": "Assess for delayed hypersensitivity to the contrast media. Intravenous pyelography is performed by administering iodine-based dye to view functionality of the urinary system. Therefore, the first nursing priority is to assess the patient for an allergic reaction that could be life threatening. The nurse should then encourage the patient to drink fluids to flush dye resulting from the procedure. Narcotics can be administered but are not the first priority. Turning the patient on the side will not affect patient safety.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing implications of common diagnostic tests of the urinary system.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which statement by the patient about an upcoming contrast computed tomography (CT) scan indicates a need for further teaching?",
        "options": [
          "“I will follow the food and drink restrictions as directed before the test is scheduled.”",
          "“I will be anesthetized so that I lie perfectly still during the procedure.”",
          "“I will complete my bowel prep program the night before the scan.”",
          "“I will be drinking a lot of fluid after the test is over.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“I will be anesthetized so that I lie perfectly still during the procedure.”",
        "explanation": "Patients are not put under anesthesia for a CT scan; instead, the nurse should educate patients about the need to lie perfectly still and about possible methods of overcoming feelings of claustrophobia. The other options are correct and require no further teaching. Patients need to be assessed for an allergy to shellfish if receiving contrast for the CT scan. Bowel cleansing is often performed before CT scan. Another area to address is food and fluid restriction up to 4 hours prior to the test. After the procedure, encourage fluids to promote dye excretion.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing implications of common diagnostic tests of the urinary system.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is preparing to test a patient for postvoid residual with a bladder scan. Which action will the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Measure bladder before the patient voids.",
          "Measure bladder within 15 minutes after the patient voids.",
          "Measure bladder with head of bed raised to 60 degrees.",
          "Measure bladder with head of bed raised to 90 degrees."
        ],
        "answer": "Measure bladder within 15 minutes after the patient voids.",
        "explanation": "Measurement should be within 5 to 15 minutes of voiding. It is a postvoid so the measurement is after the patient voids and the urine volume is recorded. Patient is supine with head slightly elevated.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Measure postvoid residual with a bladder scanner.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is watching a nursing assistive personnel (AP) perform a postvoid bladder scan on a female with a previous hysterectomy. Which action will require the nurse to follow up?",
        "options": [
          "Palpates the patient’s symphysis pubis.",
          "Wipes scanner head with alcohol pad.",
          "Applies a generous amount of gel.",
          "Sets the scanner to female."
        ],
        "answer": "Sets the scanner to female.",
        "explanation": "The nurse will follow up if the AP sets the scanner to female. Women who have had a hysterectomy should be designated as male. All the rest are correct and require no follow-up. The NAP should palpate the symphysis pubis, the scanner head should be cleaned with an alcohol pad, and a generous amount of gel should be applied.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Measure postvoid residual with a bladder scanner.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A female patient is having difficulty voiding in a bedpan but states that her bladder feels full. To stimulate micturition, which nursing intervention should the nurse try first?",
        "options": [
          "Exiting the room and informing the patient that the nurse will return in 30 minutes to check on the patient’s progress",
          "Utilizing the power of suggestion by turning on the faucet and letting the water run",
          "Obtaining an order for a Foley catheter",
          "Administering diuretic medication"
        ],
        "answer": "Utilizing the power of suggestion by turning on the faucet and letting the water run",
        "explanation": "To stimulate micturition, the nurse should attempt noninvasive procedures first. Running warm water or stroking the inner aspect of the upper thigh promotes sensory perception that leads to urination. A patient should not be left alone on a bedpan for 30 minutes because this could cause skin breakdown. Catheterization places the patient at increased risk of infection and should not be the first intervention attempted. Diuretics are useful if the patient is not producing urine, but they do not stimulate micturition.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for an 8-year-old patient who is embarrassed about urinating in bed at night. Which intervention should the nurse suggest to reduce the frequency of this occurrence?",
        "options": [
          "“Set your alarm clock to wake you every 2 hours, so you can get up to void.”",
          "“Line your bedding with plastic sheets to protect your mattress.”",
          "“Drink your nightly glass of milk earlier in the evening.”",
          "“Empty your bladder completely before going to bed.”"
        ],
        "answer": "“Drink your nightly glass of milk earlier in the evening.”",
        "explanation": "Nightly incontinence and nocturia are often resolved by limiting fluid intake 2 hours before bedtime. Setting the alarm clock to wake does not correct the physiological problem, nor does lining the bedding with plastic sheets. Emptying the bladder may help with early nighttime urination but will not affect urine produced throughout the night from late-night fluid intake.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is inserting an indwelling urinary catheter for a male patient. Which action will the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Hold the shaft of the penis at a 60-degree angle.",
          "Hold the shaft of the penis with the dominant hand.",
          "Cleanse the meatus 3 times with the same cotton ball from clean to dirty.",
          "Cleanse the meatus with circular strokes beginning at the meatus and working outward."
        ],
        "answer": "Cleanse the meatus with circular strokes beginning at the meatus and working outward.",
        "explanation": "Using the uncontaminated dominant hand, cleanse the meatus with cotton balls/swab sticks, using circular strokes, beginning at the meatus and working outward in a spiral motion. Repeat 3 times using a clean cotton ball/swabstick each time. With the nondominant hand (now contaminated), retract the foreskin (if uncircumcised) and gently grasp the penis at the shaft just below the glans. Hold the shaft of the penis at a right angle to the body.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply an external catheter and insert a urinary catheter.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse will anticipate inserting a Coudé catheter for which patient?",
        "options": [
          "An 8-year-old male undergoing anesthesia for a tonsillectomy",
          "A 24-year-old female who is going into labor",
          "A 56-year-old male admitted for bladder irrigation",
          "An 86-year-old female admitted for a urinary tract infection"
        ],
        "answer": "A 56-year-old male admitted for bladder irrigation",
        "explanation": "A Coudé catheter has a curved tip that is used for patients with enlarged prostates. This would be indicated for a middle-aged male who needs bladder irrigation. Coudé catheters are not indicated for children or women.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply an external catheter and insert a urinary catheter.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is evaluating a nursing assistive personnel’s (AP) care for a patient with an indwelling catheter. Which action by the AP will cause the nurse to intervene?",
        "options": [
          "Emptying the drainage bag when half full",
          "Kinking the catheter tubing to obtain a urine specimen",
          "Placing the drainage bag on the side rail of the patient’s bed",
          "Securing the catheter tubing to the patient’s thigh"
        ],
        "answer": "Placing the drainage bag on the side rail of the patient’s bed",
        "explanation": "Placing the drainage bag on the side rail of the bed could allow the bag to be raised above the level of the bladder and urine to flow back into the bladder. The urine in the drainage bag is a medium for bacteria; allowing it to reenter the bladder can cause infection. A key intervention to prevent catheter-associated urinary tract infections is prevention of urine back flow from the tubing and bag into the bladder. All the rest are correct procedures and do not require follow-up. The drainage bag should be emptied when half full; an overfull drainage bag can create tension and pulling on the catheter, resulting in trauma to the urethra and/or urinary meatus and increasing risk for urinary tract infections. Urine specimens are obtained by temporarily kinking the tubing; a prolonged kink could lead to bladder distention. Failure to secure the catheter to the patient’s thigh places the patient at risk for tissue injury from catheter dislodgment.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to reduce risk for urinary tract infections.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient with a continent urinary reservoir. Which action will the nurse teach the patient?",
        "options": [
          "Catheterizing the pouch",
          "Preforming Kegel exercises",
          "Changing the collection pouch",
          "To avoid using the Valsalva technique"
        ],
        "answer": "Catheterizing the pouch",
        "explanation": "In a continent urinary reservoir, the ileocecal valve creates a one-way valve in the pouch through which a catheter is inserted through the stoma to empty the urine from the pouch. Patients must be willing and able to catheterize the pouch 4 to 6 times a day for the rest of their lives. The second type of continent urinary diversion is called an orthotopic neobladder, which uses an ileal pouch to replace the bladder. Anatomically, the pouch is in the same position as the bladder was before removal, allowing a patient to void through the urethra using a Valsalva technique. In a ureterostomy or ileal conduit, the patient has no sensation or control over the continuous flow of urine through the ileal conduit, requiring the effluent (drainage) to be collected in a pouch. Kegel exercises are ineffective for a patient with a continent urinary reservoir.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast common alterations associated with urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is preparing to apply an external catheter. Which action will the nurse take?",
        "options": [
          "Allow 1 to 2 inches of space between the tip of the penis and the end of the catheter.",
          "Spiral wrap the penile shaft using adhesive tape to secure the catheter.",
          "Twist the catheter before applying drainage tubing to the end of the catheter.",
          "Shave the pubic area before applying the catheter."
        ],
        "answer": "Allow 1 to 2 inches of space between the tip of the penis and the end of the catheter.",
        "explanation": "When applying an external catheter, allow 2.5 to 5 cm (1 to 2 inches) of space between the tip of the penis and the end of the catheter. Spiral wrap the penile shaft with supplied elastic adhesive. The strip should not overlap. The elastic strip should be snug but not tight. NOTE: Never use adhesive tape. Connect drainage tubing to the end of the condom catheter. Be sure the condom is not twisted. Connect the catheter to a large-volume drainage bag or leg. Clip hair at the base of the penile shaft, as necessary. Do not shave the pubic area.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Apply an external catheter and insert a urinary catheter.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is caring for a hospitalized patient with a urinary catheter. Which nursing action best prevents the patient from acquiring an infection?",
        "options": [
          "Maintaining a closed urinary drainage system",
          "Inserting the catheter using strict clean technique",
          "Disconnecting and replacing the catheter drainage bag once per shift",
          "Fully inflating the catheter’s balloon according to the manufacturer’s recommendation"
        ],
        "answer": "Maintaining a closed urinary drainage system",
        "explanation": "A key intervention to prevent infection is maintaining a closed urinary drainage system. A catheter should be inserted in the hospital setting using sterile technique. Inflating the balloon fully prevents dislodgment and trauma, not infection. Disconnecting the drainage bag from the catheter creates a break in the system and an open portal of entry and increases risk of infection.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to reduce risk for urinary tract infections.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is providing care to a patient with an indwelling catheter. Which practice indicates the nurse is following guidelines for avoiding catheter-associated urinary tract infection (CAUTI)?",
        "options": [
          "Drapes the urinary drainage tubing with no dependent loops.",
          "Washes the drainage tube toward the meatus with soap and water.",
          "Places the urinary drainage bag gently on the floor below the patient.",
          "Allows the spigot to touch the receptacle when emptying the drainage bag."
        ],
        "answer": "Drapes the urinary drainage tubing with no dependent loops.",
        "explanation": "Avoid dependent loops in urinary drainage tubing. Prevent the urinary drainage bag from touching or dragging on the floor. When emptying the urinary drainage bag, use a separate measuring receptacle for each patient. Do not let the drainage spigot touch the receptacle. Using a clean washcloth, soap, and water, with your dominant hand wipe in a circular motion along the length of the catheter for about 10 cm (4 inches), starting at the meatus and moving away.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to reduce risk for urinary tract infections.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse is providing care to a group of patients. Which patient will the nurse see first?",
        "options": [
          "A patient who is dribbling urine and has a diagnosis of urge incontinence",
          "A patient with reflex incontinence with elevated blood pressure and pulse rate",
          "A patient with an indwelling catheter that has stool on the catheter tubing",
          "A patient who has just voided and needs a postvoid residual test"
        ],
        "answer": "A patient with reflex incontinence with elevated blood pressure and pulse rate",
        "explanation": "The nurse should see the patient with reflex incontinence first. Patients with reflex incontinence are at risk for developing autonomic dysreflexia, a life-threatening condition that causes severe elevation of blood pressure and pulse rate and diaphoresis. This is a medical emergency requiring immediate intervention; notify the health care provider immediately. A patient with urge incontinence will dribble, and this is expected. While a patient with a catheter and stool on the tubing does need to be cleaned, it is not life threatening. The nurse has 10 minutes before checking on the patient who has a postvoid residual test.",
        "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "To reduce patient discomfort during a closed intermittent catheter irrigation, what should the nurse do?",
        "options": [
          "Use room temperature irrigation solution.",
          "Administer the solution as quickly as possible.",
          "Allow the solution to sit in the bladder for at least 1 hour.",
          "Raise the bag of the irrigation solution at least 12 inches above the bladder."
        ],
        "answer": "Use room temperature irrigation solution.",
        "explanation": "To reduce discomfort use room temperature solution. Using cold solutions and instilling solutions too quickly can cause discomfort. During an irrigation, the solution does not sit in the bladder; it is allowed to drain. A container is not raised about the bladder 12 inches when performing a closed intermittent catheter irrigation.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Perform closed catheter irrigation correctly.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which observation by the nurse best indicates that a continuous bladder irrigation for a patient following genitourinary surgery is effective?",
        "options": [
          "Output that is smaller than the amount instilled",
          "Blood clots or sediment in the drainage bag",
          "Bright red urine turns pink in the tubing",
          "Bladder distention with tenderness"
        ],
        "answer": "Bright red urine turns pink in the tubing",
        "explanation": "If urine is bright red or has clots, increase irrigation rate until drainage appears pink, indicating successful irrigation. Expect more output than fluid instilled because of urine production. If output is smaller than the amount instilled, suspect that the tube may be clogged. The presence of blood clots indicates the patient is still bleeding, while sediment could mean an infection or bleeding. The bladder should not be distended or tender; the irrigant may not be flowing freely if these occur, or the tube may be kinked or blocked.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Perform closed catheter irrigation correctly.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse anticipates a suprapubic catheter for which patient?",
        "options": [
          "A patient with recent prostatectomy",
          "A patient with a urethral stricture",
          "A patient with an appendectomy",
          "A patient with menopause"
        ],
        "answer": "A patient with a urethral stricture",
        "explanation": "A patient with a urethral stricture is most likely to have a suprapubic catheter. Suprapubic catheters are placed when there is blockage of the urethra (e.g., enlarged prostate, urethral stricture, after urological surgery). A patient with a recent prostatectomy indicates the enlarged prostate was removed and would not need a suprapubic catheter; however, continuous bladder irrigation may be needed. Appendectomies and menopause do not require a suprapubic catheter.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Compare and contrast common alterations associated with urinary elimination.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Management of Care"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which nursing actions will the nurse implement when collecting a urine specimen from a patient? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Growing urine cultures for up to 12 hours",
          "Labeling all specimens with date, time, and initials",
          "Allowing the patient adequate time and privacy to void",
          "Wearing gown, gloves, and mask for all specimen handling",
          "Transporting specimens to the laboratory in a timely manner",
          "Collecting the specimen from the drainage bag of an indwelling catheter"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Labeling all specimens with date, time, and initials",
          "Allowing the patient adequate time and privacy to void",
          "Transporting specimens to the laboratory in a timely manner"
        ],
        "explanation": "All specimens should be labeled appropriately and processed in a timely fashion. Allow patients time and privacy to void. Urine cultures can take up to 48 to 72 hours to develop. Only gloves are necessary to handle a urine specimen. Gown and mask are not needed unless otherwise indicated. Never collect the specimen from the drainage bag of a catheter; obtain the sample from the special sampling port.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing implications of common diagnostic tests of the urinary system.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is obtaining a 24-hour urine specimen collection from the patient. Which actions should the nurse take? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Keeping the urine collection container on ice when indicated",
          "Withholding all patient medications for the day",
          "Irrigating the sample as needed with sterile solution",
          "Testing the urine sample with a reagent strip by dipping it in the urine",
          "Asking the patient to void and discarding that urine to start the collection"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Keeping the urine collection container on ice when indicated",
          "Asking the patient to void and discarding that urine to start the collection"
        ],
        "explanation": "When obtaining a 24-hour urine specimen, it is important to keep the urine in cool conditions, depending upon the test. The patient should be asked to void and to discard the urine before the procedure begins. Medications do not need to be held unless indicated by the provider. If properly educated about the collection procedure, the patient can maintain autonomy and perform the procedure alone, taking care to maintain the integrity of the solution. A 24-hour urine specimen is not tested with a reagent strip.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Describe nursing implications of common diagnostic tests of the urinary system.",
        "top": "Implementation",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which findings should the nurse follow up on after removal of a catheter from a patient? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Increasing fluid intake",
          "Dribbling of urine",
          "Voiding in small amounts",
          "Voiding within 6 hours of catheter removal",
          "Burning with the first couple of times voiding"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Dribbling of urine",
          "Voiding in small amounts"
        ],
        "explanation": "Abdominal pain and distention, a sensation of incomplete emptying, incontinence, constant dribbling of urine, and voiding in very small amounts can indicate inadequate bladder emptying requiring intervention. All the rest are normal and do not require follow-up. The patient should increase intake. The first few times a patient voids after catheter removal may be accompanied by some discomfort, but continued complaints of painful urination indicate possible infection. Patient should void 6 to 8 hours after catheter removal.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Assessment",
        "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
      },
      {
        "question": "A nurse administers an antimuscarinic to a patient. A decrease in which findings indicate the patient is having therapeutic effects from this medication? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Dysuria",
          "Urgency",
          "Frequency",
          "Prostate size",
          "Bladder infection"
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Urgency",
          "Frequency"
        ],
        "explanation": "When newly started on an antimuscarinic, you should monitor the patient for effectiveness, watching for a decrease in symptoms such as urgency, frequency, and urgency urinary incontinence episodes. Patients with painful urination are sometimes prescribed urinary analgesics that act on the urethral and bladder mucosa (e.g., phenazopyridine). Antibiotics are used to treat bladder infections. Agents that shrink the prostate include finasteride and dutasteride.",
        "dif": "Apply (application)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Evaluation",
        "msc": "Pharmacological and Parenteral Therapies"
      },
      {
        "question": "The nurse is using different toileting schedules. Which principles will the nurse keep in mind when planning care? (Select all that apply.)",
        "options": [
          "Habit training uses a bladder diary.",
          "Timed voiding is based upon the patient’s urge to void.",
          "Prompted voiding includes asking patients if they are wet or dry.",
          "Elevation of feet in patients with edema can decrease nighttime voiding.",
          "Bladder retraining teaches patients to follow the urge to void as quickly as possible."
        ],
        "answer": [
          "Habit training uses a bladder diary.",
          "Prompted voiding includes asking patients if they are wet or dry."
        ],
        "explanation": ", C Habit training is a toileting schedule based upon the patient’s usual voiding pattern. Using a bladder diary, the usual times a patient voids are identified. It is at these times that the patient is then toileted. Prompted voiding is a program of toileting designed for patients with mild or moderately cognitive impairment. Patients are toileted based upon their usual voiding pattern. Caregivers ask the patient if they are wet or dry, give positive feedback for dryness, prompt the patient to toilet, and reward the patient for desired behavior. Timed voiding or scheduled toileting is toileting based upon a fixed schedule, not the patient’s urge to void. The schedule maybe set by a time interval, every 2 to 3 hours or at times of day such as before and after meals. In bladder retraining, patients are taught to inhibit the urge to void by taking slow and deep breaths to relax, perform 5 to 6 quick strong pelvic muscle exercises (flicks) in quick succession followed by distracting attention from bladder sensations. When the urge to void becomes less severe or subsides, only then should the patient start the trip to the bathroom. Encourage patients with edema to elevate the feet for a minimum of a few hours in the afternoon to help diminish nighttime voiding frequency; while this is helpful, it is not a toileting schedule.",
        "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
        "obj": "Discuss nursing measures to promote normal micturition and improve bladder control.",
        "top": "Planning",
        "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
      }
    ],
    "chapter48": [
        {
            "question": "A nurse participating in a research project associated with pressure ulcers will assess for what predisposing factor that tends to increase the risk for pressure ulcer development?",
            "options": [
              "Decreased level of consciousness",
              "Adequate dietary intake",
              "Shortness of breath",
              "Muscular pain"
            ],
            "answer": "Decreased level of consciousness",
            "explanation": "Patients who are confused or disoriented or who have changing levels of consciousness are unable to protect themselves. The patient may feel the pressure but may not understand what to do to relieve the discomfort or to communicate that he or she is feeling discomfort. Impaired sensory perception, impaired mobility, shear, friction, and moisture are other predisposing factors. Shortness of breath, muscular pain, and an adequate dietary intake are not included among the predisposing factors.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the risk factors that contribute to pressure ulcer formation.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse caring for an unconscious patient who was involved in an automobile accident 2 weeks ago will give priority to which element when planning care to decrease the development of a decubitus ulcer?",
            "options": [
              "Resistance",
              "Pressure",
              "Weight",
              "Stress"
            ],
            "answer": "Pressure",
            "explanation": "Pressure is the main element that causes pressure ulcers. Three pressure-related factors contribute to pressure ulcer development: pressure intensity, pressure duration, and tissue tolerance. When the intensity of the pressure exerted on the capillary exceeds 15 to 32 mm Hg, this occludes the vessel, causing ischemic injury to the tissues it normally feeds. High pressure over a short time and low pressure over a long-time cause skin breakdown. Resistance, stress, and weight are not the priority causes of pressure ulcers.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Discuss the risk factors that contribute to pressure ulcer formation.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which nursing observation will indicate the patient is at risk for pressure ulcer formation?",
            "options": [
              "Fecal incontinence",
              "Ate two thirds of breakfast",
              "A raised red rash on the right shin",
              "Capillary refill is less than 2 seconds"
            ],
            "answer": "Fecal incontinence",
            "explanation": "The presence and duration of moisture on the skin increase the risk of ulcer formation by making it susceptible to injury. Moisture can originate from wound drainage, excessive perspiration, and fecal or urinary incontinence. Bacteria and enzymes in the stool can enhance the opportunity for skin breakdown because the skin is moistened and softened, causing maceration. Eating a balanced diet is important for nutrition, but eating just two thirds of the meal does not indicate that the individual is at risk. A raised red rash on the leg again is a concern and can affect the integrity of the skin, but it is located on the shin, which is not a high-risk area for skin breakdown. Pressure can influence capillary refill, leading to skin breakdown, but this capillary response is within normal limits.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the risk factors that contribute to pressure ulcer formation.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The wound care nurse is monitoring a patient with a Stage III pressure ulcer whose wound presents with healthy tissue. How should the nurse document this ulcer in the patient's medical record?",
            "options": [
              "Stage I pressure ulcer",
              "Healing Stage II pressure ulcer",
              "Healing Stage III pressure ulcer",
              "Stage III pressure ulcer"
            ],
            "answer": "Healing Stage III pressure ulcer",
            "explanation": "When a pressure ulcer has been staged and is beginning to heal, the ulcer keeps the same stage and is labeled with the words “healing stage” or healing Stage III pressure ulcer. Once an ulcer has been staged, the stage endures even as the ulcer heals. This ulcer was labeled a Stage III, and it cannot return to a previous stage such as Stage I or II. This ulcer is healing, so it is no longer labeled a Stage III.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the pressure ulcer staging system.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse admitting an older patient notes a shallow open reddish, pink ulcer without slough on the right heel of the patient. How will the nurse stage this pressure ulcer?",
            "options": [
              "Stage I",
              "Stage II",
              "Stage III",
              "Stage IV"
            ],
            "answer": "Stage II",
            "explanation": "This would be a Stage II pressure ulcer because it presents as partial-thickness skin loss involving epidermis and dermis. The ulcer presents clinically as an abrasion, blister, or shallow crater. Stage I is intact skin with nonblanchable redness over a bony prominence. With a Stage III pressure ulcer, subcutaneous fat may be visible, but bone, tendon, and muscles are not exposed. Stage IV involves full-thickness tissue loss with exposed bone, tendon, or muscle.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the pressure ulcer staging system.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which item should the nurse use first to assist in staging an ulcer on the heel of a darkly pigmented skin patient?",
            "options": [
              "Disposable measuring tape",
              "Cotton-tipped applicator",
              "Sterile gloves",
              "Natural light"
            ],
            "answer": "Natural light",
            "explanation": "When assessing a patient with darkly pigmented skin, proper lighting is essential to accurately complete the first step in assessment—inspection—and the entire assessment process. Natural light is recommended. Fluorescent light sources can produce blue tones on darkly pigmented skin and can interfere with an accurate assessment. Other items that could possibly be used during the assessment include gloves for infection control, a disposable measuring device to measure the size of the wound, and a cotton-tipped applicator to measure the depth of the wound, but these items are not the first items used.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the pressure ulcer staging system.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with a Stage IV pressure ulcer. Which type of healing will the nurse consider when planning care for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Partial-thickness wound repair",
              "Full-thickness wound repair",
              "Primary intention",
              "Tertiary intention"
            ],
            "answer": "Full-thickness wound repair",
            "explanation": "Stage IV pressure ulcers are full-thickness wounds that extend into the dermis and heal by scar formation because the deeper structures do not regenerate, hence the need for full-thickness repair. The full-thickness repair has four phases: hemostasis, inflammatory, proliferative, and maturation. A wound heals by primary intention when wounds such as surgical wounds have little tissue loss; the skin edges are approximated or closed, and the risk for infection is low. Partial-thickness repairs are done on partial-thickness wounds that are shallow, involving loss of the epidermis and maybe partial loss of the dermis. These wounds heal by regeneration because the epidermis regenerates. Tertiary intention is seen when a wound is left open for several days, and then the wound edges are approximated. Wound closure is delayed until risk of infection is resolved.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the normal process of wound healing.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a group of patients. Which patient will the nurse see first?",
            "options": [
              "A patient with a Stage IV pressure ulcer",
              "A patient with a Braden Scale score of 18",
              "A patient with appendicitis using a heating pad",
              "A patient with an incision that is approximated"
            ],
            "answer": "A patient with appendicitis using a heating pad",
            "explanation": "The nurse should see the patient with an appendicitis first. Warm applications are contraindicated when the patient has an acute, localized inflammation such as appendicitis because the heat could cause the appendix to rupture. Although a Stage IV pressure ulcer is deep, it is not as critical as the appendicitis patient. The total Braden score ranges from 6 to 23; a lower total score indicates a higher risk for pressure ulcer development. A score of 18 can be assessed later. A healing incision is approximated (closed); this is a normal finding and does not need to be seen first.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Complete an assessment for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who is experiencing a full-thickness wound repair. Which type of tissue will the nurse expect to observe when the wound is healing?",
            "options": [
              "Eschar",
              "Slough",
              "Granulation",
              "Purulent drainage"
            ],
            "answer": "Granulation",
            "explanation": "Granulation tissue is red, moist tissue composed of new blood vessels, the presence of which indicates progression toward healing. Soft yellow or white tissue is characteristic of slough—a substance that needs to be removed for the wound to heal. Black or brown necrotic tissue is called eschar, which also needs to be removed for a wound to heal. Purulent drainage is indicative of an infection and will need to be resolved for the wound to heal.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Discuss the normal process of wound healing.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has experienced a laparoscopic appendectomy. For which type of healing will the nurse focus the care plan?",
            "options": [
              "Partial-thickness repair",
              "Secondary intention",
              "Tertiary intention",
              "Primary intention"
            ],
            "answer": "Primary intention",
            "explanation": "A clean surgical incision is an example of a wound with little loss of tissue that heals with primary intention. The skin edges are approximated or closed, and the risk for infection is low. Partial-thickness repairs are done on partial-thickness wounds that are shallow, involving loss of the epidermis and maybe partial loss of the dermis. These wounds heal by regeneration because the epidermis regenerates. Tertiary intention is seen when a wound is left open for several days, and then the wound edges are approximated. Wound closure is delayed until the risk of infection is resolved. A wound involving loss of tissue such as a burn or a pressure ulcer or laceration heals by secondary intention. The wound is left open until it becomes filled with scar tissue. It takes longer for a wound to heal by secondary intention; thus the chance of infection is greater.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences in wound healing by primary and secondary intention.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse caring for a patient in the burn unit should expect what type of wound healing when planning care for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Partial-thickness repair",
              "Secondary intention",
              "Tertiary intention",
              "Primary intention"
            ],
            "answer": "Secondary intention",
            "explanation": "A wound involving loss of tissue such as a burn or a pressure ulcer or laceration heals by secondary intention. The wound is left open until it becomes filled with scar tissue. It takes longer for a wound to heal by secondary intention; thus the chance of infection is greater. A clean surgical incision is an example of a wound with little loss of tissue that heals by primary intention. The skin edges are approximated or closed, and the risk for infection is low. Partial-thickness repair is done on partial-thickness wounds that are shallow, involving loss of the epidermis and maybe partial loss of the dermis. These wounds heal by regeneration because the epidermis regenerates. Tertiary intention is seen when a wound is left open for several days, and then the wound edges are approximated. Wound closure is delayed until the risk of infection is resolved.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences in wound healing by primary and secondary intention.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which nursing observation will indicate the patient's wound healed by the process of secondary intention?",
            "options": [
              "Minimal loss of tissue function",
              "Permanent dark redness at site",
              "Minimal scar tissue",
              "Scarring that may be severe"
            ],
            "answer": "Scarring that may be severe",
            "explanation": "A wound healing by secondary intention takes longer than one healing by primary intention. The wound is left open until it becomes filled with scar tissue. If the scarring is severe, permanent loss of function often occurs. Wounds that heal by primary intention heal quickly with minimal scarring. Scar tissue contains few pigmented cells and has a lighter color than normal skin.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences in wound healing by primary and secondary intention.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has experienced a total abdominal hysterectomy. Which nursing observation related to the incision will indicate the patient is experiencing a complication of wound healing?",
            "options": [
              "Patient reporting, “My incision is hurting.”",
              "Approximation of the incision edges has occurred.",
              "Patient asks, “Why has my incision started to itch?”",
              "The incision appears both swollen and bluish in color."
            ],
            "answer": "The incision appears both swollen and bluish in color.",
            "explanation": "A hematoma is a localized collection of blood underneath the tissues. It appears as swelling, change in color, sensation, or warmth or a mass that often takes on a bluish discoloration. A hematoma near a major artery or vein is dangerous because it can put pressure on the vein or artery and obstruct blood flow. Itching is not a complication. Incisions should be approximated with edges together; this is a sign of normal healing. After surgery, when nerves in the skin and tissues have been traumatized by the surgical procedure, it is expected that the patient will experience pain.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe complications of wound healing.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which finding will alert the nurse to a potential wound dehiscence?",
            "options": [
              "Protrusion of visceral organs through a wound opening",
              "Chronic drainage of fluid through the incision site",
              "Report by patient that something has given way",
              "Drainage that is odorous and purulent"
            ],
            "answer": "Report by patient that something has given way",
            "explanation": "Patients often report feeling as though something has given way with dehiscence. Dehiscence occurs when an incision fails to heal properly, and the layers of skin and tissue separate. It involves abdominal surgical wounds and occurs after a sudden strain such as coughing, vomiting, or sitting up in bed. Evisceration is seen when vital organs protrude through a wound opening. When there is an increase in serosanguineous drainage from a wound in the first few days after surgery, be alert for the potential for dehiscence. Infection is characterized by drainage that is odorous and purulent.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe complications of wound healing.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which laboratory data will be important for the nurse to monitor when a patient develops a pressure ulcer?",
            "options": [
              "Vitamin E",
              "Potassium",
              "Prealbumin",
              "Sodium"
            ],
            "answer": "Prealbumin",
            "explanation": "Normal wound healing requires proper nutrition. Serum proteins are biochemical indicators of malnutrition, and serum albumin is probably the most frequently measured of these parameters. The best measurement of nutritional status is prealbumin because it reflects not only what the patient has ingested but also what the body has absorbed, digested, and metabolized. Zinc and copper are the minerals important for wound healing, not potassium and sodium. Vitamins A and C are important for wound healing, not vitamin E.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Explain the factors that impede or promote wound healing.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A nurse is caring for a patient with a wound. Which assessment data will be most relevant with regard to wound healing?",
            "options": [
              "Muscular strength assessment",
              "Pulse oximetry assessment",
              "Sensation assessment",
              "Sleep assessment"
            ],
            "answer": "Pulse oximetry assessment",
            "explanation": "Oxygen fuels the cellular functions essential to the healing process; the ability to perfuse tissues with adequate amounts of oxygenated blood is critical in wound healing. Pulse oximetry measures the oxygen saturation of blood. Assessment of muscular strength and sensation, although useful for fitness and mobility testing, does not provide any data with regard to wound healing. Sleep, although important for rest and for integration of learning and restoration of cognitive function, does not provide any data with regard to wound healing.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Explain the factors that impede or promote wound healing.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "Upon entering the room of a patient with a healing Stage III pressure ulcer, the nurse notices an odor and observes a purulent discharge, along with increased redness at the wound site. What action should the nurse give priority to?",
            "options": [
              "Completing a head-to-toe assessment, including current treatment, vital signs, and laboratory results",
              "Notifying the health care provider by utilizing Situation, Background, Assessment, and Recommendation (SBAR)",
              "Consulting the wound care nurse about the change in status and the potential for infection",
              "Conferring with the charge nurse about the change in status and the potential for infection"
            ],
            "answer": "Completing a head-to-toe assessment, including current treatment, vital signs, and laboratory results",
            "explanation": "The patient is showing signs and symptoms associated with infection in the wound. The nurse should complete the assessment: gather all data such as current treatment modalities, medications, vital signs including temperature, and laboratory results such as the most recent complete blood count or white cell count. The nurse can then notify the primary care provider and receive treatment orders for the patient. It is important to notify the charge nurse and consult the wound nurse on the patient's status and on any new orders.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Explain the factors that impede or promote wound healing.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is collaborating with the dietitian about a patient with a Stage III pressure ulcer. Which nutrient will the nurse expect to be increased after collaboration with the dietitian?",
            "options": [
              "Fat",
              "Protein",
              "Vitamin E",
              "Carbohydrate"
            ],
            "answer": "Protein",
            "explanation": "Protein needs are especially increased in supporting the activity of wound healing. The physiological processes of wound healing depend on the availability of protein, vitamins (especially A and C), and the trace minerals of zinc and copper. Wound healing does not require increased amounts of fats or carbohydrates. Vitamin E will not be increased for wound healing.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Explain the factors that impede or promote wound healing.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is completing an assessment on a patient who has a Stage IV pressure ulcer. The wound is odorous with a drain is currently in place. Which statement by the patient indicates issues with self-concept?",
            "options": [
              "“I am so weak and tired. I just want to feel better.”",
              "“I been thinking I will be ready to go home early next week.”",
              "“I really need a bath and linen change right; I feel so awful.”",
              "“I am hoping there will be something good to eat for my dinner tonight.”"
            ],
            "answer": "“I really need a bath and linen change right; I feel so awful.”",
            "explanation": "Body image changes can influence self-concept. The wound is odorous, and a drain is in place. The patient who is asking for a bath and change in linens and states that this is awful gives you a clue that he or she may be concerned about the smell in the room. Factors that affect the patient's perception of the wound include the presence of scars, drains, odor from drainage, and temporary or permanent prosthetic devices. The patient's stating that he or she wants to feel better, talking about going home, and caring about what is for dinner could be interpreted as positive statements that indicate progress along the health journey.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Explain the factors that impede or promote wound healing.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient presents to the emergency department with a laceration of the right forearm caused by a fall. After determining that the patient is stable, what is the next best step for the nurse to take?",
            "options": [
              "Inspect the wound for bleeding.",
              "Irrigate the wound to remove foreign bodies.",
              "Measure and document the size of the wound.",
              "Determine when the patient last had a tetanus antitoxin injection."
            ],
            "answer": "Inspect the wound for bleeding.",
            "explanation": "After determining that a patient's condition is stable, inspect the wound for bleeding. An abrasion will have limited bleeding, a laceration can bleed more profusely, and a puncture wound bleeds in relation to the size and depth of the wound. Address any bleeding issues. Inspect the wound for foreign bodies; traumatic wounds are dirty and may need to be addressed. Determine the size of the wound. A large open wound may expose bone or tissue and be protected, or the wound may need suturing. When the wound is caused by a dirty penetrating object, determine the need for a tetanus vaccination.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences between nursing care of acute and chronic wounds.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient on the medical-surgical unit with a wound that has a drain and a dressing that needs changing. Which action should the nurse take first?",
            "options": [
              "Provide analgesic medications as ordered.",
              "Avoid accidentally removing the drain.",
              "Don sterile gloves.",
              "Gather supplies."
            ],
            "answer": "Provide analgesic medications as ordered.",
            "explanation": "Because removal of dressings is painful, if often helps to give an analgesic at least 30 minutes before exposing a wound and changing the dressing. The next sequence of events includes gathering supplies for the dressing change, donning gloves, and avoiding the accidental removal of the drain during the procedure.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences between nursing care of acute and chronic wounds.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has a wound drain with a collection device. The nurse notices that the collection device has a sudden decrease in drainage. Which action will the nurse take initially?",
            "options": [
              "Call the health care provider; a blockage is present in the tubing.",
              "Chart the results on the intake and output flow sheet.",
              "Do nothing, as long as the evacuator is compressed.",
              "Remove the drain; a drain is no longer needed."
            ],
            "answer": "Call the health care provider; a blockage is present in the tubing.",
            "explanation": "Because a drainage system needs to be patent, look for drainage flow through the tubing, as well as around the tubing. A sudden decrease in drainage through the tubing may indicate a blocked drain, and you will need to notify the health care provider. The health care provider, not the nurse, determines the need for drain removal and removes drains. Charting the results on the intake and output flow sheet does not take care of the problem. The evacuator may be compressed even when a blockage is present.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences between nursing care of acute and chronic wounds.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who has a Stage IV pressure ulcer with grafted surgical sites. Which specialty bed will the nurse use for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Low-air-loss",
              "Air-fluidized",
              "Lateral rotation",
              "Standard mattress"
            ],
            "answer": "Air-fluidized",
            "explanation": "For a patient with newly flapped or grafted surgical sites, the air-fluidized bed will be the best choice; this uses air and fluid support to provide pressure redistribution via a fluid-like medium created by forcing air through beads as characterized by immersion and envelopment. A low-air-loss bed is utilized for prevention or treatment of skin breakdown by preventing buildup of moisture and skin breakdown through the use of airflow. A standard mattress is utilized for an individual who does not have actual or potential altered or impaired skin integrity. Lateral rotation is used for treatment and prevention of pulmonary, venous stasis and urinary complications associated with mobility.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences between nursing care of acute and chronic wounds.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse notes that a patient has a black pressure ulcer on the left hip. Which event will the nurse anticipate when planning care for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Increased monitoring of the wound condition",
              "Documenting the wound's status daily",
              "Surgical debridement of the wound",
              "Increased drainage from wound"
            ],
            "answer": "Surgical debridement of the wound",
            "explanation": "Debridement is the removal of nonviable necrotic (black) tissue. Removal of necrotic tissue is necessary to rid the ulcer of a source of infection, to enable visualization of the wound bed, and to provide a clean base for healing. A wound will not move through the phases of healing if the wound is infected. When treating a pressure ulcer, it is important to monitor and reassess the wound at least every 8 hours. Management of drainage will help keep the wound clean, but that is not the next step.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences between nursing care of acute and chronic wounds.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse caring for a patient with a healing Stage III pressure ulcer notes that the wound is clean and granulating. Which health care provider's order will the nurse question?",
            "options": [
              "Use a low-air-loss therapy unit.",
              "Irrigate with Dakin's solution.",
              "Apply a hydrogel dressing.",
              "Consult a dietitian."
            ],
            "answer": "Irrigate with Dakin's solution.",
            "explanation": "Pressure ulcers should be with noncytotoxic cleansers such as normal saline, which will not kill fibroblasts and healing tissue. Cytotoxic cleansers such as Dakin's solution, acetic acid, povidone-iodine, and hydrogen peroxide can hinder the healing process and should not be utilized on clean, granulating wounds. Consulting a dietitian for the nutritional needs of the patient, utilizing a low-air-loss therapy unit to decrease pressure, and applying hydrogel dressings to provide a moist environment for healing are all orders that would be appropriate.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "Describe the differences between nursing care of acute and chronic wounds.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is completing an assessment of the patient's skin's integrity. Which assessment is the priority?",
            "options": [
              "Pressure points",
              "Breath sounds",
              "Bowel sounds",
              "Pulse points"
            ],
            "answer": "Pressure points",
            "explanation": "Observe pressure points such as bony prominences. The nurse continually assesses the skin for signs of ulcer development. Assessment for tissue pressure damage includes visual and tactile inspection of the skin. Assessment of pulses, breath sounds, and bowel sounds is part of a head-to-toe assessment and could influence the function of the body and ultimately skin integrity; however, this assessment is not a specific part or priority of a skin assessment.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Complete an assessment for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is completing a skin risk assessment using the Braden Scale. The patient has slight sensory impairment, has skin that is rarely moist, walks occasionally, and has slightly limited mobility, along with excellent intake of meals and no apparent problem with friction and shear. Which score will the nurse document for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "15",
              "17",
              "20",
              "23"
            ],
            "answer": "20",
            "explanation": "With use of the Braden Scale, the total score is a 20. The patient receives 3 for slight sensory perception impairment, 4 for skin being rarely moist, 3 for walks occasionally, 3 for slightly limited mobility, 4 for intake of meals, and 4 for no problem with friction and shear.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Complete an assessment for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a surgical patient. Which intervention is most important for the nurse to complete to decrease the risk of pressure ulcers and encourage the patient's willingness and ability to increase mobility?",
            "options": [
              "Explain the risks of immobility to the patient.",
              "Turn the patient every 3 hours while in bed.",
              "Encourage the patient to sit up in the chair.",
              "Provide analgesic medication as ordered."
            ],
            "answer": "Provide analgesic medication as ordered.",
            "explanation": "Maintaining adequate pain control (providing analgesic medications) and patient comfort increases the patient's willingness and ability to increase mobility, which in turn reduces pressure ulcer risks. Although sitting in the chair is beneficial, it does not increase mobility or provide pain control. Explaining the risk of immobility is important for the patient because it may impact the patient's willingness but not his or her ability. Turning the patient is important for decreasing pressure ulcers but needs to be done every 2 hours and, again, does not influence the patient's ability to increase mobility.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with a Stage IV pressure ulcer. Which nursing diagnosis should the nurse add to the care plan?",
            "options": [
              "Readiness for enhanced nutrition",
              "Impaired physical mobility",
              "Impaired skin integrity",
              "Chronic pain"
            ],
            "answer": "Impaired skin integrity",
            "explanation": "After the assessment is completed and the information that the patient has a Stage IV pressure ulcer is gathered, a diagnosis of Impaired skin integrity is selected. Readiness for enhanced nutrition would be selected for an individual with an adequate diet that could be improved. Impaired physical mobility and Chronic pain do not support the current data in the question.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List nursing diagnoses associated with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse documents the following assessment data: right heel with reddened area that does not blanch. Which nursing diagnosis will the nurse assign to this patient?",
            "options": [
              "Imbalanced nutrition: less than body requirements",
              "Ineffective peripheral tissue perfusion",
              "Risk for infection",
              "Acute pain"
            ],
            "answer": "Ineffective peripheral tissue perfusion",
            "explanation": "The area on the heel has experienced a decreased supply of blood and oxygen (tissue perfusion), which has resulted in tissue damage. The most appropriate nursing diagnosis with this information is Ineffective peripheral tissue perfusion. Risk for infection, Acute pain, and Imbalanced nutrition do not support the data in the question.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List nursing diagnoses associated with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Diagnosis",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse caring for an immobile patient wants to decrease the risk of the formation of pressure ulcers. Which action will the nurse take first?",
            "options": [
              "Offer favorite fluids.",
              "Turn the patient every 2 hours.",
              "Determine the patient's risk factors.",
              "Encourage increased quantities of carbohydrates and fats."
            ],
            "answer": "Determine the patient's risk factors.",
            "explanation": "The first step in prevention is to assess the patient's risk factors for pressure ulcer development. When a patient is immobile, the major risk to the skin is the formation of pressure ulcers. Nursing interventions focus on prevention. Offering favorite fluids, turning, and increasing carbohydrates and fats are not the first steps. Determining risk factors is first, so interventions can be implemented to reduce or eliminate those risk factors.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Complete an assessment for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which health care team member will the nurse consult when a patient has received a nursing diagnosis of Impaired skin integrity?",
            "options": [
              "Respiratory therapist",
              "Registered dietitian",
              "Case manager",
              "Chaplain"
            ],
            "answer": "Registered dietitian",
            "explanation": "Refer patients with pressure ulcers to the dietitian for early intervention for nutritional problems. Adequate calories, protein, vitamins, and minerals promote wound healing for the impaired skin integrity. The nurse is the coordinator of care and collaborating with the dietitian would result in planning the best meals for the patient. The respiratory therapist can be consulted when a patient has issues with the respiratory system. Case management can be consulted when the patient has a discharge need. A chaplain can be consulted when the patient has a spiritual need.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a nursing care plan for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "When a comatose patient develops a Stage II pressure ulcer, the nurse includes the nursing diagnosis of Risk for infection to the care plan. Which is the best goal for this patient?",
            "options": [
              "The patient will state what to look for with regard to an infection.",
              "The patient's family will demonstrate specific care of the wound site.",
              "The patient's family members will wash their hands when visiting the patient.",
              "The patient will remain free of odorous or purulent drainage from the wound."
            ],
            "answer": "The patient will remain free of odorous or purulent drainage from the wound.",
            "explanation": "Because the patient has an open wound and the skin is no longer intact to protect the tissue, the patient is at increased risk for infection. The nurse will be assessing the patient for signs and symptoms of infection, including an increase in temperature, an increase in white count, and odorous and purulent drainage from the wound. The patient is unconscious and is unable to communicate the signs and symptoms of infection. It is important for the patient's family to be able to demonstrate how to care for the wound and wash their hands, but these statements are not goals or outcomes for this nursing diagnosis.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a nursing care plan for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "When caring for a group of patients, which task can the nurse delegate to the nursing assistive personnel (AP)?",
            "options": [
              "Assessing a surgical patient for risk of pressure ulcers",
              "Applying a gauze bandage to secure a non-sterile dressing",
              "Treating a pressure ulcer on the buttocks of a medical patient",
              "Implementing negative-pressure wound therapy on a stable patient"
            ],
            "answer": "Applying a gauze bandage to secure a non-sterile dressing",
            "explanation": "The skill of applying bandages to secure non-sterile dressings can be delegated to AP. Assessing pressure ulcer risk, treating a pressure ulcer, and implementing negative-pressure wound therapy cannot be delegated to an AP.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse performing a moist-to-dry dressing has prepared the supplies, solution, and removed the old dressing. In which order will the nurse implement the following steps, starting with the first one?\n\n1. Apply sterile gloves.\n2. Cover and secure topper dressing.\n3. Assess wound and surrounding skin.\n4. Moisten gauze with prescribed solution.\n5. Gently wring out excess solution and unfold.\n6. Loosely pack until all wound surfaces are in contact with gauze.",
            "options": [
              "4, 3, 1, 5, 6, 2",
              "1, 3, 4, 5, 6, 2",
              "4, 1, 3, 5, 6, 2",
              "1, 4, 3, 5, 6, 2"
            ],
            "answer": "1, 3, 4, 5, 6, 2",
            "explanation": "The steps for a moist-to-dry dressing are as follows:\n\n(1) apply sterile gloves,\n(2) assess appearance of surrounding skin,\n(3) moisten gauze with prescribed solution,\n(4) gently wring out excess solution and unfold; apply gauze as single layer directly onto wound surface,\n(5) if wound is deep, gently pack dressing into wound base by hand until all wound surfaces are in contact with gauze\n(6) cover with sterile dry gauze and secure topper dressing.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient at risk for skin impairment. Which initial action should the nurse take to decrease this risk?",
            "options": [
              "After cleansing thoroughly dry the skin.",
              "Request a therapeutic bed and mattress.",
              "Pad the bed with absorbent pads.",
              "Use products that retain moisture."
            ],
            "answer": "After cleansing thoroughly dry the skin.",
            "explanation": "Use cleansers with non-ionic surfactants that are gentle to the skin. After you clean the skin, make sure that it is completely dry. Absorbent pads and garments are controversial and should be considered only when other alternatives have been exhausted. Depending on the needs of the patient, a specialty bed may be needed, but again, this does not provide the initial defense for skin breakdown. Use only products that wick moisture away from the patient's skin.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a nursing care plan for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "A patient at risk for skin impairment is able to sit up in a chair. How long should the nurse schedule the patient to sit in the chair?",
            "options": [
              "Less than 2 hours at any one time",
              "For a total of least than 3 hours daily",
              "No longer than 30 minutes out of every hour",
              "Until the patient expresses being uncomfortable"
            ],
            "answer": "Less than 2 hours at any one time",
            "explanation": "When patients are able to sit up in a chair, make sure to limit the amount of time to 2 hours or less at any given time. The chair sitting time should be individualized. In the sitting position, pressure on the ischial tuberosities is greater than in a supine position. Utilize foam, gel, or an air cushion to distribute weight. Sitting for longer than 2 hours can increase the chance of ischemia.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Develop a nursing care plan for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Planning",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who is immobile and is at risk for skin impairment. The plan of care includes turning the patient. Which is the best method for repositioning the patient?",
            "options": [
              "Place the patient in a 30-degree supine position.",
              "Utilize a transfer device to lift the patient.",
              "Elevate the head of the bed 45 degrees.",
              "Slide the patient into the new position."
            ],
            "answer": "Utilize a transfer device to lift the patient.",
            "explanation": "When repositioning the patient, obtain assistance and utilize a transfer device to lift rather than drag the patient. Sliding the patient into the new position will increase friction. The patient should be placed in a 30-degree lateral position, not a supine position. The head of the bed should be elevated less than 30 degrees to prevent pressure ulcer development from shearing forces.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "As prescribed, the nurse leaves the pressure ulcer open to air and does not apply a dressing. Which stage of ulcer did the nurse appropriately treat?",
            "options": [
              "A Stage I",
              "A Stage II",
              "A Stage III",
              "A Stage IV"
            ],
            "answer": "A Stage I",
            "explanation": "Stage I intact pressure ulcers that resolve slowly without epidermal loss over 7 to 14 days do not require a dressing. A composite film, hydrocolloid, or hydrogel can be utilized on a clean Stage II. A hydrocolloid, hydrogel covered with foam, calcium alginate, and gauze can be utilized with a clean Stage III. Hydrogel covered with foam, calcium alginate, and gauze can be utilized with a clean Stage IV. An un-stageable wound covered with eschar should utilize a dressing of adherent film or gauze with an ordered solution of enzymes.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient appears anxious as the nurse is preparing to change their wound dressing. Which action should the nurse take?",
            "options": [
              "Distract the patient with the television.",
              "Offer to explain what they should expect.",
              "Suggest that the patient “Close your eyes.”",
              "Wait until family is visiting to support the patient."
            ],
            "answer": "Offer to explain what they should expect.",
            "explanation": "Explaining the procedure educates the patient regarding the dressing change and involves him in the care, thereby allowing the patient some control in decreasing anxiety. Telling the patient to close the eyes and turning on the television are distractions that do not usually decrease a patient's anxiety. If the family is a support system, their presence may be helpful but it isn't practical to postpone the treatment until they are present.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Psychosocial Integrity"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which intervention should be included as the nurse cleanses a wound?",
            "options": [
              "Allow the solution to flow from the most contaminated to the least contaminated.",
              "Scrub vigorously when applying noncytotoxic solution to the skin.",
              "Cleanse in a direction from the least contaminated area.",
              "Utilize clean gauze and clean gloves to cleanse a site."
            ],
            "answer": "Cleanse in a direction from the least contaminated area.",
            "explanation": "Cleanse in a direction from the least contaminated area, such as from the wound or incision, to the surrounding skin. While cleansing surgical or traumatic wounds by applying noncytotoxic solution with sterile gauze or by irrigations is correct, vigorous scrubbing is inappropriate and can cause damage to the skin. Use gentle friction when applying solutions to the skin and allow irrigation to flow from the least to the most contaminated area.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which is the best explanation for the nurse to provide when teaching the patient the reason for the binder after an open abdominal aortic aneurysm repair?",
            "options": [
              "It reduces edema at the surgical site.",
              "It secures the dressing in place.",
              "It immobilizes the abdomen.",
              "It supports the abdomen."
            ],
            "answer": "It supports the abdomen.",
            "explanation": "The patient has a large abdominal incision. This incision will need support, and an abdominal binder will support this wound, especially during movement, as well as during deep breathing and coughing. A binder can be used to immobilize a body part (e.g., an elastic bandage applied around a sprained ankle). A binder can be used to prevent edema, for example, in an extremity but in this case is not used to reduce edema at a surgical site. A binder can be used to secure dressings such as elastic webbing applied around a leg after vein stripping.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Teaching/Learning",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a postoperative patient recovering from a medial meniscus repair of the right knee. Which action should the nurse take to assist with pain management?",
            "options": [
              "Monitor vital signs every 15 minutes.",
              "Check pulses in the right foot.",
              "Keep the leg dependent.",
              "Apply ice."
            ],
            "answer": "Apply ice.",
            "explanation": "Ice assists in preventing edema formation, controlling bleeding, and anesthetizing the body part. Elevation (not dependent) assists in preventing edema, which in turn can cause pain. Monitoring vital signs every 15 minutes is routine postoperative care and includes a pain assessment but in itself is not an intervention that decreases pain. Checking the pulses is important to monitor the circulation of the extremity but in itself is not a pain management intervention.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The patient has a risk for skin impairment and has a 15 on the Braden Scale upon admission. The nurse has implemented interventions. Upon reassessment, which Braden score will be the best sign that the risk for skin breakdown is removed?",
            "options": [
              "12",
              "13",
              "20",
              "23"
            ],
            "answer": "23",
            "explanation": "The best sign is a perfect score of 23. The Braden Scale is composed of six sub-scales: sensory perception, moisture, activity, mobility, nutrition, and friction and shear. The total score ranges from 6 to 23, and a lower total score indicates a higher risk for pressure ulcer development. The cutoff score for onset of pressure ulcer risk with the Braden Scale in the general adult population is 18.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "State evaluation criteria for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with a surgical incision that eviscerates. Which actions will the nurse take? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Place moist sterile gauze over the site.",
              "Gently place the organs back.",
              "Contact the surgical team.",
              "Offer a glass of water.",
              "Monitor for shock."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Place moist sterile gauze over the site.",
                "Contact the surgical team.",
                "Monitor for shock."
            ],
            "explanation": "The presence of an evisceration (protrusion of visceral organs through a wound opening) is a surgical emergency. Immediately place damp sterile gauze over the site, contact the surgical team, do not allow the patient anything by mouth (NPO), observe for signs and symptoms of shock, and prepare the patient for emergency surgery.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Describe complications of wound healing.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with a wound healing by full-thickness repair. Which phases will the nurse monitor for in this patient? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Hemostasis",
              "Maturation",
              "Inflammatory",
              "Proliferative",
              "Reproduction",
              "Reestablishment of epidermal layers"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Hemostasis",
                "Maturation",
                "Inflammatory",
                "Proliferative"
            ],
            "explanation": "The four phases involved in the healing process of a full-thickness wound are hemostasis, inflammatory, proliferative, and maturation. Three components are involved in the healing process of a partial-thickness wound: inflammatory response, epithelial proliferation (reproduction) and migration, and reestablishment of the epidermal layers.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "Explain the factors that impede or promote wound healing.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Physiological Adaptation"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is completing a skin assessment on a medical-surgical patient. Which nursing assessment questions should be included in a skin integrity assessment? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "“Can you easily change your position?”",
              "“Do you have sensitivity to heat or cold?”",
              "“How often do you need to use the toilet?”",
              "“What medications do you take?”",
              "“Is movement painful?”",
              "“Have you ever fallen?”"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "“Can you easily change your position?”",
                "“Do you have sensitivity to heat or cold?”",
                "“How often do you need to use the toilet?”",
                "“Is movement painful?”"
            ],
            "explanation": "Changing positions is important for decreasing the pressure associated with long periods of time in the same position. If the patient is able to feel heat or cold and is mobile, she can protect herself by withdrawing from the source. Knowing toileting habits and any potential for incontinence is important because urine and feces in contact with the skin for long periods can increase skin breakdown. Knowing whether the patient has problems with painful movement will alert the nurse to any potential for decreased movement and increased risk for skin breakdown. Medications and falling are safety risk questions.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Complete an assessment for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Reduction of Risk Potential"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient with potential skin breakdown. Which components will the nurse include in the skin assessment? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Vision",
              "Hyperemia",
              "Induration",
              "Blanching",
              "Temperature of skin"
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Hyperemia",
                "Induration",
                "Blanching",
                "Temperature of skin"
            ],
            "explanation": "Assessment of the skin includes both visual and tactile inspection. Assess for hyperemia and palpate for blanching or non-blanching. Early signs of skin damage include induration, bogginess (less-than-normal stiffness), and increased warmth at the injury site compared to nearby areas. Changes in temperature can indicate changes in blood flow to that area of the skin. Vision is not included in the skin assessment.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "Complete an assessment for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Assessment",
            "msc": "Health Promotion and Maintenance"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for a patient who will have a large abdominal bandage secured with an abdominal binder. Which actions will the nurse take before applying the bandage and binder? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "Cover exposed wounds.",
              "Mark the sites of all abrasions.",
              "Assess the condition of current dressings.",
              "Inspect the skin for abrasions and edema.",
              "Cleanse the area with hydrogen peroxide.",
              "Assess the skin at underlying areas for circulatory impairment."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Cover exposed wounds.",
                "Assess the condition of current dressings.",
                "Inspect the skin for abrasions and edema.",
                "Assess the skin at underlying areas for circulatory impairment."
            ],
            "explanation": "Before applying a bandage or a binder, the nurse has several responsibilities. The nurse would need to inspect the skin for abrasions, edema, and discoloration or exposed wound edges. The nurse also is responsible for covering exposed wounds or open abrasions with a dressing and assessing the condition of underlying dressings and changing if soiled, as well as assessing the skin of underlying areas that will be distal to the bandage. This checks for signs of circulatory impairment, so that a comparison can be made after bandages are applied. Marking the sites of all abrasions is not necessary. Although it is important for the skin to be clean, and even though it may need to be cleaned with a noncytotoxic cleanser, cleansing with hydrogen peroxide can interfere with wound healing.",
            "dif": "Apply (application)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is updating the plan of care for a patient with impaired skin integrity. Which findings indicate achievement of goals and outcomes? (Select all that apply.)",
            "options": [
              "The patient's expectations are not being met.",
              "Skin is intact with no redness or swelling.",
              "Nonblanchable erythema is absent.",
              "No injuries to the skin and tissues are evident.",
              "Granulation tissue is present."
            ],
            "answer": [
                "Skin is intact with no redness or swelling.",
                "Nonblanchable erythema is absent.",
                "No injuries to the skin and tissues are evident.",
                "Granulation tissue is present."
            ],
            "explanation": "Optimal outcomes are to prevent injury to skin and tissues, reduce injury to skin, reduce injury to underlying tissues, and restore skin integrity. Skin intact, nonblanchable erythema absent, no injuries, and presence of granulation tissue are all findings indicating achievement of goals and outcomes. The patient's expectations not being met indicate no progression toward goals/outcomes.",
            "dif": "Analyze (analysis)",
            "obj": "State evaluation criteria for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Evaluation",
            "msc": "Management of Care"
          },
          {
            "question": "The nurse is caring for patients who need wound dressings. Match the type of dressing the nurse applies to its description.",
            "matching": [
              "Gauze",
              "Transparent",
              "Hydrocolloid",
              "Hydrogel",
              "Calcium alginate"
            ],
            "options": [
              "Absorbs drainage through the use of exudate absorbers in the dressing",
              "Very soothing to the patient and do not adhere to the wound bed",
              "Barrier to external fluids/bacteria but allows wound to “breathe”",
              "Manufactured from seaweed and comes in sheet and rope form",
              "Oldest and most common absorbent dressing"
            ],
            "answer": {
              "Gauze": "Oldest and most common absorbent dressing",
              "Transparent": "Barrier to external fluids/bacteria but allows wound to “breathe”",
              "Hydrocolloid": "Absorbs drainage through the use of exudate absorbers in the dressing",
              "Hydrogel": "Very soothing to the patient and do not adhere to the wound bed",
              "Calcium alginate": "Manufactured from seaweed and comes in sheet and rope form"
            },
            "explanation": "\"Gauze\" is the oldest and most commonly used absorbent dressing, offering versatility in managing various wound types.\n\"Transparent\" dressings provide a barrier against external contaminants while allowing the wound to breathe, fostering an optimal healing environment.\n\"Hydrocolloid\" dressings utilize exudate absorbers within the dressing to efficiently absorb wound drainage, aiding in moisture balance.\n\"Hydrogel\" dressings, prized for their soothing properties, do not adhere to the wound bed, promoting pain-free dressing changes and maintaining a moist wound environment conducive to healing.\n\"Calcium alginate\" dressings, derived from seaweed, come in sheet and rope forms and are particularly effective in managing moderate to heavily draining wounds, thanks to their high absorbency and conformability to wound contours.",
            "dif": "Understand (comprehension)",
            "obj": "List appropriate nursing interventions for a patient with impaired skin integrity.",
            "top": "Implementation",
            "msc": "Basic Care and Comfort"
          }
    ]
}
